[{"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "Have you ever participated in efforts to secure funding for clinical research?", "answers": ["Clinical trials can be sponsored or funded by a variety of organizations or individuals including physicians, medical institutions, foundations, voluntary groups, and pharmaceutical companies.  Additionally, government agencies such as the National Institutes of Health (NIH), the Department of Defense (DOD), Human Health and Services (HHS), and the Department of Veteran's Affairs (VA) support some clinical trials.   If you have experience grant writing or using other experience to secure funding, this could be a plus.  Share any knowledge or experience you have.", "\"I have some experience, but not a lot, with regard to grant-writing.  I worked with someone previously who did some grant-writing for a long-term care facility.  I tried to learn as much as I could from her and would love the opportunity to learn more.\"", "\"Unfortunately, the finance side of trials has never been a place where I've had an opportunity to work.  I understand that funding comes from various places and I am not opposed to learning about ways to secure funding and offer assistance in any way I can.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "CROs work with multiple clients nationally and internationally, which means employees are often expected to juggle time zones and adhere to the sponsor's tight deadlines.  What are some things you do to help manage your time efficiently?", "answers": ["Because CROs are contracted to work for other companies, details such as time zone differences can often play a big role in scheduling.  The interviewer wants to know that you are able to juggle multiple tasks within an allotted time frame.  Share some ways you keep yourself organized during a work day.", "\"I have worked with clients internationally and understand the important of accurate scheduling.  Before beginning any new project, I always like to verify the differences in time zones, what specific duties I will be expected to carry out and the deadline for each.  I then create a schedule on computer with daily reminders that I check each morning and make sure I am on schedule.\"", "\"I like to stay on track with projects.  I am a visual learner and because of that, I make a schedule on paper and keep it in a place that is visible (desktop/bulletin board, etc).  As I complete a task, I mark it off and move to the next.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "If you were the person responsible for hiring at Company ABC, what characteristics would you look for in a candidate, and do you feel that you possess those traits?", "answers": ["There is more than one reason for asking this question.  First, the interviewer wants to know what qualities you think are important to perform this job.  Second, and most importantly, your answer will tell the interviewer if you hold yourself to the same standard as you do others.    If you want to see certain characteristics in your peers, you should be able to tell the interviewer with confidence that you possess those traits, as well.  This question is one that interviewers often use to distinguish sincerity on the part of the candidate.", "\"I believe that honesty is important no matter what job title a person holds.  I have found that being honest with people creates an atmosphere of mutual trust and respect.  Those qualities, I feel, are essential when building rapport with patients and co-workers.  In the field of research, I feel we have to hold one another to a high standard of accountability.  We are responsible for reporting vital information to sponsors/companies and for caring for the candidates involved in our research.  Also, yes, I do believe I possess these qualities.  I strive very hard to make sure that I don't ask something of others that I am not willing to give in return.\"", "\"There are many characteristics that I feel are important when considering to hire someone.  Personal accountability and a willingness to learn from and contribute to a team are extremely important, in my opinion.  I do believe I possess these qualities.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "Do you have an understanding of what a 'control' or 'control group' is?", "answers": ["A control is the standard by which experimental observations are evaluated. In many clinical trials, one group of patients will be given an experimental drug or treatment, while the control group is given either a standard treatment for the illness or a placebo.  If you have worked with clinical trials/observations, you will have a clear understanding of what the 'control' or 'control group' is.  If you have not, say what  you do know.  In most cases, an interviewer will know if you already have clinical trial experience and will know where to guide you with a question like this.", "\"Yes, I do understand the importance of a 'control/control group' in trials.  I assisted with documentation for a clinical trial when I worked at XYZ.  Part of my responsibilities included monitoring the differences in vital signs of the patients who were given a placebo as compared to those who were taking the trial drug.\"", "\"I am familiar with a control/control group.  It is my understanding that when a clinical trials is being conducted, some participants are given the trial drug while the 'control group' is given either the standard treatment or a placebo, but that only the person administering the drug knows who is receiving which.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "At the end of the day, what makes you feel like you have done a good job or have been successful?", "answers": ["Everyone wants to have a sense of fulfillment or accomplishment.  The interviewer wants to know what makes you have that feeling.  Knowing what makes you feel accomplished tells the interviewer a lot about you and the kind of work ethic you have.  Be open about the things that make you feel like you have done a job well.", "\"At the end of the day, I am happy knowing I have participated in a job/study that made a difference for someone.  For instance, monitoring a clinical trial for a new medication that had great results for the participants.  That makes me feel fulfilled.\"", "\"I feel like any day that I can go to work and give my best to my co-workers, patients, and anyone I meet is a day that I have been successful.  Clinical trials happen every day.  Life happens one day at a time.  I try to live my life to the best of my ability each day.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "Are you familiar with what a protocol is with regard to clinical research?", "answers": ["Understanding common terminology used in research is important.  It may seem like an interviewer is asking simple questions, but basic knowledge and understanding is crucial.  Give your definition of 'protocol' to the interviewer.", "\"A protocol is the plan that the clinical trial is based upon.  It describes the details regarding what people may participate in the trial as well as tests, medications, and length of the study.\"", "\"Yes, I am familiar with the term 'protocol.'  With regard to clinical trials, it is the guide or plan that describes how a trial is to be carried out.  It lists what types of patients may participate, what tests or procedures need to be done, the medications, dosages, etc. that need to be monitored.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "Do you know what pharmacokinetic studies are?", "answers": ["Being able to identify different areas of study within clinical research is essential for researchers.  When an interviewer asks a question like, 'do you know....,'  or 'are you familiar...,'  share the knowledge you have, but be careful not to try to embellish your knowledge with facts that are not sure of.", "\"Yes, I am familiar with pharmakokinetic studies.  We always called them 'clinical pharmacology studies.'  These trials are used to test the methods of administration for a drug/treatment, it's frequency and safety.\"", "\"I do know about pharmakokinetic studies.  They are sometimes referred to as or clinical pharmacology studies.  They usually involve between 20-80 healthy participants and are designed to  test methods of administering the treatment (e.g. by mouth, injection, etc.) and how often, as well as the safety of the treatment.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "What is something that causes you stress at work and how do you try to overcome it?", "answers": ["Stress is inevitable no matter what profession one chooses.  It's how we deal with it that makes a difference.  The interviewer, therefore, is not looking for you to answer saying that nothing stresses you, but rather to show that you are able to control stress and work through it.", "\"I think we all experience stress in different ways.  One of the most experienced work-related stress, for me, is not being able to give everyone the results that they want in a clinical trial.  Although it is frustrating, I am also mature enough to know that if we don't succeed at something today, tomorrow we can try again.\"", "\"I think I cause myself more stress than any external event or situation.  I say that because I put a great deal of pressure on myself to be successful and see things through to the end.  As researchers we don't always get the results we are hoping for.  I have to remind myself that that is why we do research.  We search, and then we re-search.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "Contract Research Organizations such as Company ABC employ people from many different backgrounds with a variety of skills.  Have you ever worked with a very diverse group of people?", "answers": ["When working for a CRO, diversity among peers and clients should be expected.   Some people are intimidated when faced with learning new cultures and beliefs, but in the healthcare industry, it is crucial to provide effective care.  The interviewer wants to know that you are open to meeting and learning about new people and becoming an integral part of the team.  Be positive with your response.", "\"The largest diverse group I worked with was probably when I did my clinical rotation at University Medical Center.  I was afforded the opportunity to meet people from different cultures, religions, and professional backgrounds.  It gave me an eye-opening experience of how many wonderful people there are!\"", "\"I think diversity in the healthcare industry is essential.  People from all over the world now call our country their home.  I believe learning about and showing an appreciation for people from different walks of life only makes us stronger as we build upon the common bond of caring for others.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "What are some reasons that you feel participation in a clinical trial are a positive decision?", "answers": ["This question is asking for your opinion, but it is important to remember when you are giving your opinion, make sure that it is supported by facts.  This will show the interviewer you are knowledgeable about the topic of discussion.", "\"I believe that participants in clinical trials play a key role in drug development and discovery.  Clinical trials contribute to knowledge and progress in treating and preventing diseases. Most importantly, participants can help others by contributing to medical knowledge and improving public health.\"", "\"For many patients, participating in a clinical trial may be one of their last options for beneficial treatment for a disease.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "If a trial participant asks you to explain what a placebo is and why it may be used, what would your answer be?", "answers": ["As mentioned before, understanding terminology is very important, especially when dealing with medical issues/patients.  This is another question that the interviewer will use to test your knowledge and ability to express that knowledge to someone else in a manner that they can understand.", "\"I would explain to the participant that a placebo is an inactive pill, liquid or powder that has no treatment value.  I will further explain that in a placebo controlled trial, some portion of the participants will receive placebo instead of an active drug or experimental treatment and that this is done to assess the experimental treatment's effectiveness and safety versus no treatment at all.\"", "\"I will tell the participant that a placebo is a liquid, powder, or pill that has no treatment value and that is used in clinical trials to help determine the difference between the active drug or experiment compared to no treatment at all.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "Company ABC is supportive of our employee's continuing education efforts.  Have you ever thought of going back to school?\n\nCompany ABC is supportive of employees who want to continue their education.  Have you ever thought of going back to school?", "answers": ["While Company ABC may be supportive of an employee who chooses to continue his/her education, that is not to say that you are required to say you want to return to school.  This is simply one of those 'get to know you' questions.  Share your thoughts with the interviewer.", "\"I am very supportive of people who want to continue their education.  For me, I feel like I have come to a place in career where I am happy with where I am.   Notwithstanding, if Company ABC has courses or certifications that are encouraged for employees to take, I would definitely be willing.  I just don't see myself going back to school for 3 or 4 years.\"", "\"I have entertained the idea of continuing my education.  However, circumstances have not ended with me in school.  I love research and am very happy with my career at this point.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "If you had your choice of a research project to work with, what would you choose?", "answers": ["The world of research is very broad which gives those wanting to experience different areas of specialty great opportunities.   CROs work with several different sponsors/companies on various projects.  Knowing what interests you will help the interviewer try to find placement for you that best your skills or interest.", "\"Research is such an exciting industry.  If I had a choice, I would love to work on any project that has to do with cancer research.  Cancer is a dreadful diagnosis and I would love to have some part in helping to find better ways to treat and hopefully cure it.\"", "\"I have always wanted to work in research, but I really don't know if I have a favorite or preferred area.  Things change so quickly within our industry that I feel like any area I work in would be exciting."]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "Are you familiar with the difference between diagnostic trials and screening trials?", "answers": ["Knowing the differences of various types of trials is important for those working in research.  Because there is such a variety of different trials, there is often opportunity to work on more than one.  Many researchers have stated that they like this option as it gives them the chance to learn more and not experience 'burn out' as easily.  If you know the difference in the trials in this question, elaborate on them briefly.  If you are not sure, it's ok to say so and ask the interviewer to differentiate for you.", "\"Diagnostic trials are conducted to find better tests or procedures for diagnosing a particular disease or condition. Screening trials, on the  test the best way to detect certain diseases or health conditions.\"", "\"Although I am rather new to the research industry, based on the names of the two trials you mentioned, I would think that diagnostic trials look for better ways to diagnose illness while screening trials are aimed at ways to diagnose disease.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "If a patient wants to participate in a clinical trial but wants the physician conducting the experiment to provide all of his care during the time the trial is being conducted, what would be the most appropriate advice?", "answers": ["Most clinical trials provide short-term treatments related to a designated illness or condition, but do not provide extended or complete primary health care. In addition, by having the health care provider work with the research team, the participant can ensure that other medications or treatments will not conflict with the protocol.  The interviewer is not asking for 'facts,' but rather how you would relate directly with a patient who is making this request.", "\"I understand that many patients prefer to not see multiple physicians.  However, it is important for patients participating in clinical trials to be educated about the role of the staff conducting the trial.  For example, the medication or therapy that is used for a clinical trial is usually focused on a specific illness/disease.  It is important for patients to follow-up and have continued care with their primary physician.  Additionally, providers who are conducting clinical trials find it beneficial to have communication with the primary physician so that we can work together for the best outcome for the patient.\"", "\"I have always been taught that patients are advised to continue regular follow-ups and care for non-trial related medical issues with their primary care provider.  Also, the research teams I have been a part of have always made it a priority to collaborate with the primary physician.  First of all, it is a professional courtesy.  Further, the open line of communication allows the healthcare team and patient to work together more effectively.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "Are you familiar with what 'expanded access' means?", "answers": ["Expanded access is the term used to describe the means by which manufacturers make new drugs that are being investigated available, under certain circumstances, to treat a patient(s) with a serious disease or condition who cannot participate in a controlled clinical trial.  If you have experience working with patients who have been given expanded access, share some details, as appropriate.  If you don't have personal experience, share your knowledge.", "\"It is my understanding that 'expanded access' is granted, under certain circumstances, to patients who do not qualify to participate in a clinical trial of a regulatory drug.  The drug used in expanded access cannot expose patients to unreasonable risks given the severity of the disease to be treated and the patient must not have any other satisfactory therapeutic options.\"", "\"I do have some knowledge about 'expanded access' although I have not worked directly with patients who have been giveThe manufacturer must be willing to make the drug available for expanded access use. The primary intent of expanded access is to provide treatment for a patient's disease or condition, rather than to collect data about the study drug.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "What made you choose a career in research?", "answers": ["There is no right or wrong answer to this question.  The interviewer simply wants to get to know you.  If something happened in your life that made you want to contribute to research, share it.  Or maybe you have an inquisitive nature.", "\"When I was a child, one of my friends was diagnosed with leukemia.  From the time she became ill I wanted to find a way to fix her.  She eventually experienced remission and is still well today.  I never lost my desire to find ways to help people and research has one of the broadest platforms I could think of.\"", "\"Science was always intriguing to me.  From the time I was a kid, I was always the one with the experimental labs and the nurse kits.  Finding a career in research was a natural choice for me!\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "What would you tell a patient who is asking some of the things he/she should expect while participating in a clinical trial?", "answers": ["It is important for patients to be well informed before beginning any treatment whether it is routine care by a physician or participation in a clinical trial.  The interviewer wants to know that you have an understanding of what the patient's expectations of care should be and that you are comfortable with sharing that with the patient.", "\"I believe in making sure that patients are educated regarding any time of care they are going to receive.  For patients participating in trials, it is important to assure them that participants work with a research or clinical trial team, including doctors, nurses, social workers, and other health care professionals. Prior to the trial, the research team will check the health of the participant and review any special instructions for trial participation. As the trial begins and throughout its duration, the research team will administer treatment  and monitor the participant on a regular basis to determine effectiveness and side-effects of the treatment.\"", "\"The most important thing is to make sure that patients are aware of the objective of the trial.  For example, if a new drug is being tested, the objective would be that the drug is effective in treating the disease it was designed for with little to no ill-effects.  Also, assuring the participant that the research team will work closely with them throughout the duration of the trial.  Many patients are also relieved to know that the research team will work closely with their primary physician throughout the trial.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "Company ABC likes to encourage a healthy work/life balance.  What are some things you like to do make sure you have a healthy balance between work and your personal life?", "answers": ["No matter what profession a person chooses, everyone needs some time to unwind and relax.  Psychologists today say that a healthy balance in life allows a person to recharge and refocus which can result in better productivity at work.  The interviewer simply wants to know what you do for you.  Maybe you have a favorite pass-time or hobby.  This is yet another way for the interviewer to get to know you as a person.", "\"One of my favorite pass-times is writing.  After a busy day at work, I like to journal or write articles for a blog that I author.  Both of these forms of writing allow me to release any feelings of frustration I may experience, especially after a stressful day or a difficult situation at work.   The writings in my journal are private and my way of 'letting it all out.'  The blog articles, on the other hand, are my way of using creative writing to share stories with my followers.\"", "\"I really enjoy working out at the gym and, I also take a kickboxing class twice weekly.   After a good workout or class, I always feel like I can rest better and wake up energized and ready for the next day.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "Knowing that both CROs and pharmaceutical companies conduct research and trials, what do you think may be an of advantage working with a CRO rather than seeking employment with a large pharmaceutical company?", "answers": ["Just like choosing research as a career path, it is also an individual choice whether to seek employment with a CRO rather than a pharmaceutical company.  This is another question that the interviewer will use to get to know you.  It is important to know that you don't have to 'oversell' the CRO concept or 'downplay' a pharmaceutical company.  Simply stating some of the reasons you prefer a CRO is sufficient.", "\"I feel because CROs  work with several pharmaceutical clients, there is more job stabilitiy.   If one project is dropped unexpectedly, a CRO can place an employee on a  new project with a different sponsor.\"", "\"CROs are, to a certain extent, better shielded from the effects of economic decline than pharmaceutical companies. If one of their clients is forced to go under, they still have other companies to work with.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "What are some of the risks associated with being a participant in a clinical trial?", "answers": ["Participation in a clinical trial may involve some risks.  It is important for people specializing in research to understand those risks and be able to explain them (if that is part of your job description).  Share your knowledge with the interviewer.", "\"One of the main risks that many participants and the healthcare team is concerned with is potential side-effects that are known and those that have not yet been identified.\"", "\"One of the frustrating things about clinical trial risk is that participants may not know that they are receiving a placebo and, as a result, will not have the outcome they had hoped for.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "Company ABC tries to accommodate employees with regard to scheduling preferences as much as possible.  Is there a particular schedule that would a better fit with your personal/family responsibilities?", "answers": ["Many people work more than one job or have a one parent home which requires them to have a flexible schedule.  Others simply prefer to work one shift rather than another.  Being up front with the interviewer about what schedule suits your preference could help prevent conflict later on.  It is easier to plan a schedule you can agree on than it is to fix problems that arise due to fear of being rejected.  Be honest and direct.", "\"I am not married and have no children at this time.  So, I am pretty flexible with my schedule.  If I had a choice, I would prefer the late shift, as I am a bit of a night owl.  However, I am  excited about the opportunity to become a part of this team and am willing to work where I'm needed.\"", "\"I am a single mom with two school-aged children.  Ideally, the day shift would be a better fit for me.  This would allow me to fulfill both my work and home responsibilities without a conflict.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "With regard to salary, Company ABC tries to be fair to all employees.  However, salary is often commensurate with experience.  What are your thoughts regarding someone working the same job as you being paid a higher rate due to experience level?", "answers": ["Most employers do offer higher salary incentives to get more seasoned employees.  This is not meant to devalue a person's knowledge or experience, but rather paying for more experience.  It is important to note that the interviewer is not saying you will definitely make less than someone with more experience.  Many times this question is to see how you respond and how badly you want a position.  If an employee is willing to put in the work and earn the pay increase, employers often see them as someone worth investing in.  This is a good time to ask what the beginning salary is and discuss options that are negotiable such as benefits and paid time off.", "\"I understand that years of experience are often rewarded with higher earning.  I feel, given the chance to demonstrate my knowledge and skills, you will find that I am capable of doing the job as well as some of the more experienced employees.  Having said that, I will not turn down an offer of employment because of a difference in pay based on my present lack of experience.  With that in mind, what benefits are available for someone coming on board with your company with my resume?\"", "\"While I have no doubt that my education and skills are comparable to those of employees at Company ABC in the same position, I understand and appreciate the fact that Company ABC likes to acknowledge and reward employees for their years of experience.  With that in mind, I am willing to accept a position at a lower beginning rate and proving myself as worthy for a higher rate later.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "While Company ABC likes to employ people who have plans to work for us long-term, it is understandable that sometimes plans change.  Do you anticipate any significant changes in your life within the next 3-5 years?", "answers": ["One of the good things about working for a CRO like Company ABC is that there are usually several different projects for different sponsors being conducted at the same time.  Knowing what goals you have and any changes you anticipate in your life will give the interviewer an opportunity to evaluate two things: 1. what positions are available that won't disrupt your plans and, 2.  are you interested in having a long-term relationship within the company?   With a CRO, if you anticipate a move or other significant change, you may still be offered employment but within a project that fits your time frame.  Either way, be honest with the interviewer.  This will be beneficial to both you and Company ABC.", "\"I recently became engaged.  Although we have not set a date yet, we have agreed to wait twelve months before the marriage.  My fiance' just passed the Bar exam here and has been offered an opportunity to join an existing law firm.  Presently, our plans are to stay where we are and build a career, not just work a job.  Also, we do not plan on having children for at least two years after our marriage.  We both feel that being able to become established in our careers and save for our future would be the responsible thing to do before starting a family.\"", "\"My spouse is in the military and, although I would like to say with certainty that I will be living in the same place three years from now, there is no guarantee.  I am glad you asked this question because I wanted to discuss any opportunities within Company ABC where I could be useful but may not be obligated for several years until we know if he is going to be able to stay in one place.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "What is a 'controlled' clinical trial?", "answers": ["There are different types of clinical trials.  Working in a research company that conducts trials, it is important to know and understand the differences.  Share your knowledge with the interviewer.", "\"In a controlled trial, one group of patients will be given an experimental drug or treatment, while a second group is given either a standard treatment for the illness or a placebo.  It helps us to determine the differences in the response of patients to the trial drug in comparison to a standard treatment or no treatment.\"", "\"A controlled clinical trial occurs when one group of patients is given a placebo or a commonly used treatment and another group is given the experimental treatment/drug.  In this study, the workers conducting the trial are aware which patients received the experimental drug and those who did not.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "Do you understand what a 'double-blind' trial is?", "answers": ["Understanding the differences the different types of clinical trials is important when working in research.  Any time you can answer an interviewer's question with confidence and correct knowledge, you increase your chances of being offered employment.", "\"A 'double-blind' trial is a clinical trial in which neither patients nor the study staff knows which participants are receiving the experimental drug and which are receiving a placebo or standard treatment.\"", "\"Yes, I do understand 'double-blind' trials.  In this type of trial, like a controlled trial, one group of participants receives the experimental drug or treatment while another group receives a placebo or standard treatment.  The difference is, in a 'double-blind', neither the staff working the trial nor the participants is aware which group is receiving which treatment.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "What are some things that you would like for others to notice about your personality?", "answers": ["When working with large groups of people, there will be a diversity of personalities and beliefs.   This question is giving the interviewer an opportunity to get to know you.  Remember, you want them to know the good qualities about you, but don't try to 'over-sell' yourself.", "\"I think one thing that people notice about me rather quickly is that I am light-hearted and easy to get along with.  Life, in general, has enough tensions.  I like to try to have a positive attitude and be the type of person that others feel they can easily approach.\"", "\"Once people get to know me, I would like to think that they consider me to be a genuine person.  Anyone can fake their way through a day, week, or even months, but I want to be considered genuine, dedicated and kind.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "What are your thoughts regarding people who become participants in a clinical trial but leave before the trial ends?", "answers": ["Although this could be mistaken as a trick question, it is not.  However, when being asked a question like this, it is important to remember to withhold judgment.   Stating your thoughts is ok as long as you think them through.", "\"Without knowing why a participant chooses to leave a trial, it would be difficult for me to say exactly how I feel about their exiting the trial.  Some people become ill or cannot take the effects of the treatment and are forced to leave while others simply change their minds.\"", "\"I imagine that people who have worked with clinical trials longer than me may be a bit more opinionated concerning the matter.  My thoughts are that each person should to weigh the risks and benefits prior to agreeing to a trial.  However,  it is understandable that some circumstances cannot be predicted.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "Can you think of a time you had a disagreement with a boss or co-worker, and if so, how was it resolved?", "answers": ["Any time you work with someone else, there is a chance of having a disagreement about something at one time or another.  The interviewer knows this.  It's human nature for people to have their own opinions.  What is important to the interviewer in this question is whether or not you are willing to compromise and work through difficult situations with your co-workers.  Being unwilling to compromise or find alternative solutions to a dispute can affect everyone on the team, even if it is indirectly.  Sharing a personal experience is OK, but do not embellish it to 'be the hero.'", "\"I believe if we think about it, each of us could remember at least one disagreement with a friend or co-worker.  Although I consider myself to be pretty easy-going, I am also very passionate about my patients and the care that they receive.  I have been aware of disagreements between other co-workers, but really like to think of myself as more of a peacekeeper.  I feel like professional people should be able to discuss things logically and come to an agreement that is satisfactory for everyone involved.\"", "\"I think the most common disagreement between myself and others have involved our personal feelings about how healthcare should be carried out.  However, I have learned, as have most of the people that I have worked with, that while our opinions are important, plans of care are designated by strict guidelines and with the input of everyone on the care team as well as the patient.  Learning to respect those guidelines and patient wishes usually resolves issues that arise.\""]}, {"topic": "Contract+Research+Organization", "question": "What do you think your best and worst qualities are?", "answers": ["No one wants to share anything negative about themselves.  However, any honest person will admit that he has both good and bad characteristics.  The important thing is recognizing the things that may need to be improved and being willing to address them.  Share some things about your personal qualities with the interviewer and remember, when sharing any quality that could be improved, tell how you are working to make a change.", "\"I would have to say that one of the things I'd like to improve about myself and that most people recognize about me is I always want to be the 'fixer.'  While I know that this is not always a negative thing, for me, I have often let the fact that I couldn't fix a certain situation be something that troubled me.  On a lighter note, I believe I have a positive, out-going personality.  I enjoy getting to know others and like to make them feel comfortable.\"", "\"My best quality, I believe, is that I am willing to work on any project I am asked to take on.  My worst quality is that I am willing to take on too many projects at once.  I've had to learn to pace myself and prioritize things that need to be done so that  am not overwhelmed and so that my quality of work does not suffer because I am too busy.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "What do you think is the most popular product or service we offer at Company ABC?", "answers": ["Your level of knowledge about Company ABC will show the interviewer just how engaged you are in the interview process. Investing time into researching Company ABC before your interview will ensure that you are prepared to impress! Discuss what you think is the most popular offering by Company ABC. This can even be an educated guess based on online reviews, particular products/services they feature on their website, or through their advertising efforts.", "\"There are a lot of great choices at Company ABC that I find exciting so that's a tough question! I see your advertisements for 'Product ABC' quite a lot so I am going to guess that this is one of your most popular offerings.\"", "\"From the research that I have conducted on your social media platforms, and website, I feel that your best services are A, and B. Is that correct? I would love to hear more.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "We believe in leading by example at Company ABC and seek to hire those who put their health first. What is the best thing you've ever done for your own personal health?", "answers": ["It's absolutely okay to give a personal answer for this type of interview question. Because Company ABC is focused on health and wellness, you should be open and real when it comes to your own personal  journey. Discuss the best choice that you've made for your personal health and the positive impact that choice has had on your life.", "\"The best decision that I ever made for my own personal health was to quit smoking cigarettes. I achieved this 4 years ago and haven't looked back since. I feel so much more energy and of course it's helped my skin as well.\"", "\"The best habit that I started for myself was to go to bed early every day so that I could wake up earlier. I am more productive this way and sleep a lot better, too.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "How do you handle stress on the job?", "answers": ["Are you someone who is able to handle stress on the job? How do you manage the stressful times? Talk to the interviewer about your ability to manage pressure in the workplace.", "\"I handle stress very well and when you call my references, they will attest to this fact. When I am under pressure on the job, I focus on the task at hand and make sure to not get distracted. Staying on deadline is very helpful and I will delegate when necessary to alleviate some stress.\"", "\"Stress is part of any demanding job and I embrace it to the fullest.  I take good care of myself personally and prioritize my workload to maintain a healthy balance in my stress levels.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Give me an example of a time when you went above and beyond.", "answers": ["Display to the interviewer that you are able to do more that the bare minimum. Show that you are able to react appropriately when you see that your employer has a need that goes beyond your usual day-to-day expectations.", "\"Last week I noticed that my manager had not completed the schedule for the following week. Some of the staff were complaining that they didn't have their work schedule yet. Rather than going to my manager with the complaint, I offered to take on some of her work load so that she would have the time to complete the schedule. We worked together for a couple of overtime hours that day and were able to catch her up on everything. It felt good to help but also benefited me by way of organization.\"", "\"Going above and beyond is what I do on a regular basis. I do not insist on sticking with \"the usual\" when it comes to the level of service that my clients receive. I will always lend a hand to my coworkers when they need it, and I offer up a smile even on the tough days.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "At Company ABC our clients come from all walks of life. Do you have experience with a broad range of people with varying needs?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you will be a great match for their customers, no matter their age, needs, or understanding of the health industry. Discuss the types of customers you have the most exposure to and be sure to highlight your ability to relate to the broad range of clientele at Company ABC.", "\"In my current position I have a range of clients from youth to retirement age. I love to help people of all ages who find value in taking care of their body. I am a friendly and talkative person which makes it easy for me to relate to customers from all walks of life. I look forward to developing relationships with your valued clients.\"", "\"Currently, the majority of clients that I work with are children; however, I am capable of working with a diverse range of clientele. I am comfortable working with all ages and backgrounds.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "What causes you to feel dissatisfied on the job?", "answers": ["Everyone will have their own particular triggers that cause them to feel dissatisfaction on the job. Talk to the interviewer about any factors that may deflate or discourage you in the workplace.", "\"I can feel dissatisfaction on the job when I am not feeling heard or when there is not a mutual respect among the team members. I work best in more harmonious situations where there is little drama or gossip.\"", "\"I have felt dissatisfied on the job when I feel underpaid and overworked. I don't mind working hard at all but I don't like to feel as though I'm being taken advantage of.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "What do you hope to gain from this position with Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you are making a move that makes sense for you and your career, at this time. Share something you are hoping to gain from this role that you are not currently receiving from your current or most recent position. \n\nMaybe the job posting says, \u201cMust be well versed in social media marketing.\u201d  You could reply with: \u201cI love using social media for business marketing but haven\u2019t had as much opportunity to do so in my current position. I see that you are seeking someone well versed and passionate in this area. It's exactly the type of responsibility have missed in my current position.\"", "\"What I am looking for, and hope to gain from this position, is the career growth that I have been missing in my current position. I would love to expand on my sales experience and leadership skills while working with a company that I am proud to be a part of.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Where did you come across our job posting, and what prompted you to apply with Company ABC?", "answers": ["The employer would like to know what methods and resources you are using in your job search so they can determine which of their methods is working best. You can expand your answer to include any other exposure you have had to the company.", "\"I initially saw your job posting on LinkedIn, however I have been exposed to your organization many times before through your radio commercials and advertisements on Facebook.\"", "\"For the last 8 months, I have been contemplating a move and keeping my eye out for the perfect opening. When I saw this position open on your website, I knew I had to go for it, and I am so happy I did. It feels right."]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Why is this job with Company ABC right for you, at this time?", "answers": ["Discuss with the interviewer why you are looking to make a change, and how this particular role fits well with the changes that you are seeking. Be sure to give a more in-depth answer than the typical \"I am looking for growth\" answer that so many interviewers hear. Be thoughtful and draw upon the research you have done on the company.", "\"This is the right job for me because it is what I have been trained to do.  My education and previous work history are related to the role and the industry, making it a perfect fit.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Although not a requirement, we prefer to hire those with some education in health, fitness, or nutrition. Walk me through any education and training you feel would add to your success with Company ABC.", "answers": ["Your education background is likely listed on your resume; however, the interviewer is looking for you to expand on that experience. If you do not have any education directly related to health, fitness, or nutrition you can choose to discuss other areas of your education that will benefit Company ABC. These areas may include business training, technical skills, or sales training for instance.", "\"The majority of my education and training is surrounding sales and marketing. I am happy to spend time learning the health and nutrition portion of your business. Because I am well educated in business, I will be able to make a positive impact in this role right away through my strong up-selling and customer service skills.\"", "\"I recently graduated with my Bachelor's degree in Kinesiology. Some of the courses that I took included Motor Control and Learning, Introduction to Research, Statistical Inquiry, \u200bHuman Anatomy and Physiology. I believe that these courses will benefit my performance when it comes to the programs and services that you offer here.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "At Company ABC we believe that health is more than just exercising. If you could recommend 3 habits to our clients,  for achieving optimal health, what would you recommend?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to ensure that you have a well-rounded idea of health, which will benefit Company ABC customers. You can discuss the best advice that you would give a potential client or talk about some healthy habits that you follow yourself.", "\"I understand the importance of guiding customers to optimal health through a well-rounded approach. If I could suggest three of my top habits, besides regular exercise, I would recommend drinking plenty of water, getting enough sleep, and avoiding unnatural food ingredients as much as possible.\"", "Here are some suggestions you could make for your clients to achieve optimal health:\n\n- Increasing vegetable intake\n- Consider good fats vs. bad fats\n- Choose good grains such as quinoa or brown rice\n- Eat more lentils \n- Try lemon water\n- Do a healthy cleanse on a routine basis \n- Reduce alcohol intake \n- Eat more fish and less red meat \n- Take the stairs whenever possible!", "Great answer! I would be prepared to expand on your answer. Why are these the 3 habits that you would recommend? This will help give the interviewer insight into your thought process."]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Company ABC is asking for 8 years of industry experience and you have just 5. Why do you think you are qualified for this position?", "answers": ["To many employers, the number of years' experience is flexible - so long as you have the results to show for the years that you do have. Talk to the interviewer about your major career successes. This is the time to sell yourself. Make no apologies for your lack of years!", "\"Although I have 5 years' experience vs 8 years' experience I can absolutely do this job well. In my previous role, I was outperforming colleagues who had 12  years of experience. To me, it's all about drive and ability to be a quick study. I have all of these qualities and more.\"", "\"Along with my 5 years working in this industry, I have worked in related industries my entire career. Also, I hope that my graduate degree gives me a little boost in experience over the required undergraduate degree.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Do you have experience in corrective discipline and terminations?", "answers": ["Terminations and corrective discipline measures can be very difficult to do but, with experience, they do get easier. Talk to the interviewer about the extent of your experience with terminations and discipline. \n\nIf you do have the experience: \"I have been a part of individual terminations and group lay-offs throughout my career. I am comfortable with these types of tasks.\"", "\"I have been a part of individual terminations and group lay-offs throughout my career. I am comfortable with these types of tasks.\"", "If you do not have the experience: \"I have not been in a position to perform terminations or hold corrective discipline meetings; however, I would be willing to perform these types of tasks with a small amount of training and research.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Rate your communication skills from 1-10 with proper examples backing your given rating.", "answers": ["On a scale of 1-10, how skilled are you in communication? Why did you choose that particular rating for yourself?", "\"I rate my communication skills as a 9/10 as I will, on occasion, have times when I am not as clear as I would like to be. My supervisor and co-workers will attest to my clear and concise communication skills. Because I am an open leader, my team will let me know if I need to clarify anything.\"", "\"I will rate myself an 8.5 because I consider myself a strong communicator.  It is the foundation of all success in business.  I am always striving to be a better communicator so I leave the rest of the scale as an aspirational measure.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "We offer growth opportunities to employees who shine! How would you like to see your career grow with Company ABC?", "answers": ["Before your interview be sure to visit Company ABC career opportunities online. Take note of the range in opportunities. Perhaps there are opportunities in other locations or one particular job posting that caught your eye. Assure the interviewer that you desire a long term opportunity with Company ABC by discussing the career path you would like.", "\"I saw a few leadership opportunities posted on your company website that seemed very interesting. Ultimately, I would like to work my way into a management role that offered opportunities for me to train new staff. I am a strong leader, and coach, and am confident I will shine in those areas.\"", "\"I am interested in a variety of paths with your company. I could absolutely see myself working in your programs department, as a Program Director, as I further my knowledge on your product and services.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Company ABC has many strong competitors. In your opinion, how do we stand out from the crowd?", "answers": ["It is important that you research Company ABC before your interview and be sure to learn about their business landscape. Who are their competitors? What are customers saying online? Check out some popular review sites to get an idea of what the public is saying about Company ABC vs their competitors. Keep your answer positive and complimentary.", "\"I believe that Company ABC stands out through the diverse range of products and services that you offer. Your seem to have a more innovative approach than most others in the marketplace.\"", "\"Your company seems to have an extra special touch when it comes to the care of your clients. Your follow up is really great and I enjoy your holistic approach.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Have you ever been a customer of Company ABC? If so, describe your experience.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you have experienced what it's like to be a customer / client of Company ABC. It is highly recommended that you try their services and /or products before your interview. 'I have never been a customer here' is never an acceptable answer. Your answer should remain positive and complimentary. Highlight the biggest take-away from your experience.", "\"My first experience as a customer of Company ABC was a couple of years ago when my friend recommend you. My experience was very positive and memorable which is a big reason why I applied here when I saw the job opening. I really got the impression that your employees were knowledgeable and highly trained.\"", "\"I am a regular client here and that's actually how I was able to find out about your job posting. My experiences at Company ABC have always been very positive and I look forward to seeing things from the other side.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "We believe in continually educating our staff at Company ABC. If we could offer you a course on any topic related to our business, what would you choose?", "answers": ["The interviewer is digging a bit deeper to learn about your specific interests within their industry. Perhaps you already know a great deal about fitness but you want to refine your education in nutrition. Pick one area where you would choose to expand your knowledge, if given the opportunity. Close your answer by expressing appreciation for the potential opportunity.", "\"I have always had a keen interest in fitness and am curious to learn more about the ways in which nutrition directly affects the body. The right foods can actually heal certain ailments and that is really interesting to me. If I could take a course on any topic related to the health industry, I would definitely choose a nutrition based topic. I am even more excited to work for Company ABC knowing that you place so much value on continued education!\"", "\"I love this question as I am a huge fan of continued education. If I could take any coursework related to the health industry, I would take something related to holistic herbal studies.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Why is health, nutrition, and weight management important to you?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to get to know you a little bit more from a personal perspective. This type of question is a great opportunity for you to stand out from the other candidates by offering a unique and memorable answer. This is not the time to give a general answer. Keep your reply brief but open and honest. Perhaps you have struggled with your weight, or helped someone in your family overcome an illness through healthy lifestyle changes!", "\"Health and nutrition has been an important part of my life from a very young age. My dad has diabetes and I have seen the positive difference it made when he started to choose a healthy lifestyle. When he exercises and makes the best food choices, he feels so much better. I think everyone should be aware of the major connection between our lifestyle choices and our quality of life.\"", "\"My story is unique because I have been on a personal weight loss journey for the past 12 months. I have lost a total of 90 pounds and have found this strong passion for helping others to see their health related dreams become reality.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Have you ever worked in a cross-functional environment?", "answers": ["If you work for a larger company, you may have been asked to work on a project with teams from another department. Your ability to work with cross-functional teams will be a big asset to your potential employer, especially if they are a larger organization. \n\nMaybe you headed a project which required you to collaborate with the members from the engineering and sales teams. You may have had the opportunity to organize a volunteer activity or team building exercise, company-wide. Share any challenges that came up and what you learned from the experience.", "\"I am regularly exposed to cross-functional teamwork in my current position. I believe that when expectations are communicated clearly from the beginning, a cross-functional team project can be very successful. I go into these types of projects with an understanding that everyone has their own strengths and limitations based on their expertise and job function.\"", "\"I have worked in a cross-functional setting for many years. Primarily with the  administrative department and the accounts receivable department. Clear communication is key when collaborating with different teams. Clarity in expectations is of huge importance.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Who would you say inspires you?", "answers": ["This question is something that you should have an answer ready for at all times. \r\nPerhaps you look up to a parent who was a hard worker or a teacher who encouraged you to become who you are today. Whomever this inspiring person may be, remember that it's an answer from the heart that the interviewer is looking for.", "\"My inspiration comes from my grandmother. She has spent every day of her life working hard and I have never once heard her complain about being tired and overworked. She taught me the value of a good reputation and I still seek out her opinion when I need inspiration.\"", "\"There are a few individuals in this industry who inspire me. I follow a few industry influencers such as Rich Froning, Jennifer Cohen, and Steve Kamb. They inspire me because they are smart, and encourage healthy eating and smart fitness regimes.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "What work situations excite and motivate you?", "answers": ["It is important, for your success, that the hiring manager knows how to keep you motivated and excited to come to work every day. Share with the interviewer what they could do to ensure that you are happy and productive.", "\"I am most motivated, on the job, when tasks are organized and the vibe is positive. I really value strong teamwork and good leadership.\"", "\"Paving new paths and creating structures to support organizations excite me the most.  I am self motivated and enjoy seeing my hard work make a difference for an organization.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "How do you like to encourage ideas in others?", "answers": ["Encouragement to others is a great skill to possess. Talk to the interviewer about your ability to encourage creative ideas in your team members.", "\"I like to encourage other people to be creative in their thinking and present ideas to the company, no matter how off the wall they may seem. Some of our most successful employees are ones who are confident in their ability to bring forward their unique ideas. I encourage participation through an open door policy and strong praise for those who show initiative.\"", "\"I like to make a positive impact on the lives of others and see them grow so I do continually encourage them, verbally. Words of affirmation can be very motivating for most people.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "How many days were you absent from work last year?", "answers": ["A part of being a diligent employee is to ensure that you are always on time and present when expected. It's great to even be 10 minutes early rather than just showing up right on the dot. Talk to the interviewer about your attendance.", "\"I had zero unexcused absences last year. In total, I took 12 vacation days out of my 15 allotted days. I was sick just 2 and those were accompanied by a note from my Doctor. Once I was late due to a terrible snow storm and I always try to be 10 minutes early for my shift.\"", "\"I was absent a total of 5 days last year, excluding my vacation time. All of my absences were previously excused by my manager.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "What is your availability?", "answers": ["Before answering scheduling questions, it's important to be clear on the interviewer's  expectations. If you haven't had a chance to clarify their scheduling needs, now would be the perfect time to ask! \n\nConsider asking, 'What are the scheduling expectations for this position?' If they expect you to work 12 hour days, it would be important for you to know that before you respond with, 'Absolutely! No problem!' You want to be sure that you can meet their expectations. \n\nIf it turns out their schedule expectations won't work for you, think about what you CAN offer and see if you can meet in the middle. It's much better to discuss these things in an interview than for you to commit to a schedule that won't work for you.", "\"I am available for full time work which is preferably 8-5 Monday to Friday. I am happy to be a team player and work some overtime, as required. Will these hours meet your expectations?\"", "\"If overtime is required in this role, I am happy to accommodate whenever I can. My only restriction is that I cannot work Wednesday nights as I have an evening course those days.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Have you ever been advised by a fellow employee or supervisor to lie about a situation? How did you handle this ethical dilemma?", "answers": ["Ethical dilemmas in the workplace will come up from time to time. Assure the interviewer that you are able to handle these types of dilemmas with professionalism and poise.", "\"I have never been told to lie to a fellow employee or supervisor on the job. If I were to be asked to lie I absolutely would not do that. I am not the type of personality to be pushed around on the job. I will always be myself and keep my integrity first.\"", "\"From my recollection, I have not been asked to lie while in the workplace. I would not tolerate being put in an ethical dilemma.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "How do you define success?", "answers": ["What does success mean to you? Tell the interviewer how you see success and be sure to tie your answer into the success that you plan to bring to this particular position, should you be offered the role.", "\"I define success by my ability to reach the goals that are set out for me. On a personal level, the things I wish to achieve in my life. On a work level, the targets that are set out for me as well as the professional development that I seek.\"", "\"To me, success means doing what you love and what you are good at, while making a difference in the lives of others.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Tell me about a time when you effectively delegated tasks.", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know that you are capable of confidently delegating tasks to your employees or coworkers.\n\nA great leader is someone who can effectively manage their time by ensuring tasks are fairly divided while utilizing the strengths of others. \nDisplay to the interviewer that you have the wherewithal to recognize the strengths of your team by delegating tasks which compliment their individual skill sets.", "\"In my current position I was asked to put together a team for a special client project. I was able to handpick the team members and organize the project execution. I chose my strongest employees in a variety of areas. In our initial meeting, I delegated the tasks while explaining my reasoning. This was a great opportunity for me to show each team member that I had the utmost confidence in their abilities. I played to their strengths and it worked out really well. We delivered to our client on time and under budget.\"", "\"Every month I have a meeting with all team members to talk about our plan for the month and how we will delegate the work. It's a great strategy for us and everyone starts the month with laid out expectations.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "What type of goals do you like to set for yourself and your team?", "answers": ["What types of goals are you most keen on setting for your employees? Talk to the interviewer about the types of goals that you find most important.", "\"I put my team's goals into three categories. Financial goals, client acquisition goals, and personal growth goals. Financial goals focus on their monetary sales targets for the quarter. Client acquisition goals are the amount of new client relationships that they bring in. And personal growth goals focus on their own professional development. This can include taking a course or reading a new career related book.\"", "\"The goals that my team focus' on most are the amount of happy clients helped, the amount of volunteer hours we have put in, and of course - our profit. We reassess these goals every month.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "When a problem requires a quick solution, how do you respond?", "answers": ["When it comes to complex problem solving, the decisions do not always come easily. It takes practice, experience, and confidence to learn what sorts of decisions yield the best results. \n\nProblems that require you to act quickly can be emergency situations such as knowing where the fire extinguisher is and grabbing it fast enough to put out small grease fire in the company kitchen. Other quick decisions could be if you are asked to take on a new responsibility and only given five minutes to decide if it's something you are prepared to take on. \n\nGoing with your gut is a skill, and the more you learn to trust your intuition, the easier it becomes to make these types of decisions. Demonstrate that you are confident and able to react swiftly when the need arises.", "\"When an urgent problem arises at work, I always try to respond in a calm and assuring manner. I am a natural leader which means that my team often looks to me for answers. One instance of my fast-thinking was just last week when we had an administrative employee no-show on a very important and busy day for us. I called a temp agency and they had the position filled in just one hour.\"", "\"I react swiftly in emergency situations. Perhaps my skills come from my years as a parent, having to think fast and put out fires! If a quick solution is required I will do a fast overview of the facts and make a decision based on risk factors.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "What is your current salary?", "answers": ["A potential employer will often base their offer on your current salary. You should be transparent about your most recent earnings and be prepared to back up any salary requests.", "\"I am currently earning a base salary of $78,000 plus a car allowance of $900/month and health benefits. I am looking for a competitive salary in my next position.\"", "\"I am currently making $100,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Health", "question": "Tell me a little bit about yourself.", "answers": ["Many interviewers will start off with this question, which could throw you off a bit. You've done all of this research on the company but have you prepared to talk about yourself?  \n\nThe interviewer is looking for relevant information to the position you applied for. Respond by mentioning your education, how many years of experience you have in your field, and be sure give some details about your most current position. Conclude your response with a statement about what you are looking for in a position at this time.", "\"With pleasure!  I have over 10 years in experience with selling professional services and am interested in growing my career to the next level. On a more personal note, I love to read, go hiking and spend a lot of my extra time volunteering with the humane society.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "To work at Company ABC, you have to be really passionate about compliance and accuracy.  Tell me why this is important to you.", "answers": ["Many people might not understand why the area of billing and medical coding are important and the interviewer wants to ensure you aren't just looking for your next job, but you genuinely care about the impact your role can make for your clients on the receiving end (who work directly with patients.  Talk about the importance of your work", "\"We've all been on the receiving end of getting an incorrect bill.  People who have been to the hospital or clinic don't have the time or energy for those kinds of mistakes.  Through my work, I can make sure patients can focus on getting better rather than making phone calls to figure out an incorrect bill.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "The health insurance industry is very complex.  All of our positions require strong organizational skills and attention to detail. How do you ensure that your work is properly organized, and highly accurate?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about the ways that you ensure accuracy and organization in your day to day activities. Perhaps you use a particular app or software. Maybe you are a pen and paper person. Whatever your method, be sure to highlight that you are successful in organizing your day.", "\"I am a highly detailed person, and I thrive on having a high level of organization in my day. This organization includes my scheduling, paperwork, and more. If I am offered a position with Company ABC you will never find me to be disorganized! I utilize my Outlook calendar and set alerts for myself for deadlines and important activities. My documentation is strong as well.\"", "\"I'm a bit of a nerd.  I carry around a notebook and write down important facts if I think there is a chance I will forget them. However, I put time and attention into using the latest technology that others on my team are leveraging so we can be more efficient.  If there is a way we can share information, it will help everybody!\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "We encourage professional curiosity in our workplace and an entrepreneurial mindset.  If you could start your own business, what would you do?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants a glimpse into your passion outside of work, but also your savvy as a small business owner working with your own budget.  It is ok to be creative with this answer.", "\"I love teaching yoga and have dreamed of opening my own studio.  I have a plan put together on how I could achieve this from the space element, to how many classes per week we would want, to how many workers I would need.  I still need a bit more capital to get it off the ground, but hope to have this side business one day.  Yoga is amazing for health and wellness and it has helped me greatly in my own life.\"", "\"If I could start any business, I would want to do photography professionally.  I love taking pictures and experimenting with lenses, angles, and technology.  I have taken pictures for friends and family and they seem really happy with what I'm doing.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "We want to hire people who can grow within our company.  When have you stretched yourself in your current role and done more than what was expected of you?", "answers": ["The interview wants to know that you are scalable within the organization and can grow to a higher level role in the future.  Discuss a time when you solved a problem before your manager knew it existed or when you anticipated a need within the business.", "\"I noticed that our department was utilizing Excel spreadsheets for complex reports.  The process was very manual and took about 1 hour out of everybody's day.  I noticed we had a new database tool after a recent software upgrade, so I research it, tested it, and then brought the idea to my manager as an alternative.  She loved the idea and has now asked me to train the whole team on how to use it\"", "\"I'm really excited to grow within the organization.  I noticed that our team was tracking customer conversations slightly differently making reporting very difficult.  I developed a key so that everybody knew exactly how to code and created consistency amongst the team.  The data in the reports was much better and more accurate after that\"."]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "At Company ABC, we have many positions where employees work remotely 99% of the time.  How would you set yourself up for success at your home office?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to see that you have a plan in how you will work from home successfully.  Some people can't handle this lack of structure, so show that you are able to be very productive.", "\"I was able to work from home a few days a week in my last role.  I have a specific routine I follow.  Working in pajamas does NOT happen in my house- I dress as if I was going to work, go to a specific office space in my home, and take regular breaks as I would in the office.  I utilize Skype and chat features to keep in touch with colleagues so it doesn't feel isolating.\"", "For example: \"I enjoy the flexibility that working from home offers.  Last year, when I was in school, I had several on-line courses versus classroom courses.  I made sure I was in a quiet place, free of noise and distraction, so I could fully focus on the material.  I also took advantage of all the on-line communities so it felt like my \"classmates\" were accessible.  I also met with people face-to-face when I had the chance so that we built a relationship.  I would use all of these tools in this position."]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "The health industry is strongly influenced by changing legislation.  How do you stay current with new rules and regulations that impact our industry?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to make sure you are staying up to date with changing regulations and that you are motivated to do so.  You not only have to be aware, but then recommend changes that need to happen in the organization to comply.", "\"I subscribe to several blogs on this topic and make sure I'm reading the news.  I try to take 15-30 minutes a day during lunch to read.  If anything I'm hearing would cause a major process change, I think about whether or not I can handle it for my team or if it needs to be elevated to my leader.\"", "For example:  \"I joined an association who sends out updates any time there is a changing regulation that could impact our function.  We actually talk about best practices at each of our places of work so we are sharing information.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "Company ABC, seeks to hire those with strong problem solving skills. When were you able to successfully resolve a problem in the workplace?", "answers": ["Problem-solving and dispute resolution are critical skills to possess. Display to the interviewer that you are capable of problem-solving within the workplace. Talk about a time when you were creative, proactive, and displayed the leadership qualities required to resolve a workplace issue.", "\"In my most recent position we had a consistent problem with employees showing up late for their shifts or calling in sick at the very last moment. Rather than the typical documenting and reprimanding style that management usually takes, I decided to track the results of an accountability reward system. For 180 days, my employees were rewarded for coming to work 10 minutes early. Also, for every month with zero sick days, a bonus was added. In the end, we awarded those with perfect attendance a $600 bonus. The bonus' cost us less money, in the end than the cost of lowered productivity due to absent employees. The program was a success, and upper management chose to keep it implemented for another six months. We will re-assess in December, but it seems to be working very well.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "What inspired you to apply for this position at Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer is looking to hear what in particular, has led you to apply.  Pick out exciting elements from the job post, parts about the company you love from your research, making sure to show enthusiasm and passion in your answer.", "\"I applied for this position at Company ABC because I want to make navigating health insurance easier for everybody.  I saw that this is one of your strategic initiatives and I could truly make an impact in this role.\"", "For example:  \"I wasn't actively looking for new roles, but after reading the job ad for this role, I felt like I couldn't pass it up.  It sounds like an exciting adventure into some new spaces for the company and I love building new programs and systems.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "At Company ABC, we deal with confidential patient data.  Tell me about a time you followed HIPAA regulations even when it wasn't easy or convenient to do so.", "answers": ["The HIPAA privacy rules are paramount in the health insurance industry.  The amount of patient data you have access to is overwhelming.  Make sure you can show your understanding of the rules while displaying your own personal integrity in upholding them.", "\"I was faxing over some patient data to a clinic.  I didn't get a confirmation back so I checked the fax number and it was not correct and went to the wrong location.  I could have just walked away and gone back to my desk, but not knowing who was on the receiving end of that data, I had to report the incident.  I felt awful about it, but it was quickly resolved and if I would have said nothing, it could have escalated into a huge fine for the company.  Plus, I'm an honest person, so I had to tell the truth.\"", "For example:  \"My neighbor got into a car accident a few weeks ago and she told me that some of her claims had been denied.  She begged me to go into work to see what I could find out.  I had to tell her there was no way I could do that and it was a huge HIPAA violation.  I mentioned to her that she should call our Company ABC call center and asked for Lynn, who I knew could help her.  I felt bad that she put me in that position, but good I could give her a person to call who could hopefully address her concerns.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "Patients are becoming increasingly technology savvy and have higher expectations than ever from our industry.  Innovation is required to provide more cost effective and high value care.  Tell me about a new idea you recommended in your current role.", "answers": ["In the US, everybody knows that health care is expensive.  Eventually, innovative minds will come together to find a better solution.  In the meantime, tell the interviewer about a new idea you've had that impacted your department and the business.", "\"The idea of paying for performance is a concept we discuss often in my current company.  In my current role, I recommended a different data point to analyze, track and measure to help us understand out patients better and then see if the coverage levels could be influenced to create different plans for the next calendar year.  We are still at beginning stages, but my leader was elated that I thought of this .\"", "For example: \"Patients like apps so all of their information is at their finger tips.  However, I have the app and noticed there wasn't an easy way to get to the provider website from the claim.  Many of the questions people have aren't on the health plan side, but are for their provider.  I spoke to the IT team about this and adding some quick links was actually a really simple add.  We have seen higher ratings for our app since implementing this.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "This role would involve sales to new partners who want to offer their employees our health insurance.  What are some ways you add value to prospective clients so that you can have meaningful discussions?", "answers": ["The interviewer is looking to see how you add value through the sales process to prospective clients.  Gone are the days of calling around and fishing for information.  You can find most of what you need online and you need to be prepared so that the door doesn't slam in your face.", "\"I'm able to research their company financials and employee demographics to understand how our insurance products could be the best benefit to them.  Then, I ask around to see who the decision maker is  so that I'm trying to get in front of the right person.  When I call, I'm able to present a data set that makes it hard to refuse a meeting with me!\"", "For example:  \"I utilize all of the Salesforce tools to keep very good notes about all of my prospective clients.  I remember things about them that seem small, but give me an edge.  I do much more listening than talking to understand what the pain points are, and then put solutions together that specifically address their needs, not what I think they need.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "What is your patient care philosophy or customer care philosophy (if coming from different industry)?", "answers": ["It's always a great idea to research the company before your interview. You want to get to know their care philosophy so that your answer can reflect what is important to them. What is the core of your care philosophy? Keep your answer concise yet sincere.", "\"Every day at work, I remind myself that everyone I come across has their struggles. Every person we care for has a story. I make sure to get to know my customers as best I can.  Everyone has the right to be treated compassionately.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "Our goal is to hire people who are very ambitious.  Tell me about a time you went the extra mile, even when it may not have been required or asked of you.", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to make sure you fit with Company ABC's culture and ambition is very important to them.  Highlight examples were you went that extra step without being asked.", "\"My manager asked me to review a spreadsheet of providers to make sure they were credentialed properly at a certain medical facility.  Upon looking at the spreadsheet, I noticed many errors in the spelling of people's names as well as fields on the document that didn't make sense.  Instead of just making sure they had all the missing pieces of the credentialing process, I cleaned up the entire spreadsheet to make sure everything was accurate so that reports would have the proper data.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "At Company ABC, we have large patient data sets we need to analyze.  Tell me about a large data set you had to analyze and how you added value through your analysis.", "answers": ["Data analysis is becoming a critical part of any role.  Demonstrate an analysis you did that truly made an impact for the business.", "\"I was looking at year over year data and noticed a huge increase in the amount of claims for heart related incidents in the month of March and April.  I did a bit of research on the demographics of the patients in the 45 and under category and it was an unusually high number of women. I pulled in our community relations team and they started asking more questions when they are are community engagement events.  The stress and anxiety levels of women in that age bracket was very high.  After showing my leader this data, she worked with the leader of the community relations to provide more outreach and education to women in this group.   Our efforts resulted in a smaller number of claims the following year.\"", "\"I watch our department budget like a hawk.  I have to analyze financial data month over month and year over year to make sure everything aligns.  I enjoy this work- it is like putting puzzle pieces together so that all of our needs are met.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "We work with patients and customers who are confused or upset about their medical insurance.  Tell me about a time you had to teach and train an upset customer.  How did you handle the situation and what was the outcome?", "answers": ["Health insurance can be very complex to the average person and the interviewer wants to know if you can handle a person who is very upset.  Show that you care about each caller and that you have empathy for that individual.  Showcase your problem solving skills and the fact you can handle a high degree of emotion on the phone without getting rattled, still helping the customer, and trying to get them what they need.", "\"I had a caller the other week who was crying because her insurance didn't cover a procedure that she had a month prior.  She was very upset and stated that she couldn't afford to pay this bill.  I let her talk without interrupting her and listened.  I repeated back to her what the issue was to make sure I understood her correctly.  I took her information down and looked up her account to see what her insurance covered.  I discovered that our insurance did cover 80% of the procedure, but she had to pay for the other 20%.  Through further conversation in a calming voice, I was able to tell her that insurance did cover a big portion of the procedure and gave her the number of the financial assistance office at the hospital to see if they could put her on a payment plan for the remaining portion.  I knew from my experience that most health care systems offer this.  She sounded relieved and grateful when we hung up and thanked me for my help.\"", "\"I had a caller who didn't know what his statement meant- he said all of the medical terminology didn't make sense to him.  I wrote down his questions and then pulled up his statement and walked him through each part so he understood the statement.  He actually didn't have any payments he would be responsible for, so he was very happy.  He didn't know this until I took the time to walk him through the statement.  He thanked me at the end of the call.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "At Company ABC, we've invested in the latest technology to create efficient work flows. Tell me how you've gone about learning new technology in the past?", "answers": ["In health care, technology is changing rapidly.  You need to demonstrate expertise in electronic systems and embrace learning new technology.", "\"I am currently use a proprietary CRM that our company develop.  This is where I track all of my conversations with customers.    I also use all of the Microsoft Office tools and especially love OneNote.  The has eliminated my need to have post-it notes and I'm better able to keep track of everything.  When I stated this role, it took me about 1 week to learn the system and then I was fully up and running.\"", "\"In my internships, I used a lot of Office 365 tools, especially Power Point and Excel.  I have put together at least 20 presentations this year alone!  Learning new technology comes easy to me because I grew up with it and can watch YouTube videos if I don't understand something right away.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "At Company ABC, we do a lot of community education trying to help the people in our local communities understand their health insurance.  Tell me about outreach you have done in the community in your previous role.\"", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to make sure you are comfortable presenting information in public.  People in the health insurance industry are asked to speak frequently, so making sure you have the skills to teach others is critical.", "\"I have led sessions at community meetings for people who might not know what kind of coverage they have.  This is one of the best parts about my job because I can see the light bulb go off in their heads when they see how their specific insurance plan applies to them and what kinds of free, an preventative, services are available.\"", "\"I love volunteering in my town.  I signed up to be a mentor for a girl in my community and I read to her every Tuesday.  I haven't had the opportunity to talk about health insurance to a public audience, but I am sure asked a lot of questions at family dinners and holidays.  I provide a wealth of education to my own family about how to make the most out of their insurance and understand the claims process.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "This role requires patient collection, so you might have to have difficult conversations. Tell me about a difficult conversation you've had with a patient or customer.", "answers": ["Company ABC requires cash collection for unpaid bills.  This is nobody's favorite part of the job, but it is really important that the company collect the cash owed to them.  Describe how you've kept your cool with difficult customers in the past.", "\"I know it isn't health care related, but back in college when I was a waitress, I had a very upset customer at the restaurant who didn't have his meat prepared the way he wanted.  I apologized, but he was very upset to the point of yelling.  I tried to stay calm so I wouldn't appear rattled. He did stop eventually- I apologized again, told him I would comp his meal, and that I would talk to the chef.  I also asked him if he would like to order something different.  He did end up choosing another option and was quiet after that.\"", "\"I used to work in a call center, so I often had customers upset about the fact they had to wait a long time to talk to a \"live person\".  I had one customer who went on and on about how her time was valuable and how she couldn't believe it took her this long to get a real person on the end of the line.  I let her vent and then apologized.  I told her I was here now and asked how I could help her.  I listened very carefully to what she needed and instead of passing her to another individual when she asked me a question I didn't know,  I was able to have her hold while I found out the answer instead of transferring her.  She was grateful I was able to help her and had calmed down by the end of the call.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "Many of our jobs at Company ABC require us to do projects when there is down time.  Can you give an example of a project you led start to finish?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you are capable of taking on more work, outside your normal job responsibilities and can flex higher level skills.  The project doesn't need to be huge in scope, but make sure to highlight what you did, as opposed to using the words WE.", "\"I always have a list of projects to work on and I really enjoy them.  I had the opportunity to lead a project designed at creating a peer feedback review process.  My manager discovered errors in some of the work from our team.  I had the idea to create a double-check where a peer reviewed the work.  It did take more time, but was very help in reducing errors.  We were able to reduce errors by 90%.  My manager was really pleased and team was happy and proud of the work being done.\"", "Since I'm a new grad, I haven't led any projects at work yet, but when I was a college student, I completed a project for a local health care system where I did an audit of all of their credentialed providers.  My goal was to see if there were any parts of the process I could automate so that the manual checks could be faster.  I was able to set up a feed with the state licensing board which eliminated the need for somebody to manually check their license.  It was a great project and I know I added value to them, even as a college student!\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "If you could expand your knowledge and expertise in any area of the health plan space, which would you choose?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to dig deeper into your true areas of interest when it comes to the health care industry. They want to know that  your passions align well with what UnitedHealth Group is offering. Talk to the interviewer about the areas of health care you would like to focus on most, and then tie that information in with what the position at UnitedHealth Group would be offering you.", "\"If I could expand my expertise in any health care service area I would choose a role that had the most impact on patient lives.  This is one of the reasons I have applied with your company. I feel that your focus will be a great fit with my long-term career goals.\"", "\"I'm interested in research.  One of the things that attracted me to working with your company is your ongoing community-based research collaborations.  I'd be curious to hear if Company ABC has any needs in this area.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "At Company ABC, we believe in continuous feedback.  Tell me about a time you received constructive feedback.  What did you do after hearing this?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know if you can take criticism without getting your feelings hurt.  In today's workplace, you can't be afraid to give or receive criticism.  It is ok to be candid, but show your future employer that you heard the feedback and did something about it.", "\"I received feedback from my manager that because I was pushing for so many new ideas, it seemed like I knew more than everybody else- especially some of the staff who had been here for many years.  I took this feedback and decided to include others on my team in shaping some of the new ideas I had before bringing them up in the team meeting.  This approach really helped to get their buy-in.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "Tell me about your healthcare related education and training.", "answers": ["Take a few minutes to walk the interviewer through your formal post-secondary education as well as any on the job training. Talk about your most positive take-away's from your post-secondary experience and be sure to tie in how that experience will help you succeed in this position.", "\"I thought I wanted to be a nurse, but I don't like all of the bodily fluids associated with it!  I have very strong attention to detail and I'm good with numbers and analysis, so decided to pursue a Medical Coding degree.  I had some great internships where I had to balance many responsibilities at one time, preparing me for a job at Company ABC.\"", "\"I decided to pursue a degree in Health Information Management after learning more about it at a college visit.  I had no idea what it was, but I'm so happy I found it.  The courses were so interesting and there is much more to it than people realize.  I had to do a lot of multi-tasking with a full course-load plus an evening job to pay for college.  This experience with time management as well as the specific HIM courses I took will prepare me well for this role at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "At Company ABC, innovation is really important to us.  Give an example of an innovative idea you've had recently.", "answers": ["Most companies are trying to work smarter, not harder.  What are some ways, (even simple ways) you've been able to innovate in your work environment?", "\"When I started in my current role, I noticed that we were spending a lot of time playing phone tag with our clients.  I started to use a calendar app that syncs with my Outlook calendar to eliminate all of the back and forth.  After implementing this, I think I have saved 4 hours a week.  I showed it to all of my team mates and now the whole company is using it!\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "How do you connect with a customer you are working with virtually?", "answers": ["At Company ABC, many of the roles involved customer service with people on a chat or via email.  The interviewer wants to know if you can effectively resolve their questions while building a relationship.", "\"Even if we are having a virtual conversation, I still try to be as personable as possible.  I can typically see what area of the country the customer is, so I'll ask them about the weather or a sporting event in their town while resolving their question.  My drop off rate is pretty low, so I think this approach has worked well.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "If Company ABC hired you today, what would you accomplish first?", "answers": ["When you start a new position, it is essential to set a goal on how you will make a positive impact quickly after being hired. Tell the interviewer what your impact goal is, should you be the successful candidate. If you want to make an impact with your answer, refer to the immediate needs of the company such as creating efficiencies, or updating technology.", "\"It is important to understand the business inside and out, so I would want to meet with people in all areas.  Then, I would work with you on a 30, 60, 90 day plan so we can review the most important elements to work on.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "What is your process of explaining technical information to people who aren't technical?", "answers": ["Company ABC works with providers who have patients who utilize our insurance.  However, while physicians are smart, many are not familiar with the platform and don't know about new technologies.  Explain how you have been effective in communicating technical info so they can understand it.", "\"I try to put some feelers out there on their level so I can speak to it.  I give lots of examples of what the technology is like and many visuals to explain what it does.  I also walk through the data visually so they can see the impact of the numbers.\"", "For example:  \"I speak in the simplest terms possible.  If I start to get more technical questions from the group, I will up my game a bit and speak more technically, but then re-phrase for all of those folks who aren't at that level.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "At Company ABC, sometimes we have to make difficult decisions on whether or not a medical service is covered.  In the past, how have you been able to put aside your personal feelings for the good of the business?", "answers": ["You have to make very difficult decisions in the health insurance industry and some of them don't feel great when you have a patient who is impacted.  Ensure the interviewer knows you can handle a difficult situation and do your job effectively.", "\"I was working with a patient going through a very difficult time and had a procedure that just wasn't covered.  There was an alternative that was, but she had decided that wasn't the best route for her to take.  I felt really awful giving her this news, but I knew I couldn't approve it.  I did mention the scenario to my leader to double check I had done the right thing and she verified that I made a good call.\"", "For example: \"I have a lot of empathy for others, so these situations are hard.  I worked with a gentleman who had a denied claim and tried to point him in the direction of community resources that could possibly help him pay for some of his expenses.  I also referred him to a social worker at the hospital where he had his surgery to see what resources and payment plans they could come up with for him.  I tried to give him the best service and look into as many alternatives as possible.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "At Company ABC, we want a world class call center where each team member is empowered to give feedback to others.  Tell me about a time you gave feedback to a colleague.", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to make sure you are comfortable giving feedback to others, even if you aren't a supervisor.  Demonstrate that you are confident in delivering a feedback message to others.", "\"I heard my colleague on the phone and she was struggling from the very beginning.  I could hear agitation in her voice after 30 seconds into this call.  I couldn't hear what the caller was saying, obviously, but I could hear her frustration.  After the call ended, I asked her what happened.  She said the caller was very rude and was very upset and she felt really hurt about what he was saying.  I talked with her about some ways to handle upset customers and about listening and staying calm.  She said she knew that, but I told her that frustration was very apparent.  She seemed a little off-put for a few days, but later in the week, she thanked me for being honest with her.\"", "For example: \"We were listening to some calls as a group so we could learn from each other.  I noticed that people have a hard time speaking up when we are in these situations, but I try to find one positive and negative thing to say about each call and the way the representative handled it.  I'm not afraid to voice my opinion and I know it will help not only the rep who dealt with that caller, but the whole team.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "At Company ABC, we have many health insurance competitors that we need to have a pulse on.  In your current role, how do you stay up to date with competitors?", "answers": ["All private health insurance companies are vying for the business.  If a competitor has a product that could impact the business, you need to know.  Likewise, if a competitor is struggling, you might be able to create an advantage for Company ABC.", "\"I set up Google alerts for all the major competitors so I can follow them.  I read something in an obscure business journal about one of our competitors having some financial trouble, so I reached out to several of their clients the next day to see what the pulse was.  They were also nervous and uncertain about the future of their current provider, so were much more willing to have conversations with me about our product.  I'm still in the middle of the contract process, but it looks promising so far.\"", "For example: \"I have relationships wit all of the sale team members at our major competitors.  I find it easier to have friends versus enemies because I know what is going on at their companies before it hits the news.  Often times, because I've built a solid relationship with that sales team, they give me leads that could be a good fit for our business and don't fit their product offerings.  I try to help them when I can as well, when it makes sense.\""]}, {"topic": "Health+Insurance", "question": "At Company ABC, we believe in transparency with our health insurance customers and our employees.  Tell me about your leadership style in regards to transparency?", "answers": ["Internal employees are expecting complete transparency when working with Company ABC.  The modern job seeker knows that employers make mistakes and are likely to forgive mistakes as long as there is transparency and ownership.", "\"I try to be a vulnerable leader at work.  Openly discussing mistakes and errors teaches the team that it is ok to fail, but hopefully we fail fast and then move on to solutions that work.  Transparency leads to innovation.\"", "For example: \"I start all of my team meetings with successes and failures, so everybody has a chance to say what is on their mind.  This regular exercise gets the team comfortable talking about the things that aren't going very well, that are often hidden.  We've been doing this for 6 months now, and the room went from quiet to very enthusiastic and supportive.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "What do you know about the workplace culture at Company ABC? What is your ideal workplace environment?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about the research you have conducted when it comes to the workplace culture at Company ABC. Assure the interviewer that you would find their workplace culture a stable fit.", "\"I have researched the workplace culture at Company ABC and feel that your environment is a perfect fit for what I am seeking. You encourage continued education of your employees and foster a collaborative environment.\"", "\"My ideal workplace environment will include leaders who are encouraging and comfortable giving constructive feedback. I also prefer to work in an environment where growth and continued education is encouraged. I have heard great things about working for Company ABC, and from what I understand, you offer exactly this type of environment.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to hire healthcare professionals who have passion for our industry. If you could increase public awareness on any healthcare related issue, which would you choose?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about the areas of healthcare that bring passion to you. Is there a particular issue that you would carry more public awareness to if you could?", "\"There are so many healthcare issues that I am passionate about, but if I could choose one, I wish that the general public were more aware of the signs and dangers of undiagnosed childhood diabetes.\"", "\"This is a very tough question as there are so many underfunded, and worthy, healthcare issues. I am going to go with one of my biggest areas of interest and research. If I could increase public awareness on any healthcare related issue, I would choose pancreatic cancer. Yes, cancer does receive a lot of awareness; however, pancreatic cancer does not. This year, over 53,000 people in the USA will be diagnosed with pancreatic cancer nearly 80% will die from the disease - both men and women.\"", "\"If I could increase public awareness on any healthcare related issue, I would choose the early detection of kidney disease or people being aware of signs, symptoms, and dangers of undiagnosed diabetes. Those topics are important to me because my high school best friend died of kidney failure at age 30. She was too young, and that could have been prevented if she had the knowledge.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "How do you handle communicating bad news to a fellow worker or subordinate?", "answers": ["One of the toughest parts of communication can be delivering bad news to people that you work with and for whom you care. Whether it is providing a less than positive work review or terminating someone, giving bad news is not an easy task. Assure the interviewer that you can handle this type of duty in a transparent, concise, and professional manner.", "\"I certainly do not enjoy communicating bad news to a co-worker, but I do have experience in doing so. When this type of task is required of me, I make sure to practice empathy. Truth is always key, so I will be honest and clear when communicating the news. For instance, if I am to terminate someone's employment, I will not sugar coat the reasons why. It's best they know so that they can learn from the experience.\"", "\"I am very to-the-point when it comes to my communication skills. Good or bad news, there is always a way to improve the situation and create something good from it. After delivering bad news, I will work with my coworker to find a viable solution.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "Do you consider yourself a patient person? How do you increase your patience level in challenging situations?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you consider yourself a patient individual. Impatience can cause a lot of stress and anxiety in coworkers, so it is essential that you can showcase your ability to remain patient and professional in workplace situations. \n\nPatience is indeed a virtue but can be challenging to maintain when it seems that situations continue to push your buttons. Show the interviewer that you possess the ability to keep your cool in challenging conditions.", "\"I do consider myself a patient person. I would rate myself an eight /10 for patience because I certainly have room to grow, but I do have a very long fuse. If I need a boost of patience in a challenging situation, I will take a step away, count to 10 and then return to the situation. I recently read a book, 'The Power of Patience' by M.J. Ryan which also gave me some excellent new methods for coping with stress.\"", "\"I was once working with a group that could not quite get along, and it tested my patience a bit because it prevented us from staying on track and focusing on the goals.  I went above and beyond in helping the group get along by scheduling lunches as a team and helping to mediate situations that needed it.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to hire individuals who value education. Walk me through your related post-secondary education. Where did you struggle the most? Which courses were your favorite?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about your post-secondary education. Discuss your high points and the more challenging points.", "\"I graduated with a Bachelor of Science in Nursing from Felician College in 2009. While attending University, I feel that my most challenging course was Statistics for Life Sciences. I completed this course with a B grade. My best course was in Mental Health Studies. I found it to be fascinating and graduated top of my class in that course.\"", "\"I recently graduated with my degree in Clinical Medical Assisting. There were many challenges along the way; however, I would say that my overall experience was incredibly positive. If I had to choose my biggest struggle, I would say that Anatomy and Physiology were the most in-depth. With that said, I did receive very high grades in those courses. My favorite subject of study, overall, was Pharmacology.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "At Company ABC we see a lot of candidate interest for positions such as this. Why are you the best candidate for us?", "answers": ["What makes you a stand-out candidate when there are so many other potential candidates for Company ABC to consider? Talk to the interviewer about the qualities that make you the best candidate for them.", "\"There are a lot of talented people in the healthcare pool but what makes me stand out is my willingness to take feedback. I am a humble employee. Also, I am a dedicated worker. I have had just one sick day in 5 years.\"", "\"I believe that I am the best candidate for you because of my double degree in both Healthcare Management, and Health Services Administration. In addition to these studies, I am also bilingual in both English and Spanish. This skill will enable me to communicate very clearly with your predominantly Spanish community.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "When have you been asked to perform a function or complete a task in which you had little or no experience in doing?", "answers": ["Have you ever had to take on a task or a role that you felt was over your experience level? Talk to the interviewer about a time when you have dealt with this type of situation. What was the outcome, and what did you learn?", "\"When my manager went on unexpected medical leave for three months last year I was asked to step into her position in the interim. I knew the basics but was certainly not trained on the specifics of the role. I was able to take it on successfully by leaning on my team, reading a lot of company manuals, and asking many questions. Once my manager returned she was very pleased with the progress that I made, and I received a promotion.\"", "\"At times, I will be asked to perform tasks in our computer system that I am not completely familiar with. When this happens, I will not ask for help right away. Rather, I will search for the answer either in our manuals or online. I am comfortable taking on new tasks and enjoy learning new skills.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to hire individuals dedicated to their professional development. If you could improve your knowledge on any healthcare related topic, which would you choose?", "answers": ["Being dedicated to your professional development and knowledge is a huge bonus for most employers. Talk to the interviewer about the area of healthcare that you would expand your knowledge if given the opportunity.", "\"I feel that I can always learn more about compassionate care and the techniques surrounding long-term compassionate care. I like the idea of professional development and am open to any coursework you suggest.\"", "\"There is always more to learn in a variety of areas; however, I would especially enjoy furthering my education and training in pediatric care. I find children to be most interesting to work with.\"", "\"I'd choose more knowledge in my field of nursing and get certified. It would make me more confident and help me better serve my patients.\"", "Good answer! If I were the interviewer I would probably follow up and ask why nephrology specifically (unless we had clearly touched on this in previous questions)."]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "What type of career growth would you like to see with Company ABC? How can we help you to advance?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about the ways that you would like to grow in your career over the next few years. The company wants assurance that you see this as a long-term fit and they want to know how to help you grow.", "\"I would like to grow into a leadership role in the next 3-4 years. Any additional training in leadership, mentorship, and management would be a great way to help me advance in your organization.\"", "\"Thank you for asking! I would love to advance into medical billing and coding once I have enough experience in general health services administration. I foresee this happening in the next 2-3 years and am committing to this path by attending evening classes and a few related workshops.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "Who has inspired you in your life and why?", "answers": ["Your life's inspiration can come from a book, a mentor, your family, a celebrity, author - literally anyone! Talk to the interviewer about who has inspired your life and why.", "\"I find inspiration in a variety of people and things. I would have to say that the person who has most greatly inspired me has been my grandmother. She always had a smile on her face no matter how hard she worked and she loved everyone. She was well respected and always gave more than she received. I try to live like her as much as I can.\"", "\"The previous physician that I worked under was a huge inspiration to me. Her passion for patient health and her career successes were motivating and put the fire in me to climb the ladder in my career.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus based on our facilities profits. Last year my earnings were $52,000, and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I am currently making $80,000 per year.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "Do you think it is possible to be a good team member, yet disagree with the leader?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you can be diplomatic in the workplace, even when you may not agree with your leader. \n\nShow the interviewer that it is possible for you to be a good team member, yet disagree with the leader from time to time. Explain that you believe everyone is entitled to their own professional opinion, yet capable of maintaining respect for each other at the same time. \nShow that even if you disagree with the final decision they make, you support the direction the team is heading.", "\"I think that it is possible to be a great team member, even when disagreeing with the leader. It's all in how you maintain respect for each other despite the difference in opinion.\"", "\"Yes, I think it is possible! What makes a great team member is not that they agree with everything but the level of respect and positive thought that goes into the person's communication style. It's okay to disagree you have to communicate your thoughts professionally.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "In the healthcare industry, problems arise frequently. When a major problem arises, what is your first reaction?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know if your reactions to problems reflect maturity and professionalism. How you react will significantly determine how you fit with their existing team. \n\nPerhaps your computer crashes, and you realize you may have just lost all of your hard work. Or maybe you are limited on time and have a deadline rapidly approaching. Demonstrate to the interviewer that you take a very methodical approach to problem-solving, rather than reacting impulsively when a problem occurs.", "\"When a major problem arises, my first instinct is to take a step back and absorb what just happened. I then go into \"", "\"I have taught myself to become much calmer with my first reactions when problems arise. Now, I will step back and review my options for solving the problem rather than allow myself to become frustrated.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "What do you feel we do best here at Company ABC?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to feel confident that you are engaged in the interview process. Display that you have researched Company ABC before your interview and getting to know what they do best. Talk about your research and findings.", "\"I have researched Company ABC quite extensively and through my research, I feel that your specialty is XYZ. This area is where your patient feedback is mostly positive, which was great to read!\"", "\"As your website and advertisements say, you are the best in the area for patient compassion. I could not agree more that compassion is the number one area we should be great when it comes to the healthcare industry.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "There are many options for employment in the healthcare field. Why do you want to work for Company ABC?", "answers": ["What attracts you to this position with Company ABC? Talk to the interviewer about your primary reasons for being drawn to this role. Solidify your answer by clearly stating your interest in landing the role.", "\"I want to work for Company ABC because your industry reputation is second to none. I am seeking a long-term career opportunity in an emotionally and physically healthy environment. I would love to work here.\"", "\"There are multiple reasons why I want to work for your organization. First, you are best in the industry for my particular specialty (insert specialty). Second, your workplace culture is collaborative and positive. Third, I feel that your community would offer me the growth that I crave in my career, and the opportunity to advance from within.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "In your opinion, what is the most important quality you can possess as a healthcare professional?", "answers": ["Think about the qualities you admire in other healthcare professionals. Talk to the interviewer about the qualities that you feel a healthcare provider should possess. Do you have these qualities?", "\"I feel that the most important qualities that a healthcare professional can possess are endless compassion, dedication, and a thirst for knowledge. I do possess these qualities and am excited to think about my potential growth with Company ABC by applying these qualities.\"", "Here are some additional qualities that healthcare professionals should possess: \n\n- Clear communicator \n- Avid listener \n- Easy to understand\n- Ready to put patient needs first (selfless)\n- Desire to help\n- Integrity in all they do\n- Professionalism \n- Detail oriented \n-  Able to self-manage\n- Healthy coping skills\n- Empathetic\n- Motivated \n- Ethical"]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "Working in healthcare is a very demanding career path. What keeps you motivated on the hardest days?", "answers": ["When you are having an especially stressful day, what keeps you motivated to continue? How can the interviewer be assured that you will always bring your 'A' game no matter what challenges you face?", "\"I can stay motivated, even on the tough days, because I know that my career focuses on helping people. I love to assist others and to know that I make a difference is all that I need.\"", "\"My motivation comes primarily from within me. I am skilled when it comes to pushing myself, and I remind myself on a regular basis that I am here to help others. I have a true servant-hood mentality, which drives me. In addition to this factor, I find external motivation from working with positive people who can teach me along the way. New knowledge and a fresh approach are fantastic motivators.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "In your opinion, what has been the greatest advancement in healthcare this year? How do you stay up to date on new trends and breakthroughs in the healthcare industry?", "answers": ["Display to the interviewer that you are interested in the new advances in healthcare. Be prepared to defend your answer.", "\"I follow a few medical journals such as the New England Journal of Medicine and The Lancet. I read a fascinating article a short time ago discussing the advancements in artificial retinae and other solutions for the blind. It's incredible to me how far these solutions have come.\"", "\"I believe that Patient-Centric R&D and Direct to Patient Clinical Research is the next big thing for the healthcare industry. I stay up to date on new trends through a variety of Google alerts, and some popular medical journals such as JAMA (Journal of American Medical Association).  I love to learn new trends and tips, so if you'd like to share with me your favorites, I would love to hear about those!\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "Tell me about your greatest work related accomplishment.", "answers": ["Talking about your most significant accomplishment will give the interviewer a definite idea of where you place your values. It will also show the interviewer more about your personality, how you like to be motivated, and how to coach you in the future. It is okay to brag a little bit when answering this question. Show that you are proud of yourself and your career accomplishments!", "\"The greatest accomplishment in my career was graduating University as an honors student while still working full time in a related field. I was top of my class, and working full time. This success showed me that I could dedicate myself to my career, and reach the goals that I set for myself. It felt great to accomplish so much and receive recognition for my dedication.\"", "\"I have many accomplishments that make me proud. Overall, I would say that my greatest work accomplishment is the positive reputation that I have in the healthcare industry. I take great pride in my work and am happy that this comes through in the results of my day to day work.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "What is your greatest weakness?", "answers": ["Pick a weakness that is not a core skill for this position. You can be candid in your answer; recognizing that you aren't great at something and acknowledging your need to improve.  Be sure to have an action plan in place for improving on this weakness. \n\nPerhaps you are watching TED talks to gain skills in a particular area, reading the latest-and-greatest book on the subject, or maybe you are taking a seminar at a nearby community center. We are all human with our weaknesses, so don't be afraid to share yours!", "\"I believe I could improve on some technical skills including Excel and PowerPoint. Currently I am at a beginner to intermediate level; however, I would be more comfortable at an advanced level. I have enrolled myself in an evening/weekend workshop for the next six weeks. We will see how stellar my skills are after that course!\"", "\"This is super cliche, but it's also true. I am not good at delegating to others. When I become submerged in a project, I don't like to give away any of the control. While this can be good, it can also definitely inhibit the outcome of the project and my growth as a team player and individual. \nI am currently working on this, as I know it is a deficit.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "What is your personal mission statement?", "answers": ["Not everyone has a mission statement or personal mantra just off the cuff. In business, especially when entering leadership, this is an important question to ponder. Do you have a quote that inspires you or a saying that you grew up with that resonates with you?", "\"My mantra is that 'people who shine from within do not need the spotlight.' I feel that it is incredibly important to be a humble leader and I take this mission statement very seriously. I want my team to be in the spotlight rather than being the kind of leader that takes credit for good work.\"", "\"My mission is to give my best 100% of the time. It's important to me that I have a great reputation in this industry through hard work and a positive attitude.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "When are your leadership skills the most effective?", "answers": ["When you have a great relationship with the individuals you are leading, your leadership skills will be the most effective. Show the interviewer that you recognize a great relationship starts with clear communication, trust, and honesty. Tell the interviewer that you spend time genuinely getting to know your team. \n\nFor instance, perhaps you like to understand what activities they have going on both inside and outside of work, their kids' names, or if they have any pets. Building a relationship with your team will ensure that you can frequently and genuinely ask them how they are doing.  The more comfortable they are, the better chance they will come to you for help in the workplace when they need it.", "\"My leadership skills are the most effective when my relationship with the employee isn't just a surface connection. I want to have true knowledge of their life and a good understanding of their career goals. When my employees know that I can help them to achieve their goals, they are more likely to be an engaged part of the team.\"", "\"I feel that my leadership skills are directly related to the happiness and engagement of my team. I spend a lot of time making sure that my team of staff are happy, confident, and invested in their jobs.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "Rate your communication skills from 1-10 with proper examples backing your given rating.", "answers": ["On a scale of 1-10, how skilled are you in communication? Why did you choose that particular rating for yourself?", "\"I rate my communication skills as a 9/10 as I will, on occasion, have times when I am not as clear as I would like to be. My supervisor and co-workers will attest to my clear and concise communication skills. Because I am an open leader, my team will let me know if I need to clarify anything.\"", "\"I will rate myself an 8.5 because I consider myself a strong communicator.  It is the foundation of all success in business.  I am always striving to be a better communicator, so I leave the rest of the scale as an aspirational measure.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "If you were not able to be in the healthcare profession, what other careers do you see yourself doing?", "answers": ["Show the interviewer that you know your strengths and talk about a profession that seems exciting and interesting to you. It's great to talk about a dream job but be sure to solidify your interest in the role and career path for which you are interviewing.", "\"I cannot imagine being unable to work in this profession because I enjoy it so much! If I had to draw on my other skills and passions, I would choose to work for a non-profit organization such as the local animal shelter. I am a big animal lover so that would be a lot of fun.\"", "\"I am a very creative person who has always had a penchant for the arts. I realize that it's completely different than my career path but if I knew, early on, that I could have made a career as an artist - I would have explored that option further. Of course, I am delighted with the choices I made and never have any regrets.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "Do you think honesty is always the best policy?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you genuinely feel that honesty is the best policy. Many will argue that honesty is not always the best policy. What is your take? Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on morality in the workplace.", "\"Sometimes full disclosure can damage someone's self-esteem, and reality isn't always best expressed in full and can be self-indulgent based on the person's intention. In those instances, honesty isn't always the best policy.\"", "\"Honesty is always the best policy. Often, it is just a matter of how you communicate and deliver your message so managing this with each situation is critical to building honest and trustworthy relationships.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "How do you determine priorities when you have multiple projects due?", "answers": ["When you feel torn between multiple projects or tasks, how do you decide which one needs your attention the most? Assure the interviewer that you can be diligent when it comes to assessing your priorities.", "\"I will determine which project requires my attention by the number of hours we are behind and then the project size. I am comfortable delegating tasks when needed, but I am also aware that these times will require an additional commitment of hours from me. Never have I under delivered on a deadline.\"", "\"Assuming that the projects have different stakeholders, I interview each to determine the value of increased productivity, morale or revenue, decreased costs, and the overall impact.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "How would your co-workers describe your attention to detail?", "answers": ["It is always best to support your reply with a real-life example. Talk to the interviewer about your level of attentiveness when it comes to details on the job.", "\"My co-workers would describe my attention to detail as very strong. I can very easily point out spelling discrepancies in communication and will notice the small things. I think big-picture as well but have always had a knack for details.\"", "\"My attention to detail is a point that I have been working on a lot this past year. I am meticulous but, in the past, have pushed my documentation back a little bit. It's something I am conscious of and continually working on.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "What makes you a great problem solver?", "answers": ["Employers want to know that you have a methodical approach to problem-solving. Consider the skills and qualities that help you successfully face problems. Perhaps you have a keen eye for detail. Maybe you can see opportunity when others can only focus on the issue. Share your strengths as a problem solver, and your ability to come up with innovative solutions.", "\"I am a great problem solver because I do not allow stress to cloud my judgment and mute my creativity. I am a keen observer with a great memory which allows me to recall unique solutions or ideas.\"", "\"I believe I am a great problem solver because I am sure to gather as many facts as possible, I look at the problem and its potential solutions from multiple angles, and I am not afraid to make a creative decision, that might seem off the beaten path.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "What do you think might be the greatest challenges faced in this job?  How will you overcome these challenges?", "answers": ["Even though it may seem like a dream job, the interviewer wants to know that you have realistic expectations of the role and that you will not be blindsided if problems or challenges present themselves. Keep your answer simple. It is okay to ask for clarification on the position if you do not fully understand what challenges are in store for you.", "\"I think the greatest challenges in this role will be to learn the proper operation of the equipment. Another challenge will be the physical aspect of the position as I will be required to stand and walk around most of the day. I will be sure to pay keen attention to training and ask questions along the way. In regards to the physical component - I will get used to the additional activity after just a couple of days, I'm sure.\"", "\"I think the added responsibility of running one of the highest volume departments in the hospital will be an adjustment, but it's a welcome challenge. I am looking forward to tackling it head on and growing through the challenges, because I know on the other side of those challenges, of that responsibility, are the biggest opportunities.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare", "question": "How do you manage your time, even on the busiest days?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know more about the types of tools you use to stay on task and meet deadlines. Discuss how you prioritize when everything demands your attention at once. Think about the ways you manage your projects and daily tasks.", "\"I manage my time by exercising the idea of 'time-blocking.' This method means that I won't incessantly check my email; instead, I will allow myself to return emails in 30-minute time blocks, four times per day. Setting calendar alerts and personal deadlines for myself has also helped a lot.\"", "\"Very carefully! I prioritize deadlines and work that needs to be done then work backward from there. When necessary, I utilize my resources and team to pitch in and contribute.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "Tell me about the most rewarding experience you have had, working in a team environment. What made it so rewarding?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to hear that you feel accomplished through teamwork. Talk about a time when you felt fulfilled through a team setting or project collaboration. \n\nAn example may be a time when you worked on a  team project in University, a recent work collaboration, or possibly an extracurricular experience such as coaching a little league team.  \n\nDiscuss the positive results of the teamwork and how you attained a positive outcome as a group.", "\"The most rewarding teamwork experience that I have had was in my last year of university. We were assigned a project in teams of 4 which accounted for quite a large part of our grade. I believe everyone pulled more than their weight because so much was at stake. Teamwork is very rewarding when everyone has something to win, or lose.\"", "\"I almost always find working in a team environment to be very rewarding; however, one of the most notable experiences came from my most recent position. We had a team of sales, marketers, and design professionals who collaborated to create a new brand strategy for the company. I learned a lot and had a great time in the process.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "The success of our brand relies heavily on our industry reputation and level of trustworthiness. How do you plan to build trust with Company ABC clients?", "answers": ["Building trust with clients is vital in the healthcare equipment and supply industry. Assure the interviewer that you are capable of creating a strong rapport with your clients by explaining how you develop and maintain these relationships. Give a relevant example, if possible.", "\"I see that Company ABC has a solid reputation in the industry which is incredibly valuable. In my current position, I spend a lot of time working with client questions and concerns. I establish trust with my clients by listening intently, delivering accurate answers the first time, and being diligent with my follow up. If hired, I would do the same for Company ABC.\"", "Here are some ways that you can build trust with your customers:  \n\n- Do not always try to sell them something \n- Offer product and service of value to them \n- Only offer to sell them what they need\n- Never inflate the benefits of a product or service \n- Do not slander the competition to make yourself look better\n- Do not make empty promises \n-  Take ownership and never blame the company for mistakes"]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "One of the ways that we provide great customer service is by offering 24/7 on-site equipment maintenance and repair. How will you contribute to our customer service standards?", "answers": ["Excellent customer service is vital in any industry; however, when working with healthcare equipment, one must be extra diligent because your customers, and their patients, rely heavily on you. Talk to the interviewer about your customer service philosophy.", "\"I think it's great that you offer this service 24/7. Being reliable and on-call is the perfect way to make your customers feel secure and trust you. To me, customer service is the most important factor in the success of any business. Your customer must always come first and my day is never done until I know everyone is taken care of.\"", "Here are some other ways you can deliver excellent customer service: \n\n- Displaying patience with your customers\n- Staying calm and confident in all situations\n- Being attentive to your customers' needs\n- Ability to react effectively to unexpected situations\n- Possessing strong product knowledge \n- Delivering your deadlines on time\n- Being a clear and positive communicator"]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "When have you used an inventive method to stretch company resources beyond the normal level?", "answers": ["If you have an expense account or resource allowance, it is very respectful to the company to be as thoughtful with that allowance as possible. Talk to the interviewer about a time when you have been able to stretch company resources.", "\"I have recently implemented a schedule that allows for ride-sharing rewards which have cut down on our company's fuel expense by $9000 per month. I am quite proud of this initiative because it is not only financially responsible but also environmentally friendly.\"", "\"I recycle a lot of company materials to make the most of our resources. I also do this with people regarding cross training and sharing understanding across departments.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "What career path interests you the most in this company?", "answers": ["This question is where it is essential to have completed some research on the interviewing company. Be sure to envision where you can see yourself fitting, and growing, with the organization before your interview. Do some research on what a career path could look like with this particular company.", "\"What interests me most about your company is that there are so many options when it comes to career growth. Ideally, I would like to earn my way into a Territory Sales role, then a Regional Manager position. Eventually, a Director of Sales or Marketing position would be ideal. Of course, I understand that this will take many years of dedication and hard work.\"", "\"I am interested in quality control.  I am very analytical and love to solve problems.  I understand that I have to learn the products before I can measure their quality.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "In the healthcare equipment and supply industry, strong attention to detail is incredibly important. On a scale of 1-10, how would you rate your attentiveness?", "answers": ["When the health and wellness of people are at stake, it is vital that all of the details are tended to. Assure the interviewer that you place value on the details. Give an example of a time when your manager or supervisor complimented your attention to detail.", "\"I would rate my attention to detail as an 8 out of 10. There is always room for improvement; however, my current supervisor often comments on how thorough my documentation is. I understand the importance of paying strong attention to detail.\"", "\"My attention to detail is a point that I have been working on a lot this past year. I am meticulous but, in the past, have pushed my documentation back a little bit. It's something I am conscious of and continually working on. I would currently rate myself as a 7.5 out of 10 and am aiming to be a 10/10!\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "When have you taken an existing process and used your own creativity to make it better?", "answers": ["Are you given the creative freedom to improve existing processes? Talk to the interviewer about your ability to take an existing process and grow it creatively.", "\"Last month my supervisor asked me to take our existing sales training package and improve it. My goal was to make the system more engaging for recruits. Once we implemented my ideas, we increased our new trainee retention rate by 16%. I was quite proud of what my creativity could do!\"", "\"There are so many great business practices out there that there is not always a need to reinvent the wheel.  I took a \"touch base\" practice we used to get a pulse of the team and customized it for a field-based corporate sales group to build better relationships with them.  It has been effective and fun!\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "At Company ABC we use a variety of robust internal software programs. What type of programs and software are you well versed in? Do you consider yourself tech savvy?", "answers": ["You may not need to know the exact programs used by Company ABC but you should be able to outline to the interviewer the programs that you are accustomed to using and how those skills are transferable. Be sure to mention any general programs that you are well versed in such as Excel or PowerPoint.", "\"I pick up on new programs very quickly and quite enjoy the challenge of learning new technology. For instance; I attended courses in Excel last year to improve my abilities in pivot tables and other advanced skills. For industry related experience, I am an intermediate user in Program ABC and XYZ. I believe many components of these programs are similar to your proprietary software.\"", "\"Could you share with me the programs and software used most regularly by Company ABC? I have experience in A, B, and C also I have exposure to a variety of software that may be related to the software used here.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "Tell me about a project you completed recently that was ahead of schedule.", "answers": ["Is it essential for you to meet and exceed work-related deadlines? Assure the interviewer that you can remain focused on a project and accomplish your goals ahead of schedule.", "\"In my current position I am expected to cold call 100 customers per week. Most of our associates will break this down into 20 per day, five days per week. What has attributed greatly to my success in this role is that I call 50 customers each day for the first two days and then have time to make additional calls throughout the week. This method generally equals a 25% surplus of cold calls to my portfolio. I am always ahead of target by going over and above that cold calling schedule.\"", "\"After recently hiring an entirely new team of people to roll out a capital equipment project, I realized they needed to learn to work together. I created cross-functional work group sessions to bring this team closer so they could work at an accelerated pace. We delivered the project seven days ahead of the original schedule. I truly believe this was because of great teamwork.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "At Company ABC we prefer to hire those with formal healthcare and medical training. Do you have related post-secondary education?", "answers": ["Take a few minutes to walk the interviewer through your medical training and post-secondary education. Chances are, you have this experience listed on your resume; however, the interviewer is looking for you to expand. Discuss your best course or your most challenging one. You can talk about any awards or recognition achieved while attending your post-secondary training and education. Be sure to tie in why your education will help you in this role. \n\nIf you have related training: \"I am a Registered Nurse (RN) with a Bachelor of Nursing from Tennessee Technological University. While attending this program, I found that I have an incredibly strong interest in Human Physiology. This interest has carried into my career and is one of the reasons why I am so excited about what you do at Company ABC.\"", "\"I am a Registered Nurse (RN) with a Bachelor of Nursing from Tennessee Technological University. While attending this program, I found that I have an incredibly strong interest in Human Physiology. This interest has carried into my career and is one of the reasons why I am so excited about what you do at Company ABC.\"", "If you do not have related training: \"I have performed a great deal of research on Company ABC and your products. I have approximately eight years of related work experience. Although I do not have formal medical or healthcare training, I am confident in my ability to perform this job function.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "At Company ABC we do not have a lot of local competitors; however, the ones we do have are strong competitors. In your opinion, what makes us stand out in the marketplace?", "answers": ["Researching the company is a crucial step to take before your job interview. Take note of what Company ABC focus' on most. Check online reviews to see what the customers are saying. Be sure to research their competitors so that you know what those particular companies are doing well. Where is Company ABC performing better when measured against their competitors? Keep you answer positive and stick to the facts.", "\"I have conducted some research on Company ABC, your industry, as well as your competitors. One point that stood out to me was the fact that you manufacture your products rather than importing lower quality versions. Your customers seem very pleased with the quality of your products, and I read some positive online reviews!\"", "\"I believe that what makes Company ABC stand out in the marketplace is the fact that all forms of advertising used are clear, concise, and fit with your brand. Clean branding is a major key to creating trust with consumers; thus, resulting in a successful business!\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "At Company ABC we have a wide range of clients all over the state. Are you comfortable managing a large territory that requires 50% overnight travel?", "answers": ["Many positions within the healthcare equipment and supply field will require a great deal of travel. Talk to the interviewer about your ability to be away on overnight travel. If you have restrictions on your schedule, this is the time to address that.\n\nIf you can accommodate travel: \"Currently, I travel about 40% of the time. I am comfortable with this requirement and happy to do so.\"", "\"Currently, I travel about 40% of the time. I am comfortable with this requirement and happy to do so.\"", "If you cannot accommodate travel: \"I can manage a large territory and travel within business hours. Overnight travel can be a bit tricky for me as I am a single parent; however, I can accommodate overnight travel about one week per month with some notice.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "At Company ABC our technology and products are intricately designed. Do you have a natural ability to understand, and explain, highly technological products?", "answers": ["It is crucial that you research Company ABC and their products, in detail, before your interview. Are you able to clearly understand the equipment and how it works? Show the interviewer that you already possess insight on their product offerings.", "\"I consider myself highly technical, and I can certainly take the time to learn your products inside and out before joining Company ABC. I have already taught myself a few things through researching your website. For example - you create product ABC which is an answer to medical issue XYZ. I am excited to learn more!\"", "\"When I have a clear understanding of the product or process, I have a strong ability to explain things in simple terms. I am technically savvy and also have an analytical mind. I am confident in my ability to quickly learn your products so that I can effectively relay my knowledge to your customers.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "There are strict federal regulations and guidelines in our industry that must always be followed. Are you familiar with these, and do you have a history of compliance?", "answers": ["If you have experience in the healthcare equipment and service industry, you are likely familiar with the fact that there are strict guidelines and regulations surrounding best practices. Assure the interviewer that you are familiar with this fact and that you understand the importance of compliance.", "\"Earlier in my career, I worked for the U.S Department of Health & Human Services. I became very familiar with the role that the federal government plays in the regulations and guidelines associated with the healthcare industry. I am eager to learn more about the regulations and guidelines which specifically affect Company ABC.\"", "\"Although I am new to the healthcare supply and equipment industry, and do not have a thorough understanding of your regulations, I can tell you that I have a strong history of compliance. My background is in health and safety and, with that experience, comes the ingrained knowledge that will transfer well to this role with Company ABC\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "Company ABC has a very strong reputation in this industry which means that we receive a high volume of applications for our open roles. What makes you a competitive candidate for this role?", "answers": ["If there was ever a time to \"sell\" yourself, it is now! Talk to the interviewer about your results and performance versus only talking about your feelings on why you are the best candidate for the position.", "\"I am a competitive candidate because I have a consistent history of exceeding my targets and goals for the past three years. I have been promoted two times in the last year which is nearly unheard of in my current company. In addition to these successes, I have excellent cold calling skills which I will put to work immediately after being hired with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "When have you had to change a major component of your project due to new information being presented?", "answers": ["Being able to swivel the focus of your project is a necessary skill for your success in most careers. Talk to the interviewer about a time when a significant change occurred on a project. How did you handle the implementation of the new information?", "\"I had a large project last month that was nearly complete when the client called to say that the dimensions provided were incorrect. Because of this, our team had to re-do the entire proposal. It took us an additional four days of work but, in the end, the client was delighted with our work, and it resulted in new opportunities with them.\"", "\"Last year I was nearing the end of a client project when we had an unexpected parts recall. It set us back a few weeks and was quite discouraging. I reminded my team that we could not control changes like this, and we agreed to do our best work with what we had.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "Tell me about a contribution you made to the last team you worked on.", "answers": ["It is essential to show the interviewer that you are a team player. Talk about a time that you were recently expected to achieve a goal in a team setting. How did you go above and beyond to ensure that your contribution was felt?", "\"Last month our company asked upper management to complete a full inventory audit. There were 4 of us in total and so we broke the audit requirements into shifts. These shifts had to take place when the warehouse was closed. In the end, there was one additional shift that nobody wanted to take. I volunteered myself to do that shift to show my dedication to my job and my co-workers. The gesture was appreciated, and the audit was completed on time.\"", "\"My biggest contribution to my last team came in the form of leadership. I am a natural leader and can foster strong communication with my team which directly impacted the overall results.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "Tell me about a time when you improved communication between yourself and a co-worker or client.", "answers": ["Possessing the skills to improve communication in the workplace is a precious asset. Talk to the interviewer about your ability to enhance communication in the workplace.", "\"In my current position I have one particular client who was an exceptionally brief communicator. If I asked two questions, he would answer just one. I learned that he would not acknowledge anything for which he did not have a direct answer. I began to ask him questions in a different way. For example, I would say 'Do you have an answer for me on question X?' and he would say yes or no. We would then go from there. This method was a valid form of communication for that particular client.\"", "\"We recently rolled out a large organizational change. I took a very transparent approach to communication throughout the process. I asked the team for their feedback and buy-in early in the process.  We discussed some options that could be expected. When the time came to roll out the change, there was minimal surprise with the new process. It was a success!\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "How would you describe your personality?", "answers": ["Personality and character are two very different things. The interviewer is looking for more information on your traits vs. your integrity. Your example could include buzzwords such as introverted, energetic, and confident.", "\"I would describe my personality as approachable, light-hearted, and positive. I believe that, if asked, my colleagues and supervisor would say the same about me.\"", "Here are some additional descriptive words related to personality: \n\n- Adaptable\n- Considerate\n- Diligent \n- Exuberant\n- Frank\n- Generous\n- Inventive \n- Persistent \n- Resourceful\n- Sincere"]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "Tell me about a time when you took on a new course to study in order to improve your own work performance.", "answers": ["Once you are in your career, it certainly doesn't mean that you need to stop learning. There are many job-related courses available. Talk to the interviewer about the last time you took advantage of these available courses.", "\"Our company offered the Sandler Sales program to anyone in the company who was interested. I took this workshop in 2014 and enjoyed it. My sales increased by 23% that year.\"", "\"I took a one-day seminar in Microsoft Excel.  I already knew the basics, but my boss like using macros and pivot tables, and I was spending a lot of time reading the support section to figure out how to use them.  The course was very informative.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "How do you handle stress?", "answers": ["Are you someone who can handle stress on the job? How do you manage the stressful times? Talk to the interviewer about your ability to control pressure in the workplace.", "\"I handle stress very well, and when you call my references, they will attest to this fact. When I am under pressure on the job, I focus on the task at hand and make sure not to get distracted. Staying on deadline is very helpful, and I will delegate when necessary to alleviate some stress.\"", "\"Stress is part of any demanding job, and I embrace it to the fullest.  I take good care of myself and prioritize my workload to maintain a healthy balance in my stress levels.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "List the top 3 skills that you have acquired in your last role.", "answers": ["You have likely gained many valuable skills in your career. Share with the interviewer which skills you value the most. Be sure to include capabilities that will potentially benefit this potential new employer.", "\"In the past few years I was able to upgrade my education while still working full time. The biggest skill that I gained was my ability to multi-task as I worked the dual role of employee and student. I also have strong skills in a variety of Microsoft programs such as PowerPoint and Excel.\"", "Here are some additional skills that may be transferable: \n\n- Proven experience in motivating others\n- Ability to effectively prioritize\n- Time management \n- Leadership experience\n- Research skills \n- Experience delegating tasks"]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "Do you think honesty is always the best policy?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you genuinely feel that honesty is the best policy. Many will argue that honesty is not always the best policy. What is your take? Talk to the interviewer about your thoughts on honesty in the workplace.", "\"Sometimes full disclosure can damage someone's self-esteem, and reality isn't always best expressed in full and can be self-indulgent based on the person's intention. In those instances, honesty isn't always the best policy.\"", "\"Honesty is always the best policy.  Often, it is just a matter of how you communicate and deliver your message so managing this with each situation is critical to building honest and trustworthy relationships.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "How can we motivate you on the job?", "answers": ["Every employer should know how each staff member is best motivated. Talk to the interviewer about the variety of ways in which you are best motivated on the job.", "\"I am best motivated through words of praise and recognition for a job well done. I do like to know that my efforts are noticed. In my current position, we have a leaderboard, and I do like that concept because it creates a healthy bit of personal competition for me as well.\"", "\"I am motivated by knowing something about the end customer and being able to relate to them as a person. A personal touch is always helpful for me.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "If you were hired for this position, what are the first changes you would implement?", "answers": ["Most organizations want to avoid on-boarding someone who will make immediate and significant changes. Significant changes are hard on the staff and usually, result in knee-jerk reactions such as mass turnover. It's always best to explain to the interviewer that you plan first to observe to gain a better understanding of the organization's culture and team dynamics. Focus your discussion on building a strong rapport with the staff. \n\nIf you are applying for a promotion within your current organization, you may already know what changes you would like to make upon receiving this position. Share with the interviewer what you have observed while in your current job, the changes you would make, and why you would make those changes.  \n\nDiscuss the fact that you will address any urgent and glaring issues immediately; however, assure the interviewer that you will implement significant changes only after you have a thorough understanding of the organizational dynamics.", "\"If chosen for this position, I do not believe that major and immediate change would be the answer. My first action would be to have a one-on-one meeting with everyone on the leadership team. I would want to learn what the teams greatest challenges are, and how I could alleviate those difficulties. From there, the trickle effect will be strong, and we will see an increase in sales and employee engagement. Only after that would I consider a stronger approach to change.\"", "\"I like to train in current processes before making changes. I know that my first question would be to ask what is not working.  If I can see a quick fix to try, I would try it, but I would likely still need to learn more about the business before making any changes.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "Have you ever had to fire an employee? What were the reasons for their termination?", "answers": ["Terminating an employee is never a task that people like to do. Talk to the interviewer about how you go about employee terminations. How does that conversation usually look?", "\"I have had to terminate employees in the past, yes. These terminations generally stemmed from missed targets or insubordination. I find it challenging to terminate employees because you do care about them and their well being. I have to remind myself that I did absolutely everything that I could to ensure their success but, I cannot carry the full weight.\"", "\"Unfortunately, this is a part of wearing your management hat. I recently had to separate employment with someone who was under-performing.  We coached the individuals, offered additional learning experiences and worked with them on a performance improvement plan.  It was the right person in the wrong role, and we had to decide to move forward.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "What is something you would be happy doing everyday for the rest of your career?", "answers": ["If you could choose any task to do every day for the rest of your career, what would it be and why? Talk to the interviewer about what would make you the happiest and be sure to tie it into something related to their organization.", "\"I enjoy helping people, and one of the reasons why I am so interested in your organization is because of the charitable foundations that you support. Over time, I would love to transition into a role where I could lead the team in that particular department.\"", "\"Crunching data and analyzing statistics is a big passion of mine. If I could do that for the rest of my career, I would be happy!\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "How do you deal with conflict on your team?", "answers": ["The interviewer is looking to hear about your ability to communicate with your team and professionally handle issues when they arise. \n\nThink of an example where you worked closely with your team to resolve a conflict. You could also offer a scenario where you mediated an issue between two coworkers. Show that you can keep your head on your shoulders when dealing with conflict.", "\"I have strong conflict management skills and in my current position, have had to exercise those skills from time to time. We are in a high-stress, highly commissioned work environment which can cause a lot of unnecessary conflict among the team. When a conflict arises, I like to deal with it swiftly, openly, and with poise. Transparency and openness are how I lead my team, so I will call a group meeting where we express concerns and get it all out on the table.\"", "\"Conflict is a normal part of being in business. It is most easily remedied by clear, open, and honest communication among team members.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Equipment+and+Supplies", "question": "When given an important assignment, how do you approach handling it?", "answers": ["Are you the individual who will approach an assignment head-on, or do you need to research and plan first? Do you jump in and get it all done immediately or do you balance it with other assignments? Talk to the interviewer about how you approach essential assignments at work.", "\"When my supervisor gives me an important assignment or task I am sure to assess the depth of the project then take a look at my schedule to see how I can appropriately balance it with my other work. I do not procrastinate because then it's easy to forget to fit them in.\"", "\"I tend to jump right into an assignment and plan my steps once things are underway. It's the best way that I can create a strategy without wasting any time at the start.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "It is often said that a career in healthcare is a 'thankless job.' How can we keep you motivated and engaged, even on the days when you feel your work goes unnoticed?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know how they could continue to motivate you - even on the hardest of days. Do you need to have verbal recognition? Are you motivated solely by the success of your team? Talk to the interviewer about how you have stayed motivated in the past.", "\"My chosen career was helping people at exactly the point they were least capable of censoring themselves or giving back. So, I stopped needing thanks from my patients. It's not like I don't need positive reinforcement. Everyone does. But I made a point to find it in other places instead of expecting it from my patients. Nowadays, I make an effort to expressly thank the people I work with when they do a good job.  I focus on being grateful to be allowed to see private, raw, emotional parts of people's lives.\"", "\"I am an easily motivated individual, and it does not take much to keep me engaged. I am fully aware that healthcare-related positions can seem thankless. Honestly, the best thanks that I can get is a pat on the back now and then. The majority of my motivation comes from simply helping people.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "Patient care requires a strong amount of compassion. Do you consider yourself a compassionate person?", "answers": ["To succeed in the healthcare services industry, you should have a substantial level of compassion for your patients or customers. Talk to the interviewer about the compassionate qualities that you possess. How would you rate your level of empathy for others? \n\nSome ways to describe yourself could be: \n\n- Understanding\n- Warm-hearted\n- Empathetic\n- Responsive\n- Charitable \n- Tender-hearted", "\"I understand that compassion is one of the top qualities that I need to bring to the workplace, being in the healthcare services profession. I consider myself a very compassionate individual. I am warm-hearted, responsive to my patients' needs,  and always empathetic.\"", "\"Yes, I most certainly consider myself a compassionate person. I take the opportunity to understand and help others whenever possible. While attending university, I spent a lot of time volunteering at a local hospice - not only for the added experience but also to give back to others. I look forward to continuing this level of compassionate care with your organization.\"", "\"I consider myself a very compassionate person. I am warm-hearted, responsive to my patients' needs, always empathetic and charitable.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "If you could expand your knowledge and expertise in any healthcare service area, which would you choose?", "answers": ["There are many facets of health care. If you could choose any area of healthcare to specialize in, which would you choose? Be sure to tie your answer into some aspects of what Company ABC does.", "\"If I could choose any area of healthcare services to be a subject matter expert in, I would choose geriatric care. I do feel that this particular focus is not as popular as some, and become an expert in it would allow me to snowball in my career.\"", "\"I have a variety of interests within the healthcare service, so that is a tough question for me! I suppose if I had to narrow it to just one area of expertise, I would say palliative care and the necessary family care that comes with it.\"", "\"I would say the innovation of products. By designing high tech instruments and machines, this will benefit the patients and employees will also be more productive. I see opportunities where others don't. Never settle for the status quo.\"", "Good answer! This shows your knowledge of the industry, your desire to learn, and your drive to improve productivity and patient experience."]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "How would you describe your personality?", "answers": ["Personality and character are two very different things. The interviewer is looking for more information on your traits vs. your integrity. Your example could include buzzwords such as introverted, energetic, and confident.", "\"I would describe my personality as approachable, light-hearted, and positive. I believe that, if asked, my colleagues and supervisor would say the same about me.\"", "\"I'm genuinely easy-going, probably from all the international travel I experienced in my 20's. I like to do the right thing, and sometimes I get stressed trying to reach that goal, but I think it's a worthwhile endeavor. I can be funny, but my sense of humor is pretty dry, so people don't always know that about me when they first meet me.\"", "\"I would describe my personality as approachable, light-hearted, and positive. I am honest and always do the right thing.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "Healthcare service companies require strong organizational skills and attention to detail. How do you ensure that your work is properly organized, and highly accurate?", "answers": ["The success of the healthcare industry thrives on the accuracy of information and organization. Talk to the interviewer about the ways that you ensure accuracy and organization in your day to day activities. Perhaps you use a particular app or software. Maybe you are a pen and paper person. Whatever your method, be sure to highlight that you are successful in organizing your day.", "\"I am a highly detailed person, and I thrive on having a high level of organization in my day. This organization includes my scheduling, paperwork, and more. If I am offered a position with Company ABC you will never find me to be disorganized! I utilize my Outlook calendar and set alerts for myself for deadlines and important activities. My documentation is strong, as well.\"", "\"I'm a bit of an organizational nerd. I carry around a notebook and write down important facts if I think there is a chance I will forget them. But this is usually just for transitions. Every clinic I've ever worked in has its way of communicating and recording facts, so I put time and attention into using the system the people around me are using. That way, its easier to transition care, and the patient has all their info in the same place. My notebook saves me when I'm swamped, but I try to be efficient and put info directly into the (group record/EMR/chart) when I can.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "In the healthcare services industry there are many emotions in a day. Have your emotions ever been in the way of your productivity?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know if you consider yourself to be an emotionally driven person. Talk to the interviewer about your emotions and if they have ever affected your productivity at work. \n\nKeep in mind - almost everyone is an emotional creature to some degree, but there are other ways that you can describe yourself that have a more positive connotation. If you are passionate, you could choose to refer to yourself as: \n\n- Expressive \n- Communicative\n- Open\n- Unreserved", "\"Everyone is emotional to a certain degree, and I would consider myself kind-hearted and open. A career in healthcare can be emotional at times; however, I choose to focus on the positives. For instance, - if we are close to losing a patient, I will focus on positive memories rather than the illness. This mindset has consistently allowed me to continue with a productive shift, no matter the emotions that come my way. \"", "\"This is a great question. I think the right answer is, 'of course, but not for long'!  We've all had those severe cases. A child dies, or you have to give someone a cancer diagnosis. It's professional to take a few minutes after an encounter like that and let those emotions come and go. I cope with these emotions by telling myself that it's not my story, its the patient's story.  I think it's okay to be moved by someone else's experience, but I don't need to make it mine.\"", "\"Everyone is emotional to a certain degree, and I would consider myself kind-hearted and open. A career in healthcare can be emotional at times, but I choose to focus on the positives. For instance, if we are close to losing a patient, I will focus on the positive memories rather than the illness. This mindset allows me to continue with a productive shift no matter what emotions come my way.\"", "I like that you say what you would do to avoid letting emotions get in the way, but also remember to answer the question directly.", "\"No, my emotions have not gotten in the way of my productivity. Everyone is emotional to a certain degree, and I would consider myself kind- hearted and open. A career in health care can be emotional at times, but I choose to focus on the positives. For instance, if we are close to losing a patient, I would focus on the positive memories rather than the illness. This mindset allows me to continue with a productive shift no matter the emotion that I may experience.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "When have you shown a willingness to learn a new method or new approach to solving a problem?", "answers": ["Being flexible and able to handle change is a skill that all employers desire to see. Discuss with the interviewer your ability to approach a problem using new methods. Give a recent example, but make sure to spend more time highlighting the resolution rather than the problem.", "\"When our facility came under new management last year, many new methods and policies came into place. I was able to learn some exciting new approaches to our challenges in patient care and customer management. I quite enjoyed the process.\"", "\"They say people in healthcare are 'lifelong learners.' I'm now old enough to realize that its difficult to be always adapting. I think my 45-year-old aunt telling me how to use my iPhone helped me appreciate that it's all about humility. It's not about who is teaching you, but if you are willing to learn. In the medical context, I just took an updated CPR course, and it went from the 2:15 compressions to continuous compressions, and I had to adapt to overcome my former way of thinking.\"", "\"I just took my BLS and it went from 2:30 compressions to continuous compressions. I had to adapt to avoid my past way of thinking.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to hire individuals who display a keen interest in the healthcare arena. Would you consider yourself dedicated to a career in healthcare services?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer of your dedication to a lucrative career in the healthcare services industry. The hiring manager would like to know that this position fits into your long-term plan and that, if hired, you would stay with Company ABC as long as possible.", "\"I dedicated my entire career to the healthcare services field. I find it incredibly rewarding and interesting because I get to help others, and every day brings new challenges! One of the reasons I applied for this role with Company ABC is because I can see a long-term fit here. I plan to work in the healthcare segment for my entire career.\"", "\"I know this career can take a toll on personal life, and I understand that while it can be more-or-less sustainable, it's more than just a job for me.  So far, I have dedicated my entire adult life to this career. I have shadowed numerous professionals and have worked in multiple clinics. I know this is the right career for me.\"", "\"I find it incredibly rewarding and interesting because I get to help others. One of the reasons I applied for this role is because I can see a long-term fit here. I plan to work in healthcare for my entire career.\"", "Good answer! If I were the interviewer I would probably follow up asking what made you decide to get into health care in the first place."]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "At Company ABC we take pride in our great relationships with clients, vendors, coworkers, and patients. Do you consider yourself to be a strong relationship builder?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you would treat everyone at Company ABC with great respect and a positive attitude. Discuss the ways that you would build strong and healthy relationships if hired.\n\nSome ways to build strong relationships in the workplace: \n\n- Have strong follow-up habits\n- Offer sincere conversation \n- Get to know people on a personal level\n- Be trustworthy\n- Avoid gossip\n- Offer mutual respect\n- Be mindful of your actions\n- Compliment others\n- Be positive \n- Be a strong listener", "\"I have earned compliments on my relationship-building skills. I like to get to know people and ask them questions about themselves. Most people love to talk about themselves, and I find it's a great and simple way to start building rapport with others. I consider myself to be a strong relationship builder and take pride in my 'people skills'. Rest assured, I would be a great ambassador of positive relationships for Company ABC.\"", "\"I am happy to hear that Company ABC values long-term relationships.  This fact is a bonus for me, and it's one of the reasons I chose to work in the medical field. I like working in an industry where genuine care is valued.  Healthcare is not a place for gimmicks because health is precious and irreplaceable. I've had success in university and my internships by focusing on building a reputation for consistency and followup.  What you describe is a good fit for me, and I'd like to represent a company that wants to create long-term sustainable partnerships.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "Why do you think you will be successful in this role with Company ABC?", "answers": ["Rather than share how you have gone beyond expectations in the past, focus on how your qualities will help you to exceed company expectations. Discuss the reasons why you will be great at this job. Talk about your qualifications and skills that will help you to do this job well. If you can, match your strengths to the requirements outlined in the job description.", "\"I know I will be successful in this role because I have been working in this industry for five years with great training and mentorship. I have a solid understanding of X, Y, and Z (skills listed in the job description). Also, I have all of my updated certifications as outlined in your job description. I am well-prepared for this next step in my career.\"", "\"I believe my success with Company ABC will come from having all of the hard skills that you are looking for, whether learned in school or gained through my internship experience. I have a great deal of current knowledge in the healthcare services industry and stay informed of best practices.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "In your opinion, what makes you a great problem solver?", "answers": ["Employers want to know that you have a systematic approach to problem-solving. Consider the skills and qualities that help you successfully face problems. Perhaps you have a keen eye for detail. Maybe you can see opportunity when others can only focus on the issue. Share your strengths as a problem solver, and your ability to come up with innovative solutions.", "\"I am a great problem solver because I do not allow stress to cloud my judgment and mute my sound decision making. I am a keen observer with a great memory, which allows me to recall unique solutions or ideas.\"", "\"I believe I am a great problem solver because I am sure to gather as many facts as possible. I look at the problem and its potential solutions from multiple angles, and I am not afraid to make a decision that might seem off the beaten path.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "Company ABC has a diverse workforce. When have you worked among a diverse group of people?", "answers": ["Are you accustomed to working with a very large or diverse team of individuals? Assure the interviewer that you can handle an environment that offers diversity. Even better, give an example of being able to embrace diversity in the workplace.", "\"I have worked with diverse groups of people most of my career, including my time in University. I am most comfortable and happy in this type of environment because it offers me unique learning opportunities.\"", "\"I am so glad you pointed out your need for diversity at Company ABC. I greatly value diversity. I grew up in a fairly homogeneous town in Montana. When I hit my 20's, it was so important to me to learn about other cultures. I worked with community volunteer organizations in Peru, inner-city Chicago, and Russia.\"", "\"I am comfortable and I can handle an environment that offers diversity. I am interested to learn about other cultures.\"", "While I like your content here, be sure to address the specific question and describe a time when you've worked with a diverse group of people.", "\"I worked with a diverse group of people in my position at .... I am comfortable and I can handle an environment that offers diversity. I am also interested in learning about other cultures.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "Company ABC seeks to hire those with strong problem solving skills. When were you able to successfully resolve a problem in the workplace?", "answers": ["Problem-solving and dispute resolution are critical skills to possess. Display to the interviewer that you are capable of problem-solving within the workplace. Talk about a time when you were creative, proactive, and displayed the leadership qualities required to resolve a workplace issue.", "\"I was working in a clinic where the primary population was low income. We had a lot of concerns with patients not showing up for appointments when expected. The staff wanted to start double-booking patient time slots. Instead, I got permission to spend a day in a highly-rated clinic serving the same population. Instead of scheduling, they had these 'drop-in mornings' with a shared waiting room. I took these methods and incorporated them into our setting. We did that twice a week, and it completely solved our scheduling problem.\"", "\"We had many group projects in university, and I noticed a consistent problem with team members showing up late for meetings or messaging in sick at the very last moment. As the team leader, rather than getting upset, I proposed that when a team member disrespectfully dropped the ball, they would be asked to leave the group and find a  new group or commit to an independent project. I felt this encouraged accountability and showed teamwork as a privilege rather than a right. Team member commitments increased as did work ethic among the groups.\"", "\"In my practice, I had a problem with patients not showing up for their appointments. But by constantly following up and calling them to remind about their appointments, I solved our scheduling problem.\"", "Good answer! I recommend rewording slightly to make your response more action-oriented.", "\"In my practice I had a problem with patients not showing up to their appointments. We implemented a practice of calling them with appointment reminders, which solved our scheduling problem.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "If you could expand your knowledge and expertise in any area of healthcare services, which would you choose?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to dig deeper into your real areas of interest when it comes to healthcare services. They want to know that your passions align well with what Company ABC is offering. Talk to the interviewer about the areas of healthcare you would like to focus on most, and then tie that information in with what the position at Company ABC would be offering you.", "\"If I could expand my expertise in any healthcare service area, I would choose anything within primary care. This interest is one of the reasons I have applied to your company. I feel that your focus will be a great fit with my long-term career goals.\"", "\"I'm interested in research.  One of the things that attracted me to working with your company is your ongoing community-based research collaborations.  I'd be curious to hear if the (clinic/hospital/program) had any needs in this area.  Is this something junior staff can be involved in?\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "Tell me about your healthcare related education and training.", "answers": ["Walk the interviewer through your formal post-secondary education as well as any on the job training. Talk about your most positive take-away's from your post-secondary experience and be sure to tie in how that experience will help you succeed in this position.", "\"I have a nursing degree as well as additional on the job training within clinical research. I feel that my nursing education opened up many potential industry-related avenues for me. I graduated top of my class and completed a valuable internship with 'XYZ Health Services.' All of these experiences have helped prepare me for success in this role with Company ABC.\"", "\"I did my undergraduate in chemistry and medical school at St. George's University. I loved surgery, so my electives were in general surgery, trauma epidemiology, and orthopedics. I'm happy to be moving on to more responsibility as a resident. I have had some amazing mentors, and I found that I could perform with some different teaching styles.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "What is your patient care philosophy?", "answers": ["It's always a great idea to research the company before your interview. You want to get to know their care philosophy so that your answer can reflect what is important to them. What is the core of your care philosophy? Keep your answer concise yet sincere.", "\"Every day at work, I remind myself that everyone I come across has their struggles. Every person we care for has a story. I make sure to get to know my patients whenever possible. Everyone has the right to compassionate care.\"", "\"I have three philosophies when it comes to my work; One view for the clinic, one for me, and one for the patient. First, I work in a system, and I respect that. I follow the rules, I maintain my certifications, and I appreciate the policies and values of whatever site I work. Patient care is a privilege, and I respect the role I have in clinical care and the part other people have. Second, I want to be the best at what I do. Every day I learn something, and that's because I choose to get better. \nLast, I adapt to the individual. If I'm meeting the requirements of my position, and evolving within my profession, then I am free to adjust to my patient and be the provider they need. Some patients need a lot of attention; some want less, and some need boundaries. I have trained myself to adapt my communication style, so a patient gets what they need.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "In order to work for Company ABC, you must be able to pass a full criminal background check. Do you consent to a full background check?", "answers": ["Working in the healthcare services industry means that you are in contact with vulnerable people, children, pharmaceutical drugs, drug-related equipment, confidential information, and other areas of sensitivity. Assure the interviewer that you are able and willing to pass a complete background check. If you have a criminal record, you must disclose this.", "\"I have a clean criminal record and am happy to comply with any background check you require of me.\"", "\"No problem. I understand that it's part of the job.  But I want to be up-front, I have done a full background check before, and there is a possibility you will see a charge for possession of marijuana in the check. It was several years ago, and it's no longer an issue for me because I've made significant changes in my life to pursue this career.  But I don't want you to be surprised by the information. I'm happy to answer any questions you have.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "Have you ever been involved in ordering medical supplies, maintaining inventory, or other types of healthcare-related administrative duties?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know if you understand what it takes to keep on top of ordering medical supplies and inventory. Assure the interviewer that you are capable of foreseeing needs and making the appropriate action. Highlight your ability to be responsible when it comes to related administrative tasks.", "\"I have experience in ordering medical supplies and maintaining inventory. I fully understand that there is an art to being properly organized when it comes to the availability of supplies. For medical ordering and inventory, I have used a variety of software and programs such as ABC and XYZ.\"", "\"I performed a few admin duties during my internship. I helped maintain supplies in the general surgery ward for five weeks. I was great at working behind the scenes, with the result being efficiency for others.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "At Company ABC we seek to hire individuals who have ambitions of growing their career. Where do you see yourself in 3-5 years?", "answers": ["Every hiring manager would like to know that their investment in time and training will pay off. Assure the interviewer that you see this position as a long-term fit. How does this role with Company ABC fit into your longer-term plans?", "\"In 3-5 years I would like to see my career with Company ABC include a path towards a leadership role. I am very keen on paving a long-term career in the healthcare services realm and would love the opportunity to do that here.\"", "\"One of the attractive points of working for Company ABC is that you care about the growth of your employees. I'm motivated to learn and am looking for a long-term fit. In 3-5 years, I'd like to be grounded in the clinic, learn about this site, your patient base, and earn certifications that would help the unit advance. I want to get involved in some of the local volunteer organizations. I speak Spanish, and I have an interest in urban outreach, so it would be nice to do something formal in that context, health-education, or fundraising.\"", "\"One of the attractive points of working in this company is that you care about the growth of your employees. I'm motivated to learn and looking for a long term fit. In 3-5 years, I'd like to be grounded in the clinic, learn anything & everything about the field, immerse myself in it, and earn certifications that would help the unit advance. I'd also like to get involved in some of the local volunteer organizations such as disaster response in emergencies.\"", "Excellent answer! This answer shows your desire to learn and grow, and shows that you would be a dedicated employee. This is exactly what an interviewer likes to know!"]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "Do you prefer to work in a team based position or individually?", "answers": ["In which situation are you the happiest and most productive? Talk to the interviewer about your preference when it comes to teamwork or working individually. Be sure to avoid pigeonholing yourself into one particular scenario (IE: I only like to work by myself). You may work well without the need for much management or direction, or perhaps you are better driven in a collaborative and team led environment. Either way, be honest with the interviewer about your preferences without leaning negatively, either way.", "\"Whether I am doing an independent project, or working in a team environment, I always give my best. I enjoy the camaraderie of working in a team, but I can be successful working autonomously as well.\"", "\"I have found, in the past, that I work well in an individually driven environment; however, I can certainly be productive in a team-based setting as well.\"", "\"Whether I am doing an independent project or working in a team environment, I always give my best. I enjoy the camaraderie of working in a team, but I can be successful working autonomously as well.\"", "Good answer, just be sure to address the question on whether or not you have a preference."]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "Company ABC supports a healthy work/life balance for all employees. How do you balance life and work?", "answers": ["It is essential to keep a healthy work/life balance to prevent burnout. Talk to the interviewer about how you can maintain that appropriate balance for yourself.", "\"I find that with the right company, it's pretty simple to balance life and work. When I enjoy what I do, it doesn't feel like a chore. I am always sure that when at home, my family gets my attention first. I take time on the weekends to do things for myself and ensure that I regenerate before the work week begins.\"", "\"I make a strong effort to keep a healthy balance by spending my free time away from my cell phone and having more face-to-face time with my friends and family. I indulge in the things that make me happy, on my time off. By consistently rejuvenating in this way, I can give even more energy when I am at work.\"", "\"With the right company, it's pretty simple to balance life and work. When I enjoy what I do it doesn't feel like a chore. I am always sure that when at home, my family gets my attention first. I'd go out with friends too & indulge in the things that make me happy on my time off. By constantly rejuvenating in this way, I can give even more energy when I am at work.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "Tell me about yourself.", "answers": ["Take a few minutes to tell the interviewer a few things about yourself. You can begin with your recent education, family life, volunteer work, or talk about your travels. Bring up anything that is interesting and highlights your ability to be a responsible, reliable, and bright individual.", "\"A bit about me - I love to travel, read, and conduct research. I spent the past few months traveling the world with Doctors Without Borders. It was the best experience that I could have given myself as I was able to learn so much from seeing how the rest of the world lives. I returned to the US just last month and had been actively looking for new work for the past couple of weeks. I am eager to getting into the routine of a career again.\"", "\"I am an avid marathon runner and have traveled to 10 countries in the last eight years to compete in a variety of races. I am a competitive individual and enjoy keeping fit. New to my career in healthcare services, my biggest goal is to take as many related courses as possible. I am eager to get a great start on my career.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "What part of your healthcare career brings you the most stress?", "answers": ["Stress can often be a regular part of the day to day work experience. Talk to the interviewer about which areas of your career are the most stressful. Ensure that your answer does not include a factor that would make you appear unfit for the position. (Ie: a healthcare worker should not find facing illness to be the most stressful part of the job).", "\"When the schedule is running behind due to lack of hustle on mine or my team's part, I find it stressful. I like to be on time with my schedule to ensure that our patients and clients get the proper, timely help that they need.\"", "\"To be completely transparent, I probably bring myself the most stress because of my innate desire to be the best. I strive for perfection too often, which causes undue stress on myself.  I manage this by focusing my energy on productive activities that are good for my career.\"", "\"What brings me the most stress is when the schedule is running behind. I like to be on time with my schedule to ensure that our patients are assisted properly.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "If Company ABC hired you today, what would you accomplish first?", "answers": ["When you start a new position, it is essential to be clear on how you will make a positive impact after being hired. This question is a delicate one, and you need to show respect for the onboarding process, then give a moderately ambitious project that you could execute. This concept is often called your 'value proposition' in marketing. 'Hire me because I'll do X.'\n\nRemember, this is your campaign promise. If hired, it will likely be your first target to hit, and depending on the environment; it could make or break you. The best approach is to give a functional analysis of the employers' needs and your skills.\n\nTell the interviewer what your impact goal is, should you be the successful candidate. Be sure to refer to the immediate needs of the company, such as increasing budgets, or improving patient care, for instance.", "\"When we were speaking earlier, you mentioned that you were urgently seeking to improve the level of patient care and compassion at this facility. I want to offer my skills when it comes to building patient rapport and help to improve the satisfaction of everyone that uses the services of Company ABC. I plan to make a positive impact very quickly.\"", "\"If hired today, I would commit to diving into every resource provided to me, speeding up the learning curve typical of a new hire who is also new to their career. I will soak in every learning opportunity that comes my way so that I can be a self-sufficient member of your healthcare service team within the first 30 days.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "Think about a difficult boss, professor or coworker. What made him or her difficult? How did you successfully interact with this person?", "answers": ["Show the interviewer that you work well with most personalities even though you recognize there are some folks out there who are quite difficult to please. \n\nThink about that one person at work who is hard to please. Perhaps there is someone at work who tries to intimidate others. Talk to the interviewer about what made this person challenging and what their relationship was with you. Avoid speaking poorly of anyone, and be sure to end your response on a positive note.", "\"I once worked at a small medical facility where the primary physician was very demanding. When he would walk into the facility, employees would quietly announce that he was in the building, so that everyone could prepare for his arrival. This physician had great intentions; however, his people skills were a little rough. I could see that he meant well, and I recognized that he wanted to do a lot of good things. When we interacted, I always took his feedback with the understanding that he didn't mean things as harshly as he might say them.\"", "\"During my internship, I had a fellow student who didn't pull their weight. This unmotivated person created more work for the rest of the team by being slow and unresponsive. Our team started to complete most of the tasks when it came to group projects. It didn't take much time before our professor noticed this particular individual was slacking. I feel like, in most instances, the underachievers will weed themselves out over time, and it's rarely worth making a fuss over.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "With the ongoing changes in the healthcare services industry, how do you keep your knowledge current?", "answers": ["Employers expect employees to stay up-to-date in their respective fields, and today's technology makes this reasonably easy! List several ways that you receive your industry knowledge and stay on top of trends.  \n\nTell the interviewer about those daily update emails you receive from professional organizations, conferences you attend, and seminars you have taken.\n\nLastly, it's a great idea to ask the interviewer what resources they refer to for industry trends. That question can start up a great conversation, and you may learn a thing or two as well.", "\"Every morning I listen to X Podcast because I find the information to be fresh and valuable. In addition to this podcast, I also subscribe to a couple of industry blogs. One is ABC, and the other is XYZ. I greatly value the information shared between fellow professionals. What resources do you prefer to stay on top of industry trends and changes?\"", "\"I am an avid fan of Google alerts! I will receive an email with the related information any time there is a major headline about the healthcare services industry. In addition to this, I also subscribe to a couple of medical-related journals, including A and B.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "What type of work environment do you dislike working in?", "answers": ["Are you pretty flexible in your ability to work in most environments? Have you experienced a position where the atmosphere wasn't conducive to your productivity?  Be sure to know the type of situation offered in this position before the interview. If you aren't completely clear on the workplace environment or culture, kindly ask the interviewer to expand on the work environment for you.", "\"I can be productive in most work environments, so long as the mentality is positive and teamwork is encouraged. I cannot work in an environment that feels negative or toxic.\"", "\"I prefer to focus on the positive, so if it's okay, I would like to share with you my ideal work environment. My ideal environment is organized, collaborative, positive, energetic, and encouraging. I love working with like-minded people who set challenging goals for themselves. I thrive when I work for supervisors who encourage curiosity and creativity in problem-solving.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "Rate your problem solving skills from 1-10. How do you justify your rating?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know how you would rate your problem-solving skills. Of course, you want to give yourself a strong rating; however, you must remain realistic. Everyone has room to learn and improve! Be sure to justify your score as well.", "\"I rate my problem-solving skills as an 8/10. I will, on occasion, have times when I am not as efficient as I would like to be, but all in all, I do feel that my problem-solving skills are above average. My supervisor and co-workers will attest to my fast reflexes when a problem arises, and they would also say that I remain calm under pressure.\"", "\"I would say I get a solid 8.3 on a scale of 10. It seems weird to give myself something like a .3, but I think of it as an 83%, which is a B- teetering on a solid B. It's a solid grade, with definite room for improvement, since I'm certainly not perfect. The reason for the B-/B grade would be that I'm quick to take action and figure out the solution as I go, but sometimes I could benefit from taking a moment to pause and reflect or gather other contributors before taking action. That said, I believe I generally get the best outcome possible when faced with a challenge.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "What is your greatest weakness?", "answers": ["Pick a weakness that is not a core skill for this position. You can be candid in your answer, recognizing that you aren't great at something and acknowledging your need to improve.  Be sure to have an action plan in place for improving on this weakness. \n\nPerhaps you are watching TED talks to gain skills in a particular area, reading the latest-and-greatest book on the subject, or maybe you are taking a seminar at a nearby community center. We are all human with our weaknesses, so don't be afraid to share yours!", "\"I know this will come off as cliche, but it's truthful. My weakness is not delegating. I know what I want and how I want it done, so it's often easier to do it myself. However, it can inhibit my ability to grow. I cannot take on every step of a project; I need to be able to give the task or a portion of it to another team member or direct report, let go of the control, and know it will be taken care of. I've spoken with my current manager about it, and we've developed a system where he can call me out on the behavior since often I'm not aware of it. By bringing awareness to it at the moment, I find my propensity to hold onto control has decreased, so I'm certainly moving in the right direction.\"", "\"At this point in my career within healthcare services, my newness is my greatest weakness. To overcome this, I have committed to ten extra hours per week of study. I dive into various medical journals and spend a great deal of time educating myself beyond what my degree and internship have offered.\""]}, {"topic": "Healthcare+Services", "question": "Company ABC was initially looking for someone with 5  years' experience in a similar role. Considering you have just 2 years' experience, would you be willing to accept this position at a lower salary?", "answers": ["Are you willing to earn your way up if the interviewer does not want to offer you top compensation? Discuss with the interviewer what you would expect for compensation if offered this position.", "\"I would be happy to earn my way to the top compensation level if required. I do assure you that, despite my being shy of experience by a couple of years, I am a top performer and you would not be disappointed in my performance.\"", "\"I understand I do not quite meet the qualifications of experience you are looking for and am willing to be compensated in adjustment to that fact. However, I do look forward to proving my worth to Company ABC in hopes of being considered for the median salary for the role.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "At Company ABC, we have worked very hard to make sure our workforce is inclusive and represents our customer population.  Tell me about your experience in working with diverse groups of people in a work setting.", "answers": ["Are you accustomed to working with a very large or diverse team of individuals? Assure the interviewer that you can handle an environment that offers diversity. Even better, give an example of being able to embrace diversity in the workplace.", "\"I have worked with diverse groups of people most of my career, including my time in University. I value opinions that are different than my own and find this environment challenging.  If everybody thinks alike, that is not only a boring environment, but it isn't a creative environment.\"", "\"I am so glad you pointed out your need for diversity at Company ABC.  I grew up in a small town that wasn't very diverse, so I specifically chose a college in a more diverse location so I could have exposure to other cultures.  I have learned so much about the beliefs and values of others that I have brought to the workplace to have a higher level of EQ.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "At Company ABC, we believe in continuous feedback so we can all improve.  When is a time you received constructive feedback?", "answers": ["All companies need people who can take criticism and give it without feeling weird or sensitive about it.  Demonstrate to the interviewer how you have used a piece of constructive feedback to improve and get better.", "\"In one of my reviews, I received feedback that I didn't delegate enough and therefore, it made it seem like I didn't trust my colleagues.  I really took that feedback to heart.  I took a look at my work load, which was really high, and made some priority buckets.  There was one bucket of work that was very low risk and I distributed it to my team.  One team member did a really great job so I was able to give her some of the more complex projects.\"", "For example:  \"I received feedback that everybody knows what I am thinking from my non verbal expressions, especially in meetings. That was really tough feedback to hear.  That entire next year, I worked very hard to ensure my facial expressions were positive and neutral versus worried or anxious, no matter what the content of the meetings were about.  It was a tough exercise, but I'm glad I received the feedback or I would not have known this.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "At Company ABC, we challenge ourselves to improve people's health.  When is a time you've pushed and challenged yourself outside your comfort zone?", "answers": ["The medical device industry demands forward-thinking individuals who can continue to do MORE.  The interviewer wants to hear an example of a time you've really stretched yourself for a project or initiative at work.", "\"I was working with clinics in my territory to promote our medical devices and kept hearing that our competitor was offering a better product that was more tech savvy.  I brought this feedback back to our  R & D team but also had an idea on how we could differentiate ourselves from our competitor's product.  I did a bunch of research on how to engineer something like this, even though that is far out of my scope as a sales person.  I was then put on a project team to explore actually developing this upgraded product.  Our team was able to research, design and launch a product that my physicians were so excited about.  It was the most challenging and rewarding experience!\"", "For example:  \"In college, we were given an assignment to create a marketing proposal for a local business.  I did a mix of traditional and digital.  I had seen a new technology mentioned the day before on a blog I subscribe to and even though my project was due in 2 days, I decided to research everything I could find on this new automation technology.  I didn't sleep the night before the project was due, but adding this new technology really made my project stand out.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "Tell me about a time you took initiative on your own.", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you are a go-getter and aren't going to wait to be asked what to do. Walk them through a scenario where you took it upon yourself to fix something and didn't run to your leader with a problem, but had multiple solutions.", "\"I noticed we were taking at least 2 hours a week on a manual report that seemed to be a big waste of time.  I started playing around in our system at the different reporting features and was able to test and customize a report that could take the place of the manual report.  After my testing, I brought the idea to my boss who made a few tweaks, but was thrilled I had discovered a more efficient way to give customers the same information.\"", "For example:  \"I noticed a huge skill gap in the team's use of Microsoft Excel & PPT.  Because I come from a different industry, I had to utilize these tools a lot and volunteered to host a series of lunch & learns for anybody who wanted to brush up on them.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "At Company ABC, we've been voted a best place to work.  What kind of working environment do you thrive in?", "answers": ["Every work environment is different.  The interviewer wants to get a sense of your preference for the atmosphere in which you'll be working.  Be honest, but also demonstrate flexibility since you'd don't yet know what the environment is like.", "\"I can adapt to most work environments.  I've been in very chaotic, noisy environments and can thrive with some strategies to help me focus, like my headphones.  In other positions, it has been very quiet.  I gravitate to environments that are collaborative and not too quiet so people feel like they can ask questions and interact with each other.\"", "\"In my internships, I had exposure to many different settings.  I prefer a busy, fast-paced environment to keep me on my toes. I also like when there are many people around so I can ask questions if I need.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "At Company ABC, giving back to the community is really important to us.  What are you doing in your current position to give back?", "answers": ["Charitable giving is common in the medical device industry.  The interviewer wants to see that you care about more than just a job but that you find joy and purpose in giving back to your community.", "\"At my company, we are close to an elementary school and volunteers are needed to read to the students each week.  I volunteered immediately and have been part of this program for 2 years.  Sometimes it is hard to leave the office each week because I'm so busy, but each time I go there, it is so rewarding. \"", "For example:  \"My company didn't have a robust volunteerism program and we are pretty small, so I actually started a school supply drive to benefit schools in our community.  This isn't something our teams were used to doing, so it took some promotion, but in the end, we ended up with a huge amount to donate.  The schools were so pleased and it really boosted engagement at our office.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "In the medical device industry, many of our sales relationships are with large hospital organizations.  In previous roles, how have you made connections with the right people in large hospital organizations?", "answers": ["B2B sales is critical in the medical device industry, but often times, it is really hard to find the right person to talk to because of the size of these entities.  Think about the persistent methods you have used to make a connection with the decision maker to increase sales.", "\"I have done B2B sales before and my first step is looking at the CRM platform to see who the contact is.  I reach out and if that isn't the right person or that person has left, I do a LinkedIn search to see if I can figure out who is in that role now.  I use many reach-out methods including phone calls, emails, LinkedIn messages, and even dropping by the facility.  By covering all of my bases, I am usually able to find the right person and figure out a way our products can add value to their patients.\"", "For example:  \"I have a lot of industry contacts.  In large hospital organizations, often times it is the chief supply chain officer versus the chief medical officer that you need to start with.  I reach out to some of my colleagues who have products in other spaces to see if they know who I should start with.  Because of the relationships I have built, people want to help me and they know I will help them.  I think my connections could be really valuable to Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "The technology in the medical device industry is changing rapidly.  At Company ABC, we are investing in new technology to help patients and our teams do their jobs more effectively.  How do you keep up to speed with changing technology?", "answers": ["The interviewer is looking for a candidate who is up to speed with the latest technology and can pick up new systems quickly.", "\"Our team is moving from JDE to Oracle.  I was selected to be part of a project team to help with the implementation because I tend to be on the tech-savvy side. I have been building out the process for my function and incorporating feedback from my team so they feel a part of it.  We are now in the testing phases before the go-live and everything is running smoothly.  I'm excited for the new tools and features so we can do our jobs faster.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "What is a work accomplishment you feel very proud about that you'd like to share?", "answers": ["Everybody has that shining moment in their career that they look back on and feel good about.  Share a work accomplishment that is significant to you and let the interviewer hear the passion in your voice.", "\"I have been selected to the President's Club 3 years in a row.  The first year I was selected, I am especially proud of because I was given a territory that was performing really terribly.  I didn't  know if I'd be able to turn it around.  With focus, dedication, and a close eye on numbers, I was able to make really great strides in that region and it is still a high performing area for the company.\"", "For example:  \"I'm really proud of the fact that 3 of the people who reported to me have moved on to leadership roles within my company.  Coaching and mentoring people is really important to me and I spent a lot of time with these individuals talking to them about what it would take to get to the next level.  They were like sponges and listened, and then did exactly what I knew they could do.  Teaching others is something I have a great passion for.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "At Company ABC,  our medical devices can truly change people's lives.  Sometimes, though, a patient may have a question or concern about one of our devices.  How have you handled a difficult customer interaction in a previous position?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know you can handle the stress of a difficult customer interaction.  The customer could be a physician group who use the medical device or an actual patient who has a question or concern about your product.  Show the interviewer that you can stay cool under pressure and resolve the concern.", "\"I am a lead in our department, so I take the calls that are escalated or too difficult for one of the other reps to handle.  I had a customer who was yelling about how much money he spent on the device and it wasn't working.  He was beyond the return date, so we couldn't give him a refund.  I let him get all of his anger out and finish talking.  I then asked him questions and always addressed him by first name to try and build some rapport.  I learned that he hadn't been to see his physician to follow up.  We have relationships with the care-givers at one of the local facilities, so I was able to put him on hold, and see when they had an appointment available.  When I transferred him over to the scheduler, he had calmed down a bit.  It wasn't a perfect scenario, but I tried to treat him with dignity and respect and not take it personal.\"", "For example:  \"I used to be a waitress in college and dealing with difficult customers was my specialty.  My co-workers would always give me the regulars who were cranky because I had a way of working with them that made it look easy.  One evening, I had a customer who was very upset with his food order.  I listened to his concern and asked him if he would like me to bring him something else, but he kept going on and on and was getting quite loud at this point.  I apologized again and asked told him I could give him a discount on his order or bring him another choice.  He ended up taking the discount and leaving, but at least his volume went down and he left.  Difficult customer interactions don't always end perfectly, but I feel I handled the situation appropriately.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "At Company ABC, we value professional development and education.  What is the last learning opportunity you have been able to participate in?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know if you seek to learn new information when given the chance.  Many organizations offer continuing education but some people don't even take advantage of it.  Show the interviewer that learning new information is important to you and how it could benefit the organization.", "\"I am so glad to learn that you are supportive of continuing education.  The last opportunity I had was two months ago.  It was a panel of speakers on how AI is and will continue to change our work.  It was fascinating.  I talked to a few of the speakers after and learned about the systems they are using so I can bring it back to my company for further discussion.  This kind of technology would help us be more efficient in many areas.\"", "For example:  \"I was continuously relying on another colleague to do all of my design work.  Her work load is very full and it would be so much faster to do it myself.  I asked my leader if I could take a 2 day course to learn the design platform.  She agreed so I attended and learned a lot.  I did need to do some additional practicing during my own time, but I was really excited about it, so it didn't feel like work.  Now, I can finish my work much more quickly since I can also do the design part.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "How do you want to grow your career within the medical device industry?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to hear that you would like to stay with the company as you develop new skills.  Tell the interviewer your long term goal, but make sure it aligns with where the company is going.", "\"I noticed at Company ABC, you have offices in over 20 countries.  This is really exciting to me.  I'd love to be in this role for several years, but then think about how I could use the skills I've learned to work in one of your global locations.  I'd love to work overseas for a few years and then come back to a leadership role.\"", "For example:  \"One of the elements of Company ABC that I really love is the career growth opportunities.  I'd love to take the knowledge I'll gain in this role and move to the sales organization to be the person in front of clinicians, showing them the great things our devices can do.  When you are selling something you believe in, it doesn't really feel like selling, it just feels like helping people.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "At Company ABC, we need outside the box thinkers to continue to innovate our company so we can stay competitive in the medical device industry.  Tell me about a time you thought about something differently or proposed a new way of doing something.", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to learn about your creativity and ability to come up with new ideas.  Share with the interviewer your idea, but also if it was executed and how the situation turned out.", "\"I started at my company with a staff who had been there a long time.  I'm a big believer in Lean Six Sigma principles and I saw a ton of waste in our process.  I took some time to get to know the people and learn the current process fully, but then I suggested new ways to streamline our operations such as consolidation vendor agreements, leveraging some of the global contracts we have and have people 'own' more of their own process instead of handing it off to others.  Because I had built relationships with the people in the department first, they were more open to the change.  Within the first year, we were able to produce 30% more revenue with no added staff because of the changes I recommended.\"", "For example:  \"As a new grad, I was on a lot of project teams.  There was an assignment in one of my marketing classes where we had to think about new solutions to generate leads for a real small business in our community.  I did my homework on the company and researched the competitors and main demographic of the customers.  I recommended doing a targeted re-targeting campaign on the largest competitor's website.  They liked my idea and decided to give me a small budget to try out this campaign.  I was able to increased traffic to their website and the number of people who subscribed, so they were really pleased.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "What interests you about working in the medical device industry?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to hear your passion for the industry.  Demonstrate that you feel value in the devices that could positively impact somebody's life.", "\"I have always wanted to work in an industry that is innovative and cutting edge.  It has been really fun to see how medical technology has been able to save lives.  It would be fun coming to work every day knowing you are doing something to better people's lives.\"", "For example:  \"As a new graduate, I have been exploring many different industries and the medical device industry is my number one choice.  I considered going into medicine, but I love the business side of things and this way, I can utilize those skills to help people's quality of life.\"", "\"I have always wanted to work in an industry that is innovative and cutting edge. It has been fascinating to see how medical technology has been able to save lives. It would be great coming to work every day knowing you are doing something to better people's lives.\"", "Good baseline! Next, I recommend adding in specifics related to your career experiences so far, and where you want your career to take you."]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "At Company ABC, we believe in finding the most efficient ways of doing things.  How have you used technology to be more efficient?", "answers": ["Think about ways you have to utilize technology to the fullest but also how you have learned something new and added value with the new tool.", "\"We just implemented all of the Office 365 tools.  There are more programs than I can imagine in that suite, so in my free time, I've been looking at as many as I can to see how we could incorporate these tools into our process. I found a scheduling app that I am testing right now to save some of the back and forth with clients as we try to schedule conversations.  It has saved me at least 2 hours a week so far, so I'm planning on rolling it out to my team next month.\"", "For example:  \"I love finding any means of technology that helps me save time, both at work and at home.  I recently began using an email application that uses machine learning to automatically reply to emails for me. Just with that quick implementation, the application has already saved me countless minutes every day.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "At Company ABC, our medical device products touch lives throughout the world.  We have offices in over 20 countries.  Tell me about experience you have working with a global workforce.", "answers": ["In global companies, there are many nuances.  The EQ and exposure to working with people in other countries is really important to create community and understanding.  Highlight any experiences you've had and highlight your excitement about working in a global environment.", "\"I have learned so much from the global experiences I've had so far.  One of the biggest learnings I have had is that words mean different things to different people.  It is a good idea not to use expressions or slang terms when working with people in other countries because the translation doesn't come through.  I try to speak slowly, clearly, and use simple words to make sure we are understanding one another.\"", "For example: \"I haven't had the opportunity to work in a global organization yet, but this is one of the reasons I'm really excited to work at Company ABC.  I went to a college with many international students and I learned a great deal about cultures and traditions in other countries.  I learned a lot about listening to understand versus talking to be heard.  Given the chance, I could represent Company ABC in a very positive light to global colleagues.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "In the medical device industry, a background in science is really helpful so you can learn how our products work and help save lives.  Tell me more about your background in health sciences or anatomy.", "answers": ["At Company ABC, every employee has to have basic level knowledge of what the medical devices do but beyond that, if you don't understand basic anatomy and the medical conditions associated with the devices, you can't really see the big picture.  Give the interviewer any background you have in human anatomy or science so they see you intellectual horse-power.", "\"I started my college career wanting to be a physical therapist.  I took all of the basics in chemistry, biology, and anatomy.  As I went on, though, I realized that my passion for business outweighed my passion for hand's on patient care.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "In the medical device industry, we are highly regulated by the FDA and other entities.  What experience do you have working with regulatory bodies?", "answers": ["The medical device industry is one of the most highly regulated spaces to be in.  Tell the interviewer what exposure you have had in this space.  If you haven't had this yet, be honest, but also acknowledge that you know what they are talking about.", "\"In my current company, I work on a team with those in government relations on the device that I manage.  I work with our engineers and scientists to make sure we are proving and testing all the claims we are making about our product.  The government relations team is actually the ones with the regular contact with FDA but I help to support their work to make sure we have approval.\"", "For example:  \"I have never worked in the medical device space, but my company has other regulatory bodies that have regulations we need to follow, so I am accustomed to reporting and adhering to certain standards.  I'm confident I could quickly learn all the elements I need to regarding the FDA very quickly.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "When starting a new job, what are steps you've taken to develop a 30, 60, 90 day plan for yourself?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to make sure you'll acclimate quickly and have concrete goals to set the path.  Show them that you plan out your goals but also recognized you need your team to help.", "\"I like to take the first week to meet people and look at the data to see what the story is. also love to ask questions... many times, people within the department have thoughts and feedback that becomes really important.  I then start carving out the 30/60/90 day plan and ask my leader for feedback to see if s/he agrees or has any other initiatives they believe are important that I've missed. Keeping the lines of communication open is very important at the beginning!\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "At Company ABC, we do a lot of cross functional team projects.  Tell me about a project team you've been on and your role.", "answers": ["If you thought group projects ended in college, you were wrong!  Most organizations have their share of project work as well as the day to day work.  Walk the interviewer through a successful project where you played a big role and had large ownership.", "\"At my company, I was selected to represent my department in a larger project team to implement a new CRM system.  We met weekly, sometimes twice a week for about 12 months,  My role was to make sure our old CRM system data converted into the new one and that it was organized in a useful way.  I collaborated with IT as well as the project manager for the new system to make sure the data was useful and organized.  When the new system launched, our old and rich data was there and useable so that we could maintain relationships we our customers seamlessly.\"", "For example:  \"In college, we had to do a big project in my Marketing class where we created an advertising campaign for a local business.  I was in a group with 4 people, none of which I knew very well.  We started talking to figure out where people's strengths were and there was clearly a person who was more technical, one who was a really good presenter and communicator, a financial person, and me, the creative person.  We all had our own lanes, but came together to help on the different pieces.  We pitched our idea and the business we had modeled, actually wanted to implement the majority of our ideas.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "In the medical device industry, it is important our teams are cohesive so we can continue to drive excellence.  Tell me about a time you gave feedback to a peer?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you aren't shy about giving feedback to your peers to help them succeed.  True leaders show their true colors by mentoring and supporting colleagues, not just by supporting and training direct reports.  Show the interviewer that you care about the development of others are aren't afraid to give feedback.", "\"I noticed my peer was really struggling with her communication with another leader.  He would get very anxious and even out of breath when he was telling me about what was going on.  One of the times that he was venting to me, I listened, but then asked a few more questions to probe deeper.  Through my questions, my colleague was able to think of a few different strategies to try when working with this person in the future.  The power of the question is very powerful.\"", "For example:  \"We had bi-weekly team meetings and we do a lot of brainstorming during that time.  One of my colleagues came across really negative and would shoot down people's ideas really quickly.  This really deflated the energy in the team.  I asked him to go for a walk with me and I told him how his behavior was being perceived.  He was caught off guard by this feedback.  However, because we were walking and our bodies were moving, it helped him to calm down and hear me.  At the end, he thanked me for pulling him aside and talking to him about it and I could tell at the next meeting that he came with an attitude that was different and more open.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "Tell me about your related education and training that prepared you for this position.", "answers": ["Take a few minutes to walk the interviewer through your college work, graduate work or any skill development opportunities you have had.  Make sure you put emphasis on how that experience will help you succeed in this position.", "\"I actually have a degree in music, but went back to graduate school for business.  I think the musical part of my brain keeps me creative, but I have the finance, accounting, and consultancy skills you need to succeed in this role.\"", "\"I have a degree in biology and thought I wanted to go on to medical school, but discovered I really like the business side of health care.  I started taking classes in business and management and did an internship in the corporate office of a hospital system.  These combination of experiences would give me a really good base for a position at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "In the medical device industry, there is a lot of industry jargon and lingo and many acronyms to learn to understand the business.  What are some strategies you've used to acclimate quickly when you've started a new job in the past?", "answers": ["The medical device industry is highly technical.  Even if you aren't an engineer, you still need to know very specific information about the product so you understand the business.  There is a learning curve for any new employee, but the ones who can pick up things quickly set themselves up for success faster.", "\"When I started my last job, I was hearing so much unfamiliar terminology my first week, so I started making a list and then when I had time to ask people or look things up, I'd add it to the list until I knew what everything was.  My list became pretty extensive, so the HR person who does onboarding actually asked me if she could give it to new hires from now on because it was really helpful.\"", "For example:  \"I love Google.  In almost any environment, when you don't know something, you can start on Google and go from there.  I take the time to research outside of work the elements of the industry that I don't know to get up to speed faster.  By week 2 and 3, I'm have impressed the people I work with as contributing to the business.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "At Company ABC, our organization is highly matrixed with US and global partners on our teams.  How have you navigated this kind of environment in the past?", "answers": ["Working in a matrixed organization means you have multiple people you are accountable to, often with competing priorities.  It can be complex to navigate in this space, so the interviewer wants to know you can handle working in this environment.", "\"Currently I report to a leader here in the US, but my functional leader is in the UK. With the time change, it can be difficult for us to reach each other, so I changed my hours slightly to be in the office earlier so I could talk more via Skype with this person.  I felt like our emails weren't necessarily the most effective means of communication.  With my leader in the US and I try very hard to keep her in the loop about what I'm doing and make her feel like I'm including her in my decisions.  After a month or so of trial and error, I have a nice system down now.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Devices", "question": "Many of our projects have very strict timelines.  Tell me about a time you missed a deadline or deliverable and how you handled it.", "answers": ["Everybody makes mistakes and it is best to pick a project where the missed deadline wasn't fatal and you were able to recover and learn from your mistake.", "\"We had a new leader start recently.  To get her up to speed, she asked for a number of different reports in a 2 day turn around time.  She needed them for an executive meeting she was going to.  One of the reports was very manual and with my other responsibilities, I just wasn't able to get it done in time.  I went to her office and told her that I could have this complete tomorrow, but I wasn't able to finish it for her meeting this morning.  She asked what I was working on and I explained my competing priority.  She recommended that I come check with her to get help prioritizing in the future.  I learned a big lesson that day about using your leader as an advocate for you.  I should have come to her first.  I've kept this in mind in other scenarios when I've had competing deadlines.\"", "For example:  \"As a new grad, I remember in college, I had a huge project due in my economics class at the end of the semester.  I made a schedule that would help me get all of the pieces of this project done in time, but part of my project required outside data that I needed from a different university.  There was a delay in this data getting to me and it delayed some of the subsequent steps of my project.  I ended up getting it just a few days before the deadline.  As hard as I tried, I couldn't get it submitted on time.  I was absolutely devastated.  I called my professor who understood, but I got a reduced grade because it was late.  I learned that I should have chosen a data source that was more readily available to me but also that I could have looped in my professor earlier who might have had another idea.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "Are you familiar with what nitrites are and how they affect the human body?", "answers": ["The goal of research is to recognize ways to prevent or develop ways to effectively treat and cure.  Those who work in cancer research support that idea that a healthy diet is one thing we all can do in an effort to maintain wellness.    Nitrites are chemical additives used to preserve and add flavoring to most lunch meats, including cold cuts and hot dogs. Once in the body, they react with body chemicals and turn into cancer-causing carcinogens. Having knowledge of things like nitrites will show the interviewer your level of interest in learning and educating others.  Share any knowledge you have.", "\"I have always found it interesting how the foods we consume affect us on a cellular level.  The effect that nitrites have on a body is astounding, especially knowing the amount of processed foods that so many people consume.  I have participated in some continuing education classes and have taught a few classes regarding cancer fighting foods.\"", "\"I have recently spent some time researching optimal diets for cancer patients.  One thing that all researchers agreed upon was that processed foods, especially lunch meats and hotdogs should be avoided because of the nitrites in those types of foods..\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "Company ABC is passionate about finding ways to help prevent cancer.  What makes you feel like you would be a good fit here?", "answers": ["All employers want to know that an employee is as passionate about their cause as the company is.  What made you feel interested in Company ABC?  Share your thoughts with the interviewer.", "\"I am passionate about cancer research.  I realize that there are other companies who conduct cancer research, but knowing that Company ABC is as focused on prevention as a cure really drew me to apply here.\"", "\"I have been involved in research for quite a while, but I wanted to find somewhere that I could focus on disease prevention specifically.  I looked at different research companies and felt that :company's: mission statement was the most in line with my goals of finding ways of prevention.  I look forward to seeing where I will best fit with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "Any time there is a work environment with groups of people, it is important to have effective relationship-building skills.  What makes you a strong relationship builder?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you would treat everyone at Texas Children's Hospital with great respect and a positive attitude. Discuss the ways that you would build strong and healthy relationships if hired.", "\"I have often been complimented on my relationship building skills. I like to get to know people and ask them questions about themselves. Most people love to talk about themselves, and I find it's a great and simple way to start building rapport with others. I consider myself to be a strong relationship builder and take pride in my 'people skills'. \"", "I think it is important for everyone within a team to understand the importance of a strong working relationship.  Understand that, I believe I would be a great ambassador of positive relationships here at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "While many new medicines are now available to treat certain cancers, many of them are only available for clinical trials.  Have you ever worked with clinical studies?", "answers": ["The availability of new medications is generally governed by results of clinical trials associated with those medications.  If you have clinical trial experience, share it; if you don't, share your thoughts.", "\"I have not yet had an opportunity to work with clinical trials.  I have usually been on the other side of research, gathering information, offering comparisons, etc. until medications are ready to be presented.  I am supportive of medication clinical trials and hope to have an opportunity in the future to be closely involved for the duration of a trial.\"", "\"I worked with a previous company that had great focus on clinical trials for cancer treatment.  It is astounding to see the way medicine is changing and developing.  I look forward to the next trial I can be involved with.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "Some physicians and scientist argue that too much of the 'War on Cancer' is misdirected by focusing more on treatment rather than on prevention.  Do you agree with this?", "answers": ["We all have opinions about ways that medical research and treatment could be improved.  With cancer research, especially, it is frustrating  when researchers want to cure a disease and can't explain the true cause.  Do you think that there is inequality when comparing treatment vs. prevention in cancer care?", "\"I have heard people voice this concern before.  However, I do not know if I think there is as great a different between the efforts to prevent or cure.  All healthcare research requires a bit of a 'balancing act,' so to speak.  That is why I think it is important to have a diversity of people involved in research projects.  If we can divide groups of people and have each group focus on something different and then come together with our ideas and implement them, perhaps we can find a way to prevent new occurrences and cure those who have already been diagnosed.\"", "\"While I can understand the frustration of wanting to prevent cancer occurrence, I disagree with the statement that the focus of research is more on treatment than a cure.  Cancer prevention can be increased by individuals participating in a healthier lifestyle.  These are things that no amount of research can enforce.  We can only educate.  When others choose to participate in activities that cause cancer, we then are expected to provide a cure.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "The medical research industry has a diverse workforce.  Have you ever worked with a diverse group of pe", "answers": ["Some people are intimidated when faced with learning new cultures and beliefs, but in the healthcare industry, it is crucial to provide effective care.  The interviewer wants to know that you are open to meeting and learning about new people and becoming an integral part of the team.  Be positive with your response.\n\n\"I think diversity in the healthcare industry is essential.  People from all over the world now call our country their home.  I believe learning about and showing an appreciation for people from different walks of life only makes us stronger as we build upon the common bond of caring for others.\"", "\"I think diversity in the healthcare industry is essential.  People from all over the world now call our country their home.  I believe learning about and showing an appreciation for people from different walks of life only makes us stronger as we build upon the common bond of caring for others.\"", "For example:  \"The largest diverse group I worked with was probably when I did my clinical rotation at University Medical Center.  I was afforded the opportunity to meet people from different cultures, religions, and professional backgrounds.  It gave me an eye-opening experience of how many wonderful people there are!\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "In a recent poll, much of the general population stated that they were unaware that men can develop breast cancer.  Have you ever researched anything regarding the occurrence of breast cancer in men?", "answers": ["Because breast cancer occurs less frequently in men than women, many people are unaware of its occurrence at all.  If you have any experience researching this subject, share that knowledge with the interviewer.  Remember, your research does not have to be in a clinical lab.  Any studies you have performed should be shared.", "\"I did a case study previously comparing the effects of estrogen on both men and women and the percentage of those studied who developed breast cancer.  I would like to see more  of breast cancer research to be target specific to male patients.\"", "\"I have assisted with breast cancer research before.  The studies I had part in involved both male and female patients.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "While doing research or cancer studies, what is something you have learned that others may not know? This can be a cancer fact or something related to cancer patients.", "answers": ["Often, interviewers will ask questions that include 'what is your opinion....' or 'what have you learned...'.  These type of questions are useful for an interviewer to see where your interests lie and how motivated you are with regard to learning independently.  Share something you learned while researching cancer and include in the answer why it is of interest to you or what makes it important in providing care to cancer patients.", "\"I once did a study on depression and anxiety disorders that developed after a cancer diagnosis.  In that study I found that cancer victims are twice as likely to commit suicide than the general population.  Additionally, male cancer victims were more likely to commit suicide soon after their diagnosis.  With the advances in cancer treatment globally, realizing the number of people who still feel the need to end their own lives was a stark discovery for me personally.\"", "\"I conducted some interviews among oncologists and did some statistic research.  I learned that there are presently over 13 million cancer survivors living in the United States presently.  To me, this is something that can offer hope to newly diagnosed patients and their families.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "Research has shown that postmenopausal women who are more physically active are less likely to die from breast cancer.  What are your thoughts as to why this may be so?", "answers": ["Estrogen is necessary for the body to function. In women, the ovaries are the main source of estrogen. In men, an enzyme converts testosterone to estrogen. Fat cells in both men and women can also make estrogen. This is why too much estrogen is commonly seen in obesity.  In women, too much estrogen is linked to an increased risk for post-menopausal breast, endometrial and ovarian cancers.\nWhile not everyone understands the link between obesity and cancer risks, having some general knowledge such as the facts stated here, is beneficial.  Share your knowledge with the interviewer.", "\"I have to admit, I learned the hard way about obesity's relation to increased cancer risks.  For most of my adult life, I battled obesity.  My family practitioner gave me some educational material to read that was focused on health risks related to obesity.  In that literature, there was an article about post-menopausal women who were obese having a higher risk for developing breast cancer.  Until then, I never thought about the fat cells in our bodies creating estrogen.  I think so much focus is put on the ovaries being the estrogen producing organ that we often overlook other factors.\"", "\"I have researched some studies regarding the occurrence of breast cancer in post-menopausal women.  Many people don't realize that,although ovaries produce estrogen, fat cells in our bodies also produce it.  Although men and women both have estrogen in our bodies, women have a higher amount.  Even after menopause, those who are overweight have an increased amount of estrogen in their bodies because of the fat cells producing it.  Estrogen can cause an increased risk of breast cancer occurrence.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "One of the most frustrating things for anyone in the healthcare industry, especially medical research, is the fact that we have to treat cancer victims who were exposed to cancer-causing agents by others.  Can you think of an example of this?", "answers": ["Lifestyle habits are often associated with the risk of developing certain types of cancer.  Unfortunately, there are things that can people can be exposed to that are not because of personal choices.  Are you familiar with any of these instances?  Share your experience with the interviewer.", "\"One of the most common things I can think of is the development of lung cancer in patients who have never smoked.  While those who choose to smoke are aware of the risks and take those chances willingly, it is unfortunate that those who choose to refrain from smoking are still at risk due to exposure to second-hand smoke.\"", "\"I can think of a few examples of patients who are exposed to a cancer-causing agent.  For instance, exposure to HPV infection is a risk factor.  I think the risk of developing cancer because of HPV is an important opportunity for education on safe sex practices and the option of taking immunizations, such as the vaccine, Gardisil.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "Company ABC is supportive of employers who interested in continuing their education.  Have you thought of furthering your degree, and if so, would you stay within the research industry?", "answers": ["There are people who choose a career and later return to school.  Some have the objective is to get a higher degree in the same field or to change careers altogether.  This question gives the interviewer an opportunity to know you and what your future plans may be.  In turn, your answer allows the interviewer the chance to see where you may fit within Company ABC now and in the future.  If you have thoughts of continuing your education, don't be afraid to share that with the interviewer.  Just remember to point out why you feel you would be an asset to Company ABC now.", "\"I have considered going back to college a few times, but at this point in my life, research is my passion.  I feel I am already in an industry that is important and growing.  I feel like, if I were to take any additional classes, I would want them to be something that would add value to the education and experience I have now.\"", "\"I love research and am comfortable where I am, at this point in my career.  I have considered in years to come, when I am older, I may transition slightly into the realm of education within medical research.  That way I can still do research and have some input, but I could also educate those who are coming into the field after me.  For now, though, I am very happy with what I am doing and really look forward to seeing where you think I will be the greatest asset at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "Have you ever been involved with any efforts to secure funding for cancer research?", "answers": ["Most of the funding of cancer research by private voluntary health organizations comes from individuals, but some comes from grants to those organizations (and so might be counted as foundation or government funding as well as spending by the private voluntary health organization).  If you have been involved in helping to write grant applications or soliciting private organizations to become a part of research funding, this could be considered an asset.  Share any experience you may have.", "\"I used to work for a company that operated mostly from money received from federal grants.  When I worked there, I was an under-study to the head grant-writer.  I have hoped to find placement with a company where I can do research but also offer my services in securing funding to further our research efforts.\"", "\"Yes, I have assisted with attempts to secure private funding for breast cancer research.  I have found that the more specifically focused a research project is, the more easily private funding is secured.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "What made you choose a career in cancer research?", "answers": ["Medical research is essential in finding causes and possible cures of many diseases.   With the many healthcare career options available, what made you choose research?", "\"I have always been intrigued by medicine and wellness.  When I began to try and decide on a long-term career, I felt that becoming a researcher may give me an opportunity to find ways to care for others that would last a lifetime.\"", "\"From the time I was a teenager, I knew I wanted to be involved in some type of medical research.  After my grandmother was diagnosed with lung cancer and died, I decided that cancer research was what I wanted to do.  I think that participating in an effort to find a cure is one way that I have been able to honor her memory.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "Since February 2009, over 40 million doses of Gardasil have been distributed globally.  Have you studied this vaccine, and what are your thoughts on its use?", "answers": ["Gardasil is a vaccine for use in the prevention of certain strains of human papillomavirus, specifically HPV types 6, 11, 16 and 18.  This vaccine is one of the most recent vaccines included on the childhood immunization schedule.  Many parents have conflicted feelings about their children being given this vaccine.  Remember, when an interviewer asks your opinion, he may not always expect you to agree with his.  Nevertheless, be respectful with your answer no matter what your opinion is.", "\"I have studied FDA and CDC recommendations regarding vaccines in limited detail.  Like most new medications or research projects, vaccines are commonly under scrutiny.  It is understandable that a person who is not educated on how vaccines work would be apprehensive about them.  For me, personally, if there is anything I can do to help reduce the risk of developing cancer, I want to do it.\"", "\"I have studied the use of Gardisil as a preventive vaccine.  While I understand that some people view vaccines as a negative option in preventive care, I am supportive of any attempt to help reduce the risk of disease.  I have found that the benefits outweigh the risks associated with Gardisil, like any other vaccine.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "An estimated 12,000 children are diagnosed with cancer in the United States annually.  Have you ever participated in any research that is focused on childhood cancer?", "answers": ["While cancer is a devastating diagnosis, childhood cancer is all the more devastating.  The thought behind this is that, while some cancers are not caused by lifestyles such as smoking or other risk factors, most childhood cancers deal with some type of genetics or unintentional exposure to carcinogens.  Some researchers focus only on childhood cancer causes and efforts for a cure.  If you have never participated in any specific childhood cancer study, you may have attended a lecture or heard of some type of research.  Anything you can share with the interviewer that shows your interest will be a positive part of this interview.", "\"While I have not participated in focused childhood cancer studies, I have attended some seminars regarding cancer research and some of the long-term effects that childhood cancer survivors experience vs. adult cancer survivors.  If I were given an opportunity to participate in a focused study, childhood cancer would be one of the things I would choose.\"", "\"When I was beginning my career in research, I was given an assignment to choose a topic related to childhood cancer patients/survivors and present a report on that topic.  I chose to focus on fertility issues related to childhood cancer survivors.  I researched studies that had been conducted and interviewed some survivors.  Many of those patients experienced premature menopause and were not able to have children of their own.  While not all childhood cancer survivors experience this, based on the prior treatment that each of the survivors I interviewed had, the study revealed that radiation and chemotherapy treatment affected the ovaries and caused premature menopause.  It was an interesting study.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "Research has shown that skin cancer is the most common type of cancer seen in the United States.  Have you ever studied skin cancer or the possible ways to decrease the risk of developing it?", "answers": ["Although there are risk factors for all cancers, skin cancer preventive measures are simple, yet often neglected by others.  Share your thoughts with the interviewer regarding ways to prevent this cancer and any knowledge you may have from your research.", "\"Being someone with fair skin, I have always had to take measures to protect my skin.  One of the most difficult things, for me, is having to cover my skin when out in the sun because I love having a suntan and the feeling of the sun on my skin.  I think many people, especially younger people, neglect to understand the seriousness of this type of cancer.\"", "\"I did not have a great deal of knowledge about skin cancer until I began considering a career in cancer research.  I actually thought it would be an easier topic for me to study as I began to transition into this career.  It wasn't until I really started studying that I discovered how common skin cancer is and the many ways that people can help protect themselves and reduce the risk of developing it.  Simple things like wearing sunscreen with a high SPF or clothing to cover the skin when out in the sun are a great way to help.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "Company ABC likes to find areas of interest to our employees when assigning different research projects.  Is there a particular cancer that you would be interested in conducting a research project on?", "answers": ["Being given the opportunity to say what area of research is most interesting to you will allow the interviewer to see if there is a place where employment needs meet your interest which creates a win-win.  This is a chance to say what you want without seeming demanding.  Share what interests you and why.", "\"I read an article recently about prostate cancer.  The article said that prostate cancer is the leading cause of cancer-related death among African American men.  I would be very interested in studying this and do a comparison on its occurrence and prognosis across racial and cultural backgrounds.\"", "\"I would like to do a study on metastatic breast cancer.  I have known some women who were diagnosed with breast cancer.  One of them experienced metastasis while the others did not.  I would like to do a case study on the causes of metastasis and possible ways of preventing recurrence.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "Company ABC works with a variety of physicians, scientists, and special researchers.  One specialty we consult with is nutritionists.  What is your understanding of how nutrition may play a role in the development of certain cancers?", "answers": ["The link between cancer and diet is just as mysterious as the disease itself. Much research has pointed toward certain foods and nutrients that may help prevent--or, conversely, contribute to--certain types of cancer.  Do you have any experience linking nutritional status to the development or prevention of certain cancers?", "\"Some of the research I conducted previously showed that because adipose tissue is hormonally active, excess body fat changes the hormonal environment of the body. Body fat secretes particular chemical signals that alter normal cell functioning. When we lose body fat and maintain a lean body, certain hormones drop and this may be why risk is reduced.\"", "\"I took a nutrition class in college and one of the classes focused on healthful foods that were thought to have cancer fighting qualities.  It was an eye-opening opportunity for me that led me to not only change the way I eat, but has also helped me as I have studied nutrition and cancer on a more in depth level.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "Statistics have shown that cancer patients who are married are more likely to survive than those who are single.  Do you have thoughts that may support this statement?", "answers": ["Research shows that when you're married, you're less likely to die from major illnesses, including  heart disease and cancer as well.   A study published recently in the journal Cancer looked at more than 780,000 Californians diagnosed with cancer over a nine-year period.  It found that single men were 27 percent more likely to die from their condition than married men were. For single women, the mortality rate was 19 percent higher than for their married counterparts.  What are some reasons you can think of that may support these findings?", "\"I can understand the idea that states married people may survive longer.  In fact, I would venture to say that anyone with a strong support system or a long-term commitment with a significant other will be more likely to survive any illness.  I believe this is in part because when a patient is going through a tough treatment plan like chemotherapy, having someone to encourage them through it helps them to endure the difficultly and complete the plan.\"", "\"I can think of a few reasons that this may be true.  One factor that I think is conceivable is that a married couple often has two incomes which allows them to afford healthcare costs.  Also, if someone has a spouse or partner, that person often encourages them to seek a diagnosis and treatment plan in hopes of becoming well again.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "What would your previous co-workers say were the best and worst qualities about you?", "answers": ["No one wants to share anything negative about themselves.  However, any honest person will admit that he has both good and bad characteristics.  The important thing is recognizing the things that may need to be improved and being willing to address them.  Share some things about your personal qualities with the interviewer and remember, when sharing any quality that could be improved, tell how you are working to make a change.", "\"I would have to say that one of the things I'd like to improve about myself and that most people recognize about me is I always want to be the 'fixer.'  While I know that this is not always a negative thing, for me, I have often let the fact that I couldn't fix a certain situation be something that troubled me.  On a lighter note, I believe I have a positive, out-going personality.  I enjoy getting to know others and like to make them feel comfortable.\"", "\"My best quality, I believe, is that I am willing to work on any project I am asked to take on.  My worst quality is that I am willing to take on too many projects at once.  I've had to learn to pace myself and prioritize things that need to be done so that  am not overwhelmed and so that my quality of work does not suffer because I am too busy.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "Although much research involves a team approach, Company ABC has many employees who work independently and then participate in groups to share information.  Do you prefer a team or individual work environment?", "answers": ["Your preference of working individually or within a team is important.  Given the form of this question, expressing one preference over the other will not disqualify you from employment.  This is your chance to have some say in where you may be placed.  Remember, though, to add that you want to be a part of Company ABC and are willing to take a position if offered, even if it is not your first preference.", "\"I consider myself an easy-going person and I enjoy being challenged.  While I don't mind working independently, I like working in a group.  I enjoy working in a group because I get to learn from other's experience and opinions.\"", "\"Although I work well with others, I enjoy independent projects.  I have a more reserved personality and enjoy challenging myself.  However, I am excited about the prospect of becoming a part of Company ABC and would be willing to accept a position whether it is an individual or group assignment.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "Have you ever done any volunteer work or public education related to cancer research?", "answers": ["While volunteering is likely not a requirement for Company ABC, your willingness to volunteer or provide education regarding cancer research tells the interviewer that you are committed to being involved in any efforts possible to help create awareness.  If you have not volunteered in the past, that's OK.  Ask about opportunities for employees to be involved with research on a community/volunteer level.", "\"One thing I have wanted to do is become more involved in educating the public about our cancer research efforts.  I've spent a great deal of time conducting research, but I've not yet had the opportunity to share that research on a public level.  If Company ABC has an opportunity for someone to research as well as educate others, I would love to hear about it.\"", "\"I have participated in some public education classes such as at health units on more than one occasion.  Much of the substance of the encounters involved educating healthcare providers about efforts to help reduce the risk of developing cancer so that they could, in turn, provide more up-to-date statistics to their clients.  I would like to explore opportunities to be more involved with community education regarding cancer research and options for treatment.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "Many people have voiced different opinions regarding embryonic stem cell research.  What is your understanding of this branch of research and do you have thoughts about why some people are opposed to this?", "answers": ["There are various reasons that people voice opposition to stem cell research.  Even if you have never worked with stem cell research, you can share your thoughts about why some people may be opposed.", "\"I believe that the majority of people who oppose embryonic stem cell research do so because they don't have a clear understanding of what type of cells are used and the benefits that the research can accomplish.  Embryonic stem cells are derived from the inner cells of human blastocysts, which occur 5-10 days after fertilization, but before implantation into the uterus.  I honestly believe if those in opposition were educated to understand that embryonic stem cells are not taken from a living fetus they would be  more supportive.\"", "\"I believe there are many reasons that people oppose stem cell research.  When the word 'embryonic' is used, the majority of the population relates this to an unborn child.  If people can understand that a pregnancy has not been achieved at the time these cells are harvested and can know that cloning for reproductive purposes in human beings is not legal, they would be more open to the idea of this type of research.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "Company ABC would like to employ researchers who are interested in working on long-term projects.  With that in mind, what changes do you anticipate to occur within the next 2-3 years?", "answers": ["Knowing what goals you have and any changes you anticipate in your life will give the interviewer an opportunity to evaluate two things: 1. what positions are available that won't disrupt your plans and, 2.  are you interested in having a long-term relationship within the company?  Change is good and growth is encouraged.  However,  because employers invest time and money in training new employees, they prefer that they have a plan to stay for the long-term.  Still, if you don't plan on being in the same geographical area five years from now, it's OK to say that now.  With companies as large as Mercy Health Systems, there are often opportunities for transfers to other facilities within the same network.  Either way, being upfront and honest is always appreciated.", "\"I recently became engaged.  Although we have not set a date yet, we have agreed to wait twelve months before the marriage.  My fiance' just passed the Bar exam here and has been offered an opportunity to join an existing law firm.  Presently, our plans are to stay where we are and build a career, not just work a job.  Also, we do not plan on having children for at least two years after our marriage.  We both feel that being able to become established in our careers and save for our future would be the responsible thing to do before starting a family.\"", "\"I'm glad to know that Company ABC is hoping to place employees who are interested in long-term employment.  I love research and feel like I could adjust anywhere if needed.  However, I would really like to find a place where I can work on long-term projects.  I like to see projects as they are started and then be able to follow them through completion."]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "Have you ever had a disagreement with a co-worker, and, if so,  how did you resolve it?", "answers": ["Any time you work with someone else, there is a chance of having a disagreement about something at one time or another.  The interviewer knows this.  It's human nature for people to have their own opinions.  What is important to the interviewer in this question is whether or not you are willing to compromise and work through difficult situations with your co-workers.  Being unwilling to compromise or find alternative solutions to a dispute can affect everyone on the team, even if it is indirectly.  Sharing a personal experience is OK, but do not embellish it to 'be the hero.'", "\"I believe if we think about it, each of us could remember at least one disagreement with a friend or co-worker.  Although I consider myself to be pretty easy-going, I am also very passionate about my patients and the care that they receive.  I have been aware of disagreements between other co-workers, but really like to think of myself as more of a peacekeeper.  I feel like professional people should be able to discuss things logically and come to an agreement that is satisfactory for everyone involved.\"", "\"I think the most common disagreement between myself and others have involved our personal feelings about how healthcare should be carried out.  However, I have learned, as have most of the people that I have worked with, that while our opinions are important, plans of care are designated by strict guidelines and with the input of everyone on the care team as well as the patient.  Learning to respect those guidelines and patient wishes usually resolves issues that arise\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "If you were the person responsible for hiring new employees, what qualities would you be looking for during the interview?  Do you feel that you display those qualities yourself?", "answers": ["There is more than one reason for asking this question.  First, the interviewer wants to know what qualities you think are important to perform this job.  Second, and most importantly, your answer will tell the interviewer if you hold yourself to the same standard as you do others.    If you want to see certain characteristics in your peers, you should be able to tell the interviewer with confidence that you possess those traits, as well.  This question is one that interviewers often use to distinguish sincerity on the part of the candidate.", "\"I believe that honesty is important no matter what job title a person holds.  I have found that being honest with people creates an atmosphere of mutual trust and respect.  Those qualities, I feel, are essential when building rapport with patients and co-workers.\"", "\"I believe self-confidence and accountability are important.  I hope to always display those characteristics and to encourage them in others.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "Being a medical researcher is rewarding, but can also be very stressful at times.  Can you share a situation that was difficult for you and how you worked through it?", "answers": ["The interviewer recognizes that, while being involved in medical research is rewarding and has its benefits, it can often be trying at times.  This question gives you the chance to show how your vulnerability meets your strengths.  Having balance between the two is crucial.  Being willing to open up to the interviewer about a situation that was emotional for you and how you were able to cope will show him what can be expected of you when you are faced with a difficult situation in the future.", "\"I believe any job has its stressful situations.  One case that I will never forget occurred when I was doing a pediatric rotation.  We had a four year old child that was admitted due to having seizures.  After further testing, it was discovered that the child had a brain tumor.   The tumor was very advanced and she lost her life because of it.  That time was very emotional for everyone on the care team.  Fortunately, we had a good team leader who gave us an opportunity to talk with her and one another about the overwhelming grief that we felt.  I have found that talking through emotions is a great way to work through any unresolved grief.\"", "\"One of the most stressful situations I can recall was when I was working with a group of individuals on a research project.  We all had different responsibilities within the project.  Just before the designated date that we were going to meet and combine all of our information so that we could prepare the report, one of the team members resigned without notice and without forwarding the work that he was responsible for.  It was very stressful at the time, but we quickly learned the real definition of teamwork as we spent some extra hours and pulled together to make the project a success.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "If you are offered a position with Company ABC that required travel, would you accept it?", "answers": ["Some people jump at the chance to have a great job with the benefit of travel.  If you are one of those people, a simple 'yes' answer is great.  If you would prefer not to travel, say so, but offer a reason why that option is not appealing to you.", "\"I would love to travel to conduct research for Company ABC.  Is there an employment position available here that that requires travel?\"", "\"While I would not disagree to travel at times, I have small children and would prefer a position that offers more time at home.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "If you were asked to choose a research specialty other than cancer, what would you next choice be?", "answers": ["Researchers have so much to choose from with regard to a specialty area.  In fact, many research companies offer different areas opportunity.  Sharing an alternative to cancer research would give the interviewer the chance to find a perfect fit for you in the event that the cancer division does not have an immediate opening.", "\"I love cancer research.  I am also very interested in communicable disease research.\"", "\"I am very interested in research regarding Alzheimer's and dementia.   While cancer research is my favorite, I definitely would not turn down an opportunity to do Alzheimer's research.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Cancer", "question": "Have you ever personally participated in a clinical trial?", "answers": ["Many researchers have been known to take part in clinical trials themselves.  If you have, share your thoughts regarding what type of trial you participated in and the outcome of the trial.  If you have not, would you consider doing so?", "\"I am a member of a health and wellness company that sells nutritional supplements.  A few years ago when the company offered a new supplement that was designed to help control hunger, I participated with a clinical trial.  It was very effective and I lost 25 lbs.\"", "\"I have never participated in a clinical trial, but I have followed several.  I would not be opposed to participating in a trial if the opportunity presented itself.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "What interests you about the central nervous system?", "answers": ["Interviewers almost always ask questions like 'what interests you....'  or 'why did you choose....'  Sharing your interests is a way for the interviewer to get to know you.  Additionally, sharing what interests you the most will help the interviewer try to find placement for you within that preference.", "\"Knowing that one system in the body controls and has an effect on every other system has always been interesting to me.  I enjoy learning and discovering new ways that medical advances give hope to those who suffer from CNS disorders.\"", "\"I have always had an interest in how the brain works and how the central nervous system controls functions of the rest of the body.  There are so many more things that we, as healthcare providers, have to learn about the central nervous system.  I look forward to being a part of the process of learning and developing new ways to help patients overcome CNS disorders.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "Has there ever been a time that you had a disagreement with a co-worker, and if so, how was it resolved?", "answers": ["Any time you work with someone else, there is a chance of having a disagreement about something at one time or another.  The interviewer knows this.  It's human nature for people to have their own opinions.  What is important to the interviewer in this question is whether or not you are willing to compromise and work through difficult situations with your co-workers.  Being unwilling to compromise or find alternative solutions to a dispute can affect everyone on the team, even if it is indirectly.  Sharing a personal experience is OK, but do not embellish it to 'be the hero.'", "\"I believe if we think about it, each of us could remember at least one disagreement with a friend or co-worker.  Although I consider myself to be pretty easy-going, I am also very passionate about my patients and the care that they receive.  I have been aware of disagreements between other co-workers, but really like to think of myself as more of a peacekeeper.  I feel like professional people should be able to discuss things logically and come to an agreement that is satisfactory for everyone involved.\"", "\"I think the most common disagreement between myself and others have involved our personal feelings about how healthcare should be carried out.  However, I have learned, as have most of the people that I have worked with, that while our opinions are important, plans of care are designated by strict guidelines and with the input of everyone on the care team as well as the patient.  Learning to respect those guidelines and patient wishes usually resolves issues that arise\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "Have you ever studied Canavan Disease?", "answers": ["Many times candidates for employment feel overwhelmed when they are asked about disorders that they are not very familiar with.  It is important to remember, interviewers don't ask questions to trick you.  Asking questions specific to a field of study lets the interviewer get to know you and what your strengths and weaknesses are.  This is helpful in placing you with the right team of co-workers so that you can all learn from one another and have a well-balanced team.  Share your knowledge and always feel free to ask questions if you are not sure.", "\"I have just recently changed the focus of my career to central nervous systems disorders.  I haven't learned about Canavan disease yet, but would love an opportunity to hear more about it.\"", "\"I have not studied Canavan Disease in depth, but I do know that it is a severe progressive genetic disorder of the central nervous system.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "Have you ever been involved with attempts to secure funding for medical research?", "answers": ["Most of the funding for medic research by private voluntary health organizations comes from individuals, but some comes from grants to those organizations (and so might be counted as foundation or government funding as well as spending by the private voluntary health organization).  If you have been involved in helping to write grant applications or soliciting private organizations to become a part of research funding, this could be considered an asset.  Share any experience you may have.", "\"I used to work for a company that operated mostly from money received from federal grants.  When I worked there, I was an under-study to the head grant-writer.  I have hoped to find placement with a company where I can do research but also offer my services in securing funding to further our research efforts.\"", "\"Yes, I have assisted with attempts to secure private funding for a few research projects.  I have found that the more specifically focused a research project is, the more easily private funding is secured.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "If you could travel anywhere in the world, where would you go?", "answers": ["Employers realize that there is life outside of work.  Getting to know employees/potential employees and what interests them gives employers an opportunity to develop a relationship with them.  Share what you like.  Have you been to a destination you'd like to return to?  Is there somewhere you've always dreamed of going?  This is also an opportunity for you to get to know the employer.  Ask questions to show your interest in building a relationship.", "\"Without a doubt, I would go to Italy!  I have always wanted to travel and Italy will be one of the first places I go to once I have time to go and really experience it!  Have you ever been to another country?\"", "\"When I was younger, I went on a mission trip to Brazil.  I have always wanted to return and spend time with the missionaries who are still there.  I came back with such an appreciation for the opportunities and conveniences that we have here.  What about you?  Have you ever traveled abroad?"]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "Company ABC values strong relationships among our staff, patients, and vendors.  Do you feel you have strong relationship building skills?", "answers": ["Building strong relationships is essential for success of any business.  The healthcare industry is no exception.  Share why you think you have good relationship building skills.", "\"I have often been complimented on my relationship building skills. I like to get to know people and ask them questions about themselves; I find it's a great and simple way to start building rapport with others. I consider myself to be a strong relationship builder and take pride in my 'people skills'. \"", "\"I do feel have a strong relationship building skills.  I believe being kind to others and showing a real interest in their opinions and"]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "Do you have any knowledge of Alexander Disease?", "answers": ["There are a number of rare neurological disorders and  Alexander Disease is among them.  It is one of a group of neurological conditions known as leukodystrophies disorders that are the result of abnormalities in myelin the white matter that protects nerve fibers in the brain.  Share any experience/knowledge you have of this disease with the interviewer.", "\"I do not have an in-depth knowledge of Alexander Disease.  I do know that it is a disorder that affects the myelin matter of the brain and that it is progressive and usually fatal.\"", "I have read some about Alexander Disease.  I know that it has an onset during the first two years of life. Usually there are both mental and physical developmental delays, followed by the loss of developmental milestones, an abnormal increase in head size, and seizures.  It progresses rapidly and almost always ends in death.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "Company ABC has a variety of researchers who work in different areas.  Have you ever worked in an environment in which your co-workers were from diverse backgrounds?", "answers": ["In an industry as large as healthcare, diversity among peers is inevitable.   To be successful, it is crucial to learn how to work with a diverse group of people.  Some people are intimidated when faced with learning new cultures and beliefs, but in the healthcare industry, it is crucial to provide effective care.  The interviewer wants to know that you are open to meeting and learning about new people and becoming an integral part of the team.  Be positive with your response.", "\"The diversity of specialty areas is something I love about the healthcare field.  I like the idea of being in a career that challenges me to learn and grow.  I believe we all have something that we can contribute to others and I like to embrace the diversity among those that I work with.\"", "\"The largest diverse group I worked with was probably when I did my clinical rotation at University Medical Center.  I was afforded the opportunity to meet people from different cultures, religions, and professional backgrounds.  It gave me an eye-opening experience of how many wonderful people there are!\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "The affected brain cells of people with Parkinson's Disease contain Lewy bodies.  Do you have any knowledge of what these are or how they may be connected to Parkinson's Disease?", "answers": ["Lewy bodies are deposits of the protein alpha-synuclein.  Researchers do not yet know exactly why Lewy bodies form or what role they play in the disease, although there is some speculation.  If you have heard of these, share what you have learned with the interviewer.  If you have not, it is OK to say so.  It is important to remember that when you are asked a question, if you do not know the answer, be honest and show an interest in learning.", "\"I have heard the term 'Lewy bodies,' but have not really been educated on what they are or what their possible role in Parkinson's disease is.  Diseases of the central nervous system are often so complex.  I really look forward to learning more.\"", "\"I have done a little studying on Parkinson's Disease and have read about Lewy bodies.  What I read stated that some research suggests that the cell's protein disposal system may fail in people with PD, causing proteins to build up to harmful levels and trigger cell death.  I also read a study that suggested that there has been evidence that clumps of protein that develop inside brain cells of people with PD may contribute to the death of neurons.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "What makes you think you will be successful at Company ABC?", "answers": ["Rather than just sharing how you have gone above and beyond expectations in the past, focus on how your qualities will help you to meet and exceed expectations with Company ABC.  Talk about your qualifications and skills that will help you to do this job well. If you can, match your strengths to the requirements outlined in the job description.", "\"I know I will be successful in this role because I have been working in this industry for five years with great training and mentorship. I have a solid understanding of X, Y, and Z (skills listed in the job description). Also, I have all of my updated certifications as outlined in your job description. I am excited about this next step in my career.\"", "\"I believe my success with Company ABC will come from having all of the hard skills that you are looking for, whether learned in school or gained through work experience.  I have every confidence that I can perform this job well and become an asset to Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "What is your understanding of  Huntington's disease?", "answers": ["Disorders of the central nervous system are often debilitating.  Huntington's disease is certainly no exception.  If you have ever worked with patients with this diagnosis or done research on the disease, share your experience.", "\"I have done some research on Huntington's disease in the past.  It's devastating because this is one of those diseases that is hereditary and has no cure.\"", "\"Huntington's disease is an incurable, hereditary brain disorder that causes damage to the brain cells. Early symptoms may include mood swings, clumsiness, and unusual behavior.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "Have you ever studied Central Pain Syndrome, and if so, what do you know about it?", "answers": ["Central pain syndrome is a neurological disorder caused by damage to the sensory pathways of the central nervous system.  It is a rare condition that can develop following a variety of conditions including stroke, multiple sclerosis, spinal cord injury, brain tumors, or iatrogenic damage to the central nervous system.  Share any knowledge you have about this disorder with the interviewer.", "\"Central Pain Syndrome is caused by damage to the nerve pathways of the CNS.  Common symptoms include pain and loss of sensation, usually in the face, arms and/or legs. Pain is often constant and can be mild, moderate, or severe in intensity.\"", "\"I know that with this syndrome the patient experiences almost constant pain of varying degrees, depending upon the underlying cause of the disorder and the area of the central nervous system affected. It can potentially disrupt an individual's daily routine. In severe cases, the pain can be agonizing and unrelenting and dramatically affect a person's quality of life.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "What are your thoughts regarding using stem cell transplants to treat degenerative disorders of the central nervous system?", "answers": ["Although many people are supportive of stem cell research, the idea of transplants is still a subject of controversy in many circles.   It is always wise to speak positively about a subject, even if it may be a controversial subject.  The old saying, 'you don't have to agree with progress for progress to happen' is especially true with medicine.", "\"I have to admit, I don't have a lot of experience with stem cell research.  With that in mind, I can't give an answer based on personal research.  However, I feel like anything that we can do to help improve someone's quality of life and provide hope is something we should do.\"", "\"I think the idea of using stem cells to help treat CNS disorders is exciting.  I've read some studies on stem cell transplants.  If Company ABC has any projects that are focused on stem cell research or transplant trials, I would love to see if you think I may be a good fit to join that team.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "What education would you provide to a patient with Bell's Palsy?", "answers": ["One of the primary responsibilities of healthcare providers is patient education.  Understanding disorders and being able to help patients understand them is important.  Approximately 1 in 5,000 people develop Bell's palsy each year. Although it is classed as a relatively rare condition, it is frightening to patients as it affects the nerves of the face.  Share any knowledge you have about Bell's Palsy with the interviewer.", "\"Any disorder that affects the nerves enough to leave a paralysis can be frightening.  I think one of the most important things is to assure the patient that Bell's Palsy usually resolves within a few months.  Also, as the facial nerve begins to recover, tightening and relaxing facial muscles can help strengthen them.  Instructing patients to do this often makes them feel like they can have an active role in their own recovery.\"", "\"Difficulty swallowing is one of the side effects of Bell's Palsy and it is important to educate patients on safety measures to prevent choking.  For instance, patients should chew food well and eat slowly. Choosing soft foods, such as yogurt can also help. If there is little or no feeling in the mouth it is easy for food to build up leading to decay or gum disease. Brushing and flossing can help prevent this.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "If a patient has a temporal lobe injury, what are some symptoms that you may expect to see manifest?", "answers": ["Understanding the different parts of the central nervous system and the normal functions of the CNS will help identify abnormal symptoms if/when they occur.  A brain injury will manifest with different symptoms depending on what part of the brain is injured.  Share your knowledge of the brain by explaining symptoms of a temporal lob injury.", "\"The temporal lobe is responsible for processing sensory input and assigning it emotional meaning.  If a patient experiences an injury of the temporal lobe, I would expect him to exhibit abnormal emotions to stimuli.  For example, a patient with this type of injury may laugh at something that would normally cause a person to cry or feel sadness.\"", "\"The temporal lobe also involved in laying down long-term memories, as well as housing some aspects of language perception.  A patient with a temporal lobe injury may manifest signs of difficulty understanding a conversation.  He may also be able to recall something that happened this morning (short-term), but not be able to recall something that happened last year (long-term).\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "Do you have an understanding of the difference between the peripheral nervous system and the central nervous system?", "answers": ["Although the two systems are interconnected, the peripheral nervous system is separate from the central nervous system.  There are a number of differences between the two systems and knowing those is essential if you plan to work with CNS research/medical care.  Share some differences between the peripheral and central nervous systems with the interviewer.", "\"I have always been interested in the differences between the peripheral and central nervous systems.  One major difference between the two involves regeneration of cells. Much of the peripheral nervous system has the ability to regenerate, but the central nervous system does not have this ability.\"", "\"The central nervous system includes the brain, spinal cord, and their associated nerves.  The peripheral nervous system is the nervous system outside of the brain or spinal cord.  The nerve cells of the central nervous system are shorter than those of the peripheral nervous system.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "Over 400,000 people in the United States have Multiple Sclerosis, and around 10,000 new cases are diagnosed each year.  Do you have any knowledge or experience working with this disease?", "answers": ["Diseases of the central nervous system, such as Multiple Sclerosis, are often debilitating.  Having an understanding of the different diseases and what possible signs of progression are is helpful for researchers to determine if new methods of treatment are effective.  The interviewer may ask you to explain your knowledge of specific diseases to see what area would be a better fit for you.  Sharing any knowledge or experience you have is a plus!", "\"I have had patients before who were diagnosed with multiple sclerosis.  Symptoms range from milder cases, in which there may be numbness in the limbs. Severe cases may involve paralysis or vision loss.\"", "\"I do have some knowledge of multiple sclerosis.  In the CNS, nerve fibers are surrounded by a myelin sheath, which protects them. Myelin also helps the nerves conduct electrical signals quickly and efficiently. In MS, the myelin sheath disappears in multiple areas, leaving a scar, or sclerosis.  There is no cure, but treatment can relieve symptoms and help the person manage their daily living.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "Alzheimer's disease is often said to be more difficult for family members to endure than the actual victims of the disease.  Do you know why this is said?", "answers": ["The Alzheimer's Association states that AD is the sixth leading cause of death in the United States. About one in three seniors die with AD or another form of dementia.  What is your knowledge of why some say that the family members seem to endure more difficulty than the victim?", "\"Alzheimer's is a sad disease, for sure.  My grandmother was diagnosed with the disease and I understand why some say that it is harder for the family to endure than the patient.  The patients do experience frustrations due to being forgetful, etc.  If a patient does not have another diagnosis that leads to death and Alzheimer's progresses to its last stage, the patient returns to what appears to be an infantile state of being.  They must be fed, clothed, and have no memory or understanding.  It is a very painful thing to experience when someone you care for has no memory of you or others that they loved.\"", "\"It is understandable why people say Alzheimer's is more difficult for family members.  I'm not sure if I would go so far as to say it is more difficult, but I can understand the thought behind it.  In the beginning, patients are afraid and frustrated because of memory loss which can lead to so many dangers (forgetting medicines, driving and becoming lost, etc.).  At later stages, though, more burden to provide care is placed on the family and the patient forgets more.  So, I can see why the statement is logical to many.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "Have you ever worked with patients who Childhood Integrative Disorder, and if so, what do you know about it?", "answers": ["Autism is a complex disorder of the central nervous system and the condition has a wide range of severity along its spectrum. Childhood Integrative Disorder is one disorder within the autism spectrum.  Share any knowledge you have of the disorder.", "\"I have studied some of the diseases on the autism spectrum.  Childhood disintegrative disorder is a rare condition characterized by late onset of developmental delays or severe and sudden reversals in language, social function, and motor skills.\"", "\"The information I have seen regarding the disorder  reports that it is characterized by at least two years of normal development, followed by loss of language, social skills, and motor skills before age ten.  It is my understanding that it is one of the most severe diagnoses within the autism spectrum.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "Company ABC is supportive of employees who want to further their education.  Have you ever considered going back to school and obtaining a higher/different degree?", "answers": ["There are people who choose a career and later return to school.  Some have the objective  to get a higher degree in the same field or to change careers altogether.  This question gives the interviewer an opportunity to know you and what your future plans may be.  In turn, your answer allows the interviewer the chance to see where you may fit within Company ABC now and in the future.  If you have thoughts of continuing your education, don't be afraid to share that with the interviewer.  Just remember to point out why you feel you would be an asset to Company ABC now.", "\"I have considered going back to college a few times, but at this point in my life, research is my passion.  I feel I am already in an industry that is important and growing.  I feel like, if I were to take any additional classes, I would want them to be something that would add value to the education and experience I have now.\"", "\"I love research and am comfortable where I am, at this point in my career.  I have considered in years to come, when I am older, I may transition slightly into the realm of education within medical research.  That way I can still do research and have some input, but I could also educate those who are coming into the field after me.  For now, though, I am very happy with what I am doing and really look forward to seeing where you think I will be the greatest asset at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "Are you familiar with the use of Deep Brain Stimulation to treat neurological disorders?", "answers": ["Deep brain stimulation involves implanting electrodes within certain areas of your brain. These electrodes produce electrical impulses that regulate abnormal impulses.  If you have any knowledge or experience with this treatment, share it with the interviewer.", "\"I have some knowledge of patients with Parkinson's disease who have been treated using deep brain stimulation.  In some of them, there was a noticeable reduction in the symptoms of tremo and walking problems caused by Parkinson's disease.\"", "\"Yes, I am familiar with deep brain stimulation.   My understanding is that it is a neurosurgical procedure that uses implanted electrodes and electrical stimulation to treat movement disorders associated with Parkinson's disease, essential tremor, dystonia and other neurological conditions.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "Why did you choose medical research as a career?", "answers": ["There are a multitude of career choices and the interviewer knows this.  Your answer to this question gives him another chance to get to know you.  Did something happen in your life that made you interested in medicine?  Are you one in a long line of people in your family who chose healthcare as a career?", "\"I grew up in a family full of nurses and knew I wanted to do some kind of work in healthcare.  I went to nursing school for a while, but decided I wanted to focus more on research.  I love the feeling of discovering new things and trying to apply that discovery to something that may help improve someone's life.\"", "\"I have always been inquisitive, especially with regard to the human body.  I especially love learning about the central nervous system because it is the control center of our bodies.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "Acute Disseminated Encepalomyelitis is often misdiagnosed.  Do you know what the symptoms are and what it may be mistakenly diagnosed as?", "answers": ["Misdiagnosis can be very frustrating for both patients and healthcare providers.  Being educated on different diseases/disorders helps to reduce the number of misdiagnosed patients and allow an appropriate plan of care to be implemented.  What is your understanding of this disease?  Remember, if you are not familiar, share what you do know and ask questions to show interest.", "\"Acute Disseminated Encepalomyelitis is a form of neurological disorder that causes a person to experience a short and sudden inflammatory attack in their spinal cord and brain.  The symptoms of ADEM are similar to those of multiple sclerosis. Because of this, the disorder is many times misdiagnosed as a severe attack of multiple sclerosis.\"", "\"Acute Disseminated Encepalomyelitis causes a person to experience an inflammatory response within their brain and spinal cord.  It has a sudden onset and lasts a short period.  It is sometimes misdiagnosed as a severe attack of MS, but there there are some key differences that can be recognized by a skilled neurologist. The initial symptoms of ADEM happen intensely and rapidly as a single and short-lived attack, although some children do experience recurrent episodes over a period of months.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "Autism has several disorders within its spectrum of diagnoses.  Can you share your knowledge of one of the disorders within the Autism spectrum?", "answers": ["There are several disorders associated with autism.   Until recent years, this diagnosis was not understood and much research is still be conducted to find ways of preventing and diagnosing the disease early.  What do you know about autism?", "\"Autism is a complex spectrum of disorders.  One of the diagnoses I am aware of is Asperger's Syndrome.   It is characterized by repetitive or restrictive patterns of thought and behavior. Unlike persons with other forms of autism, people who have Asperger's syndrome retain their early language skills.\"", "\"'High-functioning autism' isn't an official medical term or diagnosis, but an informal one some people use when they talk about people with an autism spectrum disorder who can speak, read, write, and handle basic life skills like eating and getting dressed. They may live independently, and are a lot like anyone else.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "Have you ever cared for patients with Sundowning Syndrome and what do you know about the syndrome?", "answers": ["Sundowning syndrome is a symptom that patients with Alzheimer's often experience.  Some scientists think that changes in the brain of someone with dementia might affect their inner 'body clock.' The area of the brain that signals when you're awake or asleep breaks down in people with Alzheimer's.   If you've ever cared for someone with Sundowning, share your experience with the interviewer.", "\"I am actually very familiar with Sundowning syndrome.  I worked for a while in an Alzheimer's care unit and we had several patients who experienced the syndrome.  Some of the triggers that we noticed included being too tired, depressed, or sleep disturbances.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "Medical research is often a demanding job.  Company ABC likes to encourage employees to have a healthy balance between their work and personal lives.  What are some things that you do to he", "answers": ["No matter what profession a person chooses, everyone needs some time to unwind and relax.  Psychologists today say that a healthy balance in life allows a person to recharge and refocus which can result in better productivity at work.  The interviewer simply wants to know what you do for you.  Maybe you have a favorite pass-time or hobby.  This is yet another way for the interviewer to get to know you as a person.", "\"One of my favorite pass-times is writing.  After a busy day at work, I like to journal or write articles for a blog that I author.  Both of these forms of writing allow me to release any feelings of frustration I may experience, especially after a stressful day or a difficult situation at work.   The writings in my journal are private and my way of 'letting it all out.'  The blog articles, on the other hand, are my way of using creative writing to share stories with my followers.\"", "\"I really enjoy working out at the gym and, I also take a kickboxing class twice weekly.   After a good workout or class, I always feel like I can rest better and wake up energized and ready for the next day.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "At Company ABC we understand that you may have obligations or responsibilities outside of work.  If you could choose a specific schedule or shift, what would that be?", "answers": ["Many people work more than one job or have a one parent home which requires them to have a flexible schedule.  Others simply prefer to work one shift rather than another.  Being up front with the interviewer about what schedule suits your preference could help prevent conflict later on.  It is easier to plan a schedule you can agree on than it is to fix problems that arise due to fear of being rejected.  Be honest and direct.", "\"I am not married and have no children at this time.  So, I am pretty flexible with my schedule.  If I had a choice, I would prefer the late shift, as I am a bit of a night owl.  However, I am  excited about the opportunity to become a part of this team and am willing to work where I'm needed.\"", "\"I am a single mom with two school-aged children.  Ideally, the day shift would be a better fit for me.  This would allow me to fulfill both my work and home responsibilities without a conflict.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "If you were the person responsible for hiring new employees at Company ABC, what qualities would you look for in a candidate, and do you think you possess those qualities?", "answers": ["There is more than one reason for asking this question.  First, the interviewer wants to know what qualities you think are important to perform this job.  Second, and most importantly, your answer will tell the interviewer if you hold yourself to the same standard as you do others.    If you want to see certain characteristics in your peers, you should be able to tell the interviewer with confidence that you possess those traits, as well.  This question is one that interviewers often use to distinguish sincerity on the part of the candidate.", "\"I believe that honesty is important no matter what job title a person holds.  I have found that being honest with people creates an atmosphere of mutual trust and respect.  Those qualities, I feel, are essential when building rapport with patients and co-workers.\"", "\"We all possess different qualities and that is what makes a great team.  If I were responsible for interviewing and hiring new employees,I would look for someone who has a genuine interest in the job and a desire to grow and learn.  None of us knows every thing there is to know about each disease or treatment.  Being willing to learn and share what we've learned with one another makes us a better team and benefits our patients and those who will need care in the future.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "At Company ABC, we have several research projects.  Some are long-term projects and others are short-term.   Do you anticipate any significant changes in your life within the next 1-2 years that would prevent you from working on a long-term project?", "answers": ["Knowing what goals you have and any changes you anticipate in your life will give the interviewer an opportunity to evaluate two things: 1. what positions are available that won't disrupt your plans and, 2.  are you interested in having a long-term relationship within the company?  Change is good and growth is encouraged, but if you anticipate a change, it is only fair that you are upfront with the interviewer.", "\"I recently became engaged.  Although we have not set a date yet, we have agreed to wait twelve months before the marriage.  My fiance' just passed the Bar exam here and has been offered an opportunity to join an existing law firm.  Presently, our plans are to stay where we are and build a career, not just work a job.  Also, we do not plan on having children for at least two years after our marriage.  We both feel that being able to become established in our careers and save for our future would be the responsible thing to do before starting a family.\"", "\"I have no plans that would prevent me from taking on a long-term project.  I realize Company ABC has several projects with different anticipated timelines.  I am excite about the possibility of becoming involved with any project where you feel I would be an asset.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+CNS", "question": "A very common neurologic disorder is migraines.  Have you ever experienced a migraine headache or cared for someone who has?", "answers": ["Migraine is a chronic neurological disease characterized by recurrent moderate to severe headaches often in association with a number of autonomic nervous system symptoms. Typically the headache affects one half of the head, is pulsating in nature, and lasts from 2 to 72 hours. Associated symptoms may include nausea, vomiting, and sensitivity to light, sound, or smell. The pain is generally made worse by physical activity.  What is your experience with these types of headaches?", "\"Unfortunately, I can say that I do know the pain of migraines.  When I was a teenager I experienced them often.  The pain can almost feel debilitating at times.  I now have a prescription medication that I take when I begin to experience symptoms and it has been effective in controlling them for me.\"", "\"I do have experience caring for patients with migraines.  One of my patients who experienced migraine headaches also reported seeing flashing lights, spots, and, once,  a temporary loss of vision.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "Are you familiar with Jacobsen syndrome?", "answers": ["Genome research is one of the most in depth areas of medical research.  There are a variety of different chromosomal abnormalities/syndromes and Jacobsen syndrome is one of the more rare.  If you have any knowledge regarding this syndrome, share it with the interviewer.", "\"I am familiar with the disorder, but have never directly cared for a patient with the syndrome.  It's my understanding that Jacobsen syndrome results from a loss of genetic material at the end of the long arm of chromosome 11.  It results in varying symptoms, but most individuals experience delayed development in motor skills and speech, learning difficulties, and some behavioral problems.\"", "\"Individuals with Jacobsen syndrome  are missing genetic material from the end of the long arm of chromosome 11 and have extra genetic material from another chromosome.   Characteristics include distinctive facial features; delayed development of motor skills and speech; and cognitive impairment.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "At Company ABC we understand that changes occur in individual's lives and we try to assign projects accordingly.  Do you anticipate any changes in your life within the next 12-24 months?", "answers": ["Knowing what goals you have and any changes you anticipate in your life will give the interviewer an opportunity to evaluate two things: 1. what positions are available that won't disrupt your plans and, 2.  are you interested in having a long-term relationship within the company?", "\"I recently became engaged.  Although we have not set a date yet, we have agreed to wait twelve months before the marriage.  My fiance' just passed the Bar exam here and has been offered an opportunity to join an existing law firm.  Presently, our plans are to stay where we are and build a career, not just work a job.  Also, we do not plan on having children for at least two years after our marriage.  We both feel that being able to become established in our careers and save for our future would be the responsible thing to do before starting a family.\"", "\"I do not anticipate any significant changes in my life that would disrupt any work assignments.  I have reached a point in my career where I can stay for the long-term.  I understand Company ABC has both long-term and short-term projects and I would be willing to work on either and work my way up to a longer term assignment.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "What do you know about cystic fibrosis?", "answers": ["Until late in the 20th century, few people with cystic fibrosis lived beyond childhood. Improvements in medical care have increased life expectancy by decades.  Share any knowledge you have of this disorder with the interviewer.", "\"Cystic fibrosis is an uncommon genetic disorder. It primarily affects the respiratory and digestive systems. Symptoms often include chronic cough, lung infections, and shortness of breath. Children with cystic fibrosis may also have trouble gaining weight and growing.\"", "\"Cystic fibrosis is a rare disease. The most affected group is Caucasians of northern European ancestry.  Since 2010, it has been mandatory for all doctors in the United States to screen newborns for cystic fibrosis. The test involves collecting a blood sample from a heel prick. A positive test can be followed up with a \"sweat test\" to measure the amount of salt in the sweat, which can help secure the diagnosis of cystic fibrosis.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "What do you know about Tay-Sachs disease?", "answers": ["When an interviewer asks a question like 'what do you know about.....' or 'are you familiar with.....,' he is not trying to trick you or make you feel put on the spot if you don't know the answer.  Although a research company such as Company ABC may deal specifically with genome research, there may be several research projects going on at once.  Knowing what areas you have the most knowledge in and what your strengths are will help the interviewer find a place that may be a better fit for your education and skill level.", "\"Tay-Sachs is inherited in an autosomal recessive pattern, which means both copies of the gene in each cell have mutations. The parents of an individual with an autosomal recessive condition each carry one copy of the mutated gene, but they typically do not show signs and symptoms of the condition.\"", "\"Tay-Sachs disease is a rare inherited disorder that progressively destroys nerve cells (neurons) in the brain and spinal cord.  Infants with Tay-Sachs typically appear normal until the age of 3 to 6 months, when their development slows and muscles used for movement weaken. Affected infants lose motor skills such as turning over, sitting, and crawling and develop an exaggerated startle reaction to loud noises. As the disease progresses, children with Tay-Sachs experience seizures, vision and hearing loss and intellectual disability.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "What is the difference in monosomy and trisomy?", "answers": ["Understanding the difference in the simplest terms is an essential foundation for building upon knowledge.  This is especially true where medical issues are being studied.  Share the difference in these types of disorders with the interviewer.", "\"When an individual is missing one of the chromosomes from a pair, the condition is called monosomy. When an individual has more than two chromosomes instead of a pair, the condition is called trisomy.\"", "\"Monosomy and trisomy are examples of numeric genetic disorders.  In monosomy, a person is missing one of the chromosomes from a pair.  In trisomy, he has more than two chromosomes  instead of the normal pair.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "Have you ever been involved with securing funds for medical research?", "answers": ["Most of the funding of medical research by private voluntary health organizations comes from individuals, but some comes from grants to those organizations (and so might be counted as foundation or government funding as well as spending by the private voluntary health organization).  If you have been involved in helping to write grant applications or soliciting private organizations to become a part of research funding, this could be considered an asset.  Share any experience you may have.", "\"I used to work for a company that operated mostly from money received from federal grants.  When I worked there, I was an under-study to the head grant-writer.  I have hoped to find placement with a company where I can do research but also offer my services in securing funding to further our research efforts.\"", "\"Yes, I have assisted with attempts to secure private funding for breast cancer research.  I have found that the more specifically focused a research project is, the more easily private funding is secured.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "Company ABC has researchers from various backgrounds and education levels.  What are your thoughts regarding diversity in the workplace?", "answers": ["Some people are intimidated when faced with learning new cultures and beliefs, but in the healthcare industry, it is crucial to provide effective care.  The interviewer wants to know that you are open to meeting and learning about new people and becoming an integral part of the team.  Be positive with your response.", "\"The largest diverse group I worked with was probably when I did my clinical rotation at University Medical Center.  I was afforded the opportunity to meet people from different cultures, religions, and professional backgrounds.  It gave me an eye-opening experience of how many wonderful people there are!\"", "\"I think diversity in the healthcare industry is essential.   I believe learning about and showing an appreciation for people from different walks of life only makes us stronger as we build upon the common bond of caring for others.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "Are you familiar with the physical characteristics of someone with Edwards Syndrome?", "answers": ["There are some characteristics that are seen in almost all patients with a genetic abnormality.  Others are specific to a certain syndrome/disorder.  If genetic testing was not performed before the birth of a child, or no reason to suspect a genetic abnormality,  medical advice may not be sought until physical characteristics or mental delays begin to appear.  Some of the characteristics found with Edwards Syndrome are as follows:", "\"Patients with Edwards syndrome may exhibit some symptoms including clenched hands, feet with a rounded bottom, mental deficiency, underdeveloped fingernails, and an unusually shaped chest.\"", "\"I have not studied Edwards Syndrome in depth.  However, if I remember correctly, a few of the significant signs are fingernails that are not well developed and feet that appear rounded on the bottom.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "Can you tell me two types of Trisomy 16?", "answers": ["Trisomy 16 is a chromosomal abnormality in which there are 3 copies of chromosome 16 rather than two. It is the most common trisomy leading to miscarriage and the second most common chromosomal cause of it, closely following X-chromosome monosomy.  While interviewers do not expect you to know the details of every chromosomal abnormality, understanding some of them and being able to describe characteristics is favorable in an interview.", "\" Full Trisomy 16 occurs when an individual has three copies of chromosome 16 instead of the usual two and Mosaic Trisomy 16 is a rare disorder in which an extra chromosome 16 is present in some cells, but not all.\"", "\"I am familiar with Mosaic Trisomy 16and Full Trisomy 16.  Mosaic trisomy 16  is rare and shows patients having an extra chromosome 16 is present in only some cells.  Full Trisomy 16 which is caused by someone having three copies of chromosome 16 instead of the usual two and is the most common chromosomal cause of miscarriage during the pregnancy's first trimester.  Some common symptoms include intrauterine growth retardation and congenital heart defects.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "What can you tell me about Robertsonian translocation?", "answers": ["Many genetic abnormalities present problems for the patient with the abnormal genes.  Some, however, like those with Robertsonian translocation may not experience issues, but may pass the gene on to their children.  Share your knowledge with the interviewer.", "\"In most cases, there are no symptoms or visible signs of a Robertsonian translocation. Depending on where in the DNA the translocation occurs, it's very likely that a patient won't experience any side effects of the DNA chain being abnormal.  Since chromosomes come in pairs, a patient can have a Robertsonian translocation that disrupts the DNA strand, but leaves the patient with all of the genetic information needed for r cells to multiply correctly. That's why many people with this condition go through life without ever knowing that they have it.\"", "\"Many people with Robertsonian translocation go through life without ever knowing that they have it. However, even if a Robertsonian translocation doesn't present a problem within a patient's DNA, she may become a carrier of the translocation. This means there's a possibility of passing missing or extra DNA on to their children.   Multiple miscarriages, difficulty getting pregnant, and pregnancies in which the fetus develops a trisomy or other genetic abnormality could be a sign that someone has this translocation.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "What made you choose a career in genome research?", "answers": ["This is a simple question that will speak volumes to the interviewer.  With so many career choices available, the interviewer is curious to know what made you choose this profession.  If you experienced something in your past that made you appreciate a healthcare provider, share that experience.  This is a perfect opportunity for the interviewer to know you on a personal level.\n\n\"I have always had an interest in medicine and genetics is fascinating to me.  It just seemed like a logical choice for me to begin a career in genome research.\"", "\"I have always had an interest in medicine and genetics is fascinating to me.  It just seemed like a logical choice for me to begin a career in genome research.\"", "\"One of my cousins who is several years younger than me was born with genetic abnormalities.  When I was a kid I always said I was going to 'grow up and find a way to fix him.'  Even though I couldn't do that, I always had a desire to study genetics and be a part of the development of new ways to predict and treat genetic abnormalities.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "What do you know abouthe Ehlers-Danlos Syndromes?", "answers": ["The Ehlers-Danlos syndromes are a group of connective tissue disorders that can be inherited and are varied both in how they affect the body and in their genetic causes.  Share any knowledge or experience you have with the disorders with the interviewer.", "\"Ehlers-Danlos syndromes are connective tissue disorders.  Their genetic causes and the ways they affect the body vary. They are generally characterized by joint hypermobility, skin hyperextensibility, and tissue fragility.\"", "\"While I don't have a lot of in depth experience studying Ehlers-Danlos syndromes, I do know some of the symptoms.  For instance, affected individuals may have loose/unstable joints which are prone to frequent dislocations and/or subluxations, joint pain; hyperextensible joints, and early onset of osteoarthritis.  They may also experience fragile skin that tears or bruises easily,severe scarring, slow and poor wound healing.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "Are you familiar with patient teaching regarding Sickle Cell Anemia?", "answers": ["Although many researchers pass information on to other healthcare providers who are responsible for patient education, it is still important to be able to explain a disorder.  The interviewer wants to know what you would tell someone if you were the one providing patient education on Sickle Cell Disease.  Share your knowledge.", "\"Sickle Cell Disease (SCD) is a group of inherited red blood cell disorders. Healthy red blood cells are round, and they move through small blood vessels to carry oxygen to all parts of the body. In someone who has SCD, the red blood cells become hard and sticky and look like a C-shaped farm tool called a 'sickle.'  When they travel through small blood vessels, they get stuck and clog the blood flow. This can cause pain and other serious problems such infection.\"", "\"Sickle cell anemia is a disease in which the body produces abnormally shaped red blood cells that have a crescent or sickle shape. These cells do not last as long as normal, round, red blood cells, which leads to anemia (low number of red blood cells). The sickle cells also get stuck in blood vessels, blocking blood flow.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "What is your knowledge regarding the connection between maternal age and genetic abnormalities?", "answers": ["There is much speculation as to the causes of genetic abnormalities and maternal age is one thing that seems to be a link in some cases.    Do you have any knowledge/experience with information to support this?", "\"Women are born with all the eggs they will ever have. Some researchers believe that errors can crop up in the eggs' genetic material as they age which leads to genetic abnormalities in babies born to older mothers.\"", "\"I have read and done some studies on genetic abnormalities with relation to parental age.  Because men produce new sperm throughout their lives, paternal age does not increase risk of chromosome abnormalities. Older women, however,  are considered to be at higher risk of giving birth to babies with chromosome abnormalities than younger women.  This is thought to be so because women are born with all the eggs they will have for their lifetime and, as those eggs age, the genetic material within the eggs is thought to change.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "Do you have any experience/knowledge about \"Cat Cry Syndrome\"?", "answers": ["When interviewing for genome research positions, the interviewer may ask you about different genetic disorders.  Remember, no one is expected to know every diagnosis or have a complete understanding of every disorder.  If you have heard of a syndrome or disorder that the interviewer asks about, share what you know.  If you are asked about something that you have no experience with, say so and show an interest in learning.", "\"I have never learned about Cat Cry Syndrome.  There are so many genetic abnormalities and I am so intrigued by them.  The opportunities to be exposed to more education with genome research is  why I chose to apply for employment here at Company ABC.\"", "\"I have heard of Cat Cry Syndrome.   I believe the clinical name is Cri du Chat syndrome and it is caused by  missing a piece of chromosome 5.  Symptoms include a high-pitched cry that sounds like a cat (hence the name Cat Cry Syndrome), downward slant of the eyes, partial webbing of fingers or toes, and slow or incomplete development of motor skills.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "Being a healthcare provider is rewarding, but can also be very stressful at times.  Can you share a situation that was difficult for you and how you worked through it?", "answers": ["The interviewer recognizes that, while being a healthcare provider has its benefits, it can often be trying at times.  This question gives you the chance to show how your vulnerability meets your strengths.  Having balance between the two is a sought-after characteristic of healthcare providers.  Being willing to open up to the interviewer about a situation that was emotional for you and how you were able to cope will show him what can be expected of you when you are faced with a difficult situation in the future.", "\"I agree that being a healthcare provider has its stressful situations.  One case that I will never forget occurred when I worked pediatrics.  We had a four year old child that was admitted due to having seizures.  After further testing, it was discovered that the child had a brain tumor.   The tumor was very advanced and she lost her life because of it.  That time was very emotional for everyone on the care team.  Fortunately, we had a good team leader who gave us an opportunity to talk with her and one another about the overwhelming grief that we felt.  I have found that talking through emotions is a great way to work through any unresolved grief.\"", "\"I believe we all experience stress from time to time.  Whether it is work related or something outside of work, if I begin to feel stressed or overwhelmed, I try to take a step back from whatever I am doing and refocus.  For me, making lists of things that need to be accomplished during the day often helps me to not become too stressed.  It keeps me on task and knowing what to expect next.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "What do you know about Charcot-Marie-Tooth disease", "answers": ["Charcot-Marie-Tooth disease is an inherited, genetic condition. It occurs when there are mutations in the genes that affect the nerves in your feet, legs, hands and arms.  Researching common types of genetic abnormalities and being able to discuss them with the interviewer shows that you have a genuine interest in learning.  Remember, you are not expected to know everything.  Share the knowledge you do have and always show an attitude of interest in learning.", "\"Charcot-Marie-Tooth disease is a group of inherited disorders that cause nerve damage. The damage occurs mostly in the arms and legs. Charcot-Marie-Tooth is also called hereditary motor and sensory neuropathy.\"", "\"Charcot-Marie-Tooth disease results in smaller, weaker muscles.  Some patients experience loss of sensation and muscle contractions, and difficulty walking. Foot deformities such as hammertoes and high arches are also common.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "If you were the person responsible for hiring new employees, what qualities would you be looking for during the interview?  Do you feel that you display those qualities yourself?", "answers": ["There is more than one reason for asking this question.  First, the interviewer wants to know what qualities you think are important to perform this job.  Second, and most importantly, your answer will tell the interviewer if you hold yourself to the same standard as you do others.    If you want to see certain characteristics in your peers, you should be able to tell the interviewer with confidence that you possess those traits, as well.  This question is one that interviewers often use to distinguish sincerity on the part of the candidate.", "\"I believe that honesty is important no matter what job title a person holds.  I have found that being honest with people creates an atmosphere of mutual trust and respect.  Those qualities, I feel, are essential when building rapport with patients and co-workers.\"", "\"Having worked in human resources before, I know that each interviewer looks for different things.  I always looked for someone who had a genuine interest in learning and in being a team player.  Although many positions require independent work, at the end of the day, we all have the same goals and should be able to work well with one another.  I believe I have those qualities and look forward to proving that if I am offered a position here at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "How would you describe \"chromosomal translocation\" to someone who is not a medical professional?", "answers": ["Not everyone understands medical terminology and definitions.  At times, information has to be explained in a way that someone without medical training can understand (parents, children, etc.)  The interviewer wants to know that you are able to communicate effectively with people who may not have the same medical training as you.", "\"After working in the medical field for so long, I have to remind myself sometimes that not everyone understands our language.  If I were to describe chromosomal translocation to a non-medical person, I would tell them, 'Inside of each of your cells are thread-like structures made up of parts called chromosomes. These tightly wound threads are what people mean when they refer to your DNA. It's a blueprint for cell growth that makes every cell in your body unique to you.  It's like a puzzle.  A chromosomal translocation is the term used to describe when two parts of the puzzle thread join in a way that doesn't fit.'\"", "\"If I had to explain chromosomal translocation to someone I would use the idea of a jigsaw puzzle.  I would probably say, 'Imagine a jigsaw puzzle that snaps together to create a spiral staircase. That's how your DNA is structured. Each piece of your DNA strand belongs in a specific place, ensuring that your cells can split apart and multiply with your DNA imprinted inside each one.  A chromosomal translocation is the word we use to describe when two parts of the puzzle join, but don't fit the puzzle.  This results in an abnormality.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "Are you familiar with the use of hematopoietic stem cell transplantation?", "answers": ["Hematopoietic stem cell transplantation was first used as a treatment for some types of cancer but is now widely used as a therapy for various autoimmune diseases.  If you have any knowledge/experience with this type of therapy, share it with the interviewer.", "\"I have never worked on any project that involved hematopoetic stem cell transplantation, but it is my understanding that it involves the IV infusion of stem cells to reestablish hematopoietic function in patients whose bone marrow or immune system is damaged or defective.\"", "\"I did some studies on the blood's role in wellness and disease processes.  Part of that research involved studying the use of hematopoietic stem cell transplants (HSCT).  Although it can be used to treat cancer, HSCT is not considered to be an oncological procedure, but is still referred to as a  hematological process.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "Can you think of some possible drawbacks to using knockout mice?", "answers": ["A knockout mouse is a laboratory mouse in which researchers have inactivated, or 'knocked out,' an existing gene by replacing it or disrupting it with an artificial piece of DNA. The loss of gene activity often causes changes in a mouse's phenotype, which includes appearance, behavior and other observable physical and biochemical characteristics.  The interviewer knows what knockout mice are used for, but can you think of a reason that their use may not be beneficial?", "\"I understand the importance of being able to test using laboratory mice.   However, I can also see where there may be some drawbacks.  For instance, about 15 percent of gene knockouts are developmentally lethal, which means that the genetically altered embryos cannot grow into adult mice.  This lack of adult mice limits studies to embryonic development.  In some instances, the gene may serve a different function in adults than in developing embryos.\"", "\"Knocking out a gene may fail to produce an observable change in a mouse or may produce different characteristics from those observed in humans who experience the same inactivated gene. For example, mutations in the p53 gene are associated with more than half of human cancers and often lead to tumors in a particular set of tissues. However, when the p53 gene is knocked out in mice, the animals develop tumors in a different array of tissues.  Although there may be some drawbacks, I still feel the benefits of using knockout mice for testing are still profound.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "Can you tell me how many chromosomes a human has and any fact you know about them?", "answers": ["Chromosomes carry genetic information in the form of genes.  A human inherits a set  number of chromosomes from his biological mother and from his biological father.  Explain your knowledge of chromosomes to the interviewer.", "\"The typical number of chromosomes in a human cell is 46,  23 pairs.  These 23 pairs hold an estimated total of 20,000 to 25,000 genes. One set of 23 chromosomes is inherited from the biological mother (from the egg), and the other set is inherited from the biological father (from the sperm).\"", "\"Chromosomes are inherited from biological parents.  23 pairs are inherited from each parent . The first 22 pairs are called autosomes. The 23rd pair is called the sex chromosomes which determine an individual's sex.  Females have two X chromosomes (XX), and males have an X and a Y chromosome (XY).\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "Do you know the differences in Type 1 and Type 2 Myotonic Dystrophy?", "answers": ["Myotonic dystrophy is part of a group of inherited disorders called muscular dystrophies. It is the most common form of muscular dystrophy that begins in adulthood.  While their symptoms may overlap, Types 1 and 2 of myotonic dystrophy do have some distinct characteristics.", "\"Individuals with myotonic dystrophy experience muscle wasting/weakness.  Type 1 particularly affects the lower legs, hands, neck, and face. Muscle weakness in type 2 primarily involves the muscles of the neck, shoulders, elbows, and hips.\"", "\"Myotonic dystrophy type 1 is caused by mutations in the DMPK gene, while type 2 results from mutations in the CNBP gene.   Type 1 patients usually show weakness in their face, neck, hands and/or legs.  Type 2 patients experience weakness of the shoulders, elbows, hips, and neck.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "What makes you think you will be successful at Company ABC?", "answers": ["Rather than just sharing how you have gone above and beyond expectations in the past, focus on how your qualities will help you to meet and exceed expectations with Company ABC. Discuss the reasons why will you be great at this job. Talk about your qualifications and skills that will help you to do this job well. If you can, match your strengths to the requirements outlined in the job description.", "\"I know I will be successful in this role because I have been working in this industry for five years with great training and mentorship. I have a solid understanding of X, Y, and Z (skills listed in the job description). Also, I have all of my updated certifications as outlined in your job description. I am well-prepared for this next step in my career.\"", "\"I believe my success with Company ABC will come from having all of the hard skills that you are looking for, whether learned in school or gained through work experience.  I know all the key players in this region and stay informed of best practices.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "Do you know of a genetic disorder that primarily affects male individuals?", "answers": ["Females have two X chromosomes and males only have one.  This fact, along with the occurrence of what geneticists call mosaicism, may  explain why women are less susceptible than men to certain genetic diseases.  While some women may have a mostly male diagnosed disorder, there are some that are primarily diagnosed in males.  Share any information you have.", "\"One predominately  male diagnosed genetic disorder I can think of is Duchenne muscular dystrophy.  It occurs primarily in males, though in rare cases may affect females.   It is a progressive form of muscular dystrophy that causes weakness and loss  of skeletal and heart muscles.\"", "\"Mucopolysaccharidosis type II (MPS II), also known as Hunter syndrome, is a condition that affects many different parts of the body and occurs almost exclusively in males. It is a progressively debilitating disorder.  The rate of progression varies among affected individuals.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "What can you tell me about the three types of genetic disorders?", "answers": ["Understanding the differences in types of disorders is important in classifying  abnormalities and seeking treatment.    If you understand the differences in genetic disorder types, share it with the interviewer.  Also, remember, not everyone who applies to work in research has the same amount of experience.  The interviewer knows this.  Share what you know and always show an interest to learn more.", "\"While I am just beginning to learn genetic research, I know that there are different types of genetic disorders.  There are single-gene disorders, where a mutation affects one gene. \n Chromosomal disorders, where chromosomes or parts of chromosomes are missing or changed, and Complex disorders, where there are mutations in two or more genes.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "Many people have voiced different opinions regarding embryonic stem cell transplants.  What is your understanding of embryonic stem cell transplants and do you have thoughts about why some people are opposed to this?", "answers": ["There are various reasons that people voice opposition to stem cell research.  Even if you have never worked with embryonic stem cell research, you can share your thoughts about why some people may be opposed.", "\"I believe that the majority of people who oppose embryonic stem cell research/transplants do so because they don't have a clear understanding of what type of cells are used and the benefits that the research can accomplish.  Embryonic stem cells are derived from the inner cells of human blastocysts, which occur 5-10 days after fertilization, but before implantation into the uterus.  I honestly believe if those in opposition were educated to understand that embryonic stem cells are not taken from a living fetus they would be  more supportive.\"", "\"I believe there are many reasons that people oppose stem cell research.  When the word 'embryonic' is used, the majority of the population relates this to an unborn child.  If people can understand that a pregnancy has not been achieved at the time these cells are harvested and can know that cloning for reproductive purposes in human beings is not legal, they would be more open to the idea of this type of research.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "What makes  Early Onset Familial Alzheimer's disease different from a \"normal\" diagnosis of Alzheimer's ?", "answers": ["Alzheimer disease (AD) is characterized by adult-onset progressive dementia associated with cerebral cortical atrophy, beta-amyloid plaque formation, and intraneuronal neurofibrillary tangles. AD typically begins with subtle memory failure that becomes more severe and is eventually incapacitating.  While Early Onset Familial Alzheimer's displays the same characteristics, there are a few things that contribute to this diagnosis.", "\"Familial Alzheimer's Disease (FAD) characterizes families that have more than one member with AD and usually implies multiple affected persons in more than one generation. Early-onset FAD (EOFAD) refers to families in which onset is consistently before age of 65 years and often before age 55 years.\"", "Early Onset Familial Alzheimer's Disease (EOFAD)  is inherited in an autosomal dominant manner. Most individuals with EOFAD had an affected parent.  Each child of an individual with EOFAD has a 50% chance of inheriting the pathogenic variant and developing EOFAD.  Prenatal testing for pregnancies at increased risk for is possible if the pathogenic variant in the family is known.  Prenatal testing for adult-onset disorders, however,  is uncommon.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "Do you know what some of the characteristic signs of Marfan Syndrome are?", "answers": ["Marfan syndrome is a genetic disease of connective tissues. It is caused by a defect, or mutation, in the gene that determines the structure of fibrillin-1, a protein that is an important part of connective tissue.  The severity of Marfan syndrome varies from one individual to another and it typically progresses over time.  Share some of the common characteristics of the syndrome.", "\"Marfan syndrome can cause dislocation of the lens of the eye and detachment of the retina, resulting in vision loss in patients with the condition.  The syndrome affects the skeleton, eyes, heart and blood vessels, nervous system, skin, and respiratory system.\"", "\"A tall, slender build is characteristic of Marfan syndrome.  Mitral valve prolapse is also common in patients with the syndrome.  Additionally, abnormal aortic dilationcan be a serious manifestation of Marfan syndrome.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+Genome", "question": "Can you recall a time that you may have had a disagreement with a boss or co-worker, and if so, how was it resolved?", "answers": ["Any time you work with someone else, there is a chance of having a disagreement about something at one time or another.  The interviewer knows this.  It's human nature for people to have their own opinions.  What is important to the interviewer in this question is whether or not you are willing to compromise and work through difficult situations with your co-workers.  Being unwilling to compromise or find alternative solutions to a dispute can affect everyone on the team, even if it is indirectly.  Sharing a personal experience is OK, but do not embellish it to 'be the hero.'", "\"I believe if we think about it, each of us could remember at least one disagreement with a friend or co-worker.  Although I consider myself to be pretty easy-going, I am also very passionate about my patients and the care that they receive.  I have been aware of disagreements between other co-workers, but really like to think of myself as more of a peacekeeper.  I feel like professional people should be able to discuss things logically and come to an agreement that is satisfactory for everyone involved.\"", "\"I am sure there have been times when I have had a difference of opinion with a co-worker or boss.  However, I don't recall any time that there has been an incidence that could not be amicably resolved.  I have found that in environments where the work is critical, such as the medical field, it can be easy for peers to get stressed.  I have simply tried to remember to treat others the way I want to be treated and understand that just because someone is having a bad day it doesn't have to affect me negatively.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "Do you have an understanding of 'HIV reservoir'?", "answers": ["When it was first shown that triple combinations of antiretroviral (ART) drugs could suppress HIV replication, there were hopes that long-term ART would eventually lead to the clearance of all HIV-infected cells from the body. However, scientists discovered that HIV persists in an inactive, latent form in certain immune system cells.  They discovered that some of these cells can become active when ART is interrupted. The latent HIV that persists despite ART is described as the HIV reservoir, and it is considered the major barrier to achieving a cure.  Researchers seeking to find a cure for HIV are vigorously trying to discover the cause of these latent cells becoming active after such a long time of inactivity.  Share any knowledge you have regarding HIV reservoir.", "\"I followed a case study of a patient who had been diagnosed with HIV.  He participated in ART therapy faithfully for a few years and the progression of HIV appeared to slow.  However, he experienced some emotional issues and stopped the ART therapy.  He unfortunately experienced a rapid decline as the latent memory CD4 T cells became active again.\"", "\"When I first began to study HIV therapy, the researcher I worked with was doing a study on latent memory CD4 T cells.  I was able to follow his research and study the comparisons of patients who participated in aggressive ART therapy and those who stopped the therapy and experienced the effects of those cells becoming active again.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "Company ABC recognizes the importance of having a healthy work/life balance.  What are some things you enjoy doing in your time away from work?", "answers": ["No matter what profession a person chooses, everyone needs some time to unwind and relax.  Psychologists today say that a healthy balance in life allows a person to recharge and refocus which can result in better productivity at work.  The interviewer simply wants to know what you do for you.  Maybe you have a favorite pass-time or hobby.  This is yet another way for the interviewer to get to know you as a person.", "\"I really enjoy working out at the gym and, I also take a kickboxing class twice weekly.   After a good workout or class, I always feel like I can rest better and wake up energized and ready for the next day.\"", "\"One of my favorite pass-times is writing.  After a busy day at work, I like to journal or write articles for a blog that I author.  Both of these forms of writing allow me to release any feelings of frustration I may experience, especially after a stressful day or a difficult situation at work.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "Can you recall a time that you had a disagreement with a coworker, and if so, how was it resolved?", "answers": ["Any time you work with someone else, there is a chance of having a disagreement about something at one time or another.  The interviewer knows this.  It's human nature for people to have their own opinions.  What is important to the interviewer in this question is whether or not you are willing to compromise and work through difficult situations with your co-workers.  Being unwilling to compromise or find alternative solutions to a dispute can affect everyone on the team, even if it is indirectly.  Sharing a personal experience is OK, but do not embellish it to 'be the hero.'", "\"I believe if we think about it, each of us could remember at least one disagreement with a friend or co-worker.  Although I consider myself to be pretty easy-going, I am also very passionate about my patients and the care that they receive.  I have been aware of disagreements between other co-workers, but really like to think of myself as more of a peacekeeper.  I feel like professional people should be able to discuss things logically and come to an agreement that is satisfactory for everyone involved.\"", "\"I think the most common disagreement between myself and others have involved our personal feelings about how healthcare should be carried out.  However, I have learned, as have most of the people that I have worked with, that while our opinions are important, plans of care are designated by strict guidelines and with the input of everyone on the care team as well as the patient.  Learning to respect those guidelines and patient wishes usually resolves issues that arise\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "Are there any questions you would like to ask about Company ABC?", "answers": ["Although the interviewer has given you an opportunity to ask questions, be careful.  Never ask salary, perks, leave, etc.  Try to ask more questions about the company to show that you have an interest in making a contribution to it.", "\"I think you have been very clear with your explanations on how Company ABC is organized and what goals you are looking to achieve.  I suppose the main question for me is, do you have a project or specialty area where you think I can be an asset to Company ABC?\"", "\"I feel very informed by our conversation thus far.  Moving forward, I'd be interested to know which of of your projects that you feel could benefit by adding a new researcher, and whether you feel my education and skills would be a good fit here.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "Are you familiar with the \"reservoir limiting\" approach to treating HIV?", "answers": ["When you are a candidate for employment and are asked about familiarity with something specific, in this case 'reservoir limiting,' the interviewer does not expect you to give a long explanation.  If you are familiar, show your knowledge by talking about the main points of the subject.  If you are not, you may be able to use some of the words in the question to ask a question of the interviewer.", "\"Although I am not well versed in the approach of reservoir limiting, I understand that there are many approaches that focus on limiting the inactive latent cells.  I would love to hear more about reservoir limiting.\"", "\"Yes, I am familiar with this approach.  The idea behind the reservoir limiting is that using ART (or other interventions) as soon as possible after the acquisition of HIV infection may help to limit the size of the HIV reservoir which means there will be fewer, if any, inactive latent cells that could risk becoming active later.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "Have you ever been involved with attempts to secure funding for HIV research", "answers": ["Most of the funding of medical research by private voluntary health organizations comes from individuals, but some comes from grants to those organizations (and so might be counted as foundation or government funding as well as spending by the private voluntary health organization).  If you have been involved in helping to write grant applications or soliciting private organizations to become a part of research funding, this could be considered an asset.  Share any experience you may have.", "\"I used to work for a company that operated mostly from money received from federal grants.  When I worked there, I was an under-study to the head grant-writer.  I have hoped to find placement with a company where I can do research but also offer my services in securing funding to further our research efforts.\"", "\"Yes, I have assisted with attempts to secure private funding for breast cancer research.  I have found that the more specifically focused a research project is, the more easily private funding is secured.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "Have you ever considered getting a specialty certification, a higher degree, or transitioning to a new career path?", "answers": ["There are people who choose a career and later return to school.  Some have the objective  to get a higher degree in the same field or to change careers altogether.  This question gives the interviewer an opportunity to know you and what your future plans may be.  In turn, your answer allows the interviewer the chance to see where you may fit within Company ABC now and in the future.  If you have thoughts of continuing your education, don't be afraid to share that with the interviewer.  Just remember to point out why you feel you would be an asset to Company ABC now.", "\"I have considered going back to college a few times, but at this point in my life, research is my passion.  I feel I am already in an industry that is important and growing.  I feel like, if I were to take any additional classes, I would want them to be something that would add value to the education and experience I have now.\"", "\"I love research and am comfortable where I am, at this point in my career.  I have considered in years to come, when I am older, I may transition slightly into the realm of education within medical research.  That way I can still do research and have some input, but I could also educate those who are coming into the field after me.  For now, though, I am very happy with what I am doing and really look forward to seeing where you think I will be the greatest asset at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "Many research studies aim to recruit patients to participate in trials focused on depleting the HIV reservoir.  Are you familiar with any such trials?", "answers": ["HIV medicines reduce the amount of HIV in the body (the viral load) by preventing the virus from multiplying.  A latent HIV reservoir is a group of immune cells in the body that are infected with HIV but are not actively producing new HIV.  Many studies have shown that starting ART as soon as possible after HIV infection occurs greatly limits the size of the HIV reservoir that is formed.  Because of this finding, researchers are now hopeful that there may be a way to deplete the HIV reservoir completely which would mean there would be no latent cells; no latent cells means no new growth of infection.  If you have knowledge of these trials, share it.  If you do not, express an interest in learning.", "\"I have studied some about the effects of early ART on the HIV reservoir.  These trials sounds like an exciting next step in finding a cure.  I would love to hear more and be a part of the study if there is an open opportunity.\"", "\"I have heard about some of these trials but have not yet had a chance to follow any of them personally.  With what I do know about how the HIV reservoir is created and the chances of latent cells becoming active again, I would be interested in delving deeper into the subject of reservoir depletion and assist with one of these trials.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "If you could choose a research area other than HIV research, what would your next preference be?", "answers": ["Sharing your interests with the interviewer will give him a chance to offer you opportunities in a different area if an immediate position in HIV research is not available.  Also, having broader interests implies to the interviewer that you want to learn.  Share your interests and why they are appealing to you.", "\"I love HIV research, but I also have an interest in chromosomal abnormalities.  If I were to choose a second option of study, I believe I would like to focus on something related to these disorders.\"", "\"I understand that Company ABC has several areas of research.  While HIV research has been my first choice, I am not opposed to 'spreading my wings' and learning to navigate through another area.  If I were to have a second choice, I believe I would choose stem cell research.  I believe there is so  much more to learn about the benefits of stem cell use and would love to have a chance to be a part of that.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "It is often said that researchers are 'married to their work.'  Why do you think this may be so?", "answers": ["While not everyone who works in research is constantly on the go, many do work long hours.  Although this could easily be said of people who work in different career fields, the interviewer wants to know why you think this is a trait of some researchers.  If you understand the 'married to your work' phrase from personal experience, explain why.", "\"I definitely understand how some people can say that.  For me, if I am focused on a task, I don't like to stop working until I complete it.  Research is like a never-ending task.  I am especially likely to work longer hours if I have discovered something that shows promise or progress.\"", "\"I think people can say that about any number of professions.  Careers that require individual attention, like research, are often labeled as 'the spouse' or the employee is said to be 'married to his work.'\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "What do you feel is one of the most challenging obstacles to HIV research?", "answers": ["There are many challenges involved with HIV research.  The interviewer is asking your opinion.  So, don't feel like you have to give an elaborate, 'medically correct' answer.  What are your thoughts?\n\n\"I think one of the most challenging things with regard to HIV research is that, in order to determine that treatment is effective, patients must be followed for long periods of time.  It is challenging because once patients begin to feel better, they don't want to have to see physicians all the time.\"", "\"I think one of the most challenging things with regard to HIV research is that, in order to determine that treatment is effective, patients must be followed for long periods of time.  It is challenging because once patients begin to feel better, they don't want to have to see physicians all the time.\"", "\"One of the things that is very challenging or frustrating to me is when babies born to HIV+ mothers are not given their medications as prescribed.  I believe we would be able to track the effects of treatments and prognosis more efficiently if these children were given their medications from birth, as they should, and possibly find a way to stop the progression of the disease.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "Company ABC has researchers who work within a team and others who work independently before collaborating with the team.  Would you prefer to work within a group or on an individual project?", "answers": ["Because research projects may have people working on different things at the same time, there are often groups that work together while another researcher works independently.  Then at certain points, everyone shares information/findings.  This is one opportunity for you to say your preference without seeming overbearing.  Share why you prefer one option over the other.", "\"I tend to be a quiet, focus-driven person.  Because of that, I have found that I enjoy independent projects.  Nevertheless, I would not decline any offer with Company ABC, as I am very excited to see what opportunities are available here.\"", "\"I love working within a team.  I always feel like when we can work together and share ideas it challenges us each to grow and learn.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "Are you familiar with  the CCR5-32 mutation and its possible role in preventing or curing HIV?", "answers": ["CCR5-32 mutation is a rare genetic mutation that affects whether the receptor CCR5 is present in cells.  CCR5 is the receptor used by HIV to gain entry into target cells.  People who inherit the CCR5-32 mutation from one parent have reduced levels of the CCR5 receptor on their cells.  People who inherit the CCR5?32 mutation from both parents completely lack the CCR5 receptor.  In the case of Anthony Brown, also known as 'the Berlin patient,' Mr. Brown had life-threatening cancer and went through a very risk stem cell transplant procedure.  The donor of the cells was known as a  CCR5-32 homozygote (both of his parents lacked the CCR5 receptor).  In Brown's case, his newly transplanted immune system lacks CCR5 receptors and is resistant to most strains of HIV.   Knowledge of this receptor and the mutation has given HIV researchers increased hope of finding a way to cure HIV.  Share any knowledge you have and don't forget, it's OK to ask questions.", "\"I did a research paper on the Berlin patient and have tried to follow studies involving CCR5-32 mutation.  I remember when HIV first became a big topic among healthcare professionals.  In the beginning, we felt so discouraged, as if a cure was so far off.  Although we still haven't found the cure, advances in medicine have brought us so much closer.  I am waiting for the day that I will be able to witness patients who are cured completely.\"", "\"I am very new to the field of HIV research, and have not yet learned about CCR5?32 mutation.  Since the word mutation is used, I am curious to know if this is related to cell mutation that could get us a little closer to finding a cure?\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "What made you choose to participate in HIV research?", "answers": ["The interviewer knows there are many areas of research.  This question is an opportunity for him to get to know you.  For instance, if you know someone who has HIV and want to help find the cure, share that.  There is no right or wrong answer to this question.", "\"For me, HIV research is a personal challenge.  I used to work with pediatric patients and one of the most difficult things for me was seeing babies who were born to HIV+ mothers.  When I realized how many people are affected, I wanted to become part of the effort to find a cure.\"", "\"I spent some time working in an HIV clinic.  Although the care we provided was great, I wanted to do something that made me feel  like I was contributing to finding a cure.  I love the feeling of finding something new that gets us closer to a cure.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "While the term \"functional cure\" has been widely used, do you know why many researchers now prefer to say that patients are in remission rather than experiencing a functional cure?", "answers": ["There are rare examples of individuals who have been able to stop ART and maintain undetectable or low levels of HIV viral load for extended periods of time. A term that has been applied to these cases is 'functional cure', intended to mean that HIV is still present in the body but not causing harm.  However, in some of these cases HIV viral load has rebounded to high levels after a long period of being undetectable.  Share your understanding of why researchers prefer to say that these patients are in remission rather than cured.", "\"When someone is in remission, it is understood that there is always a chance of a 'rebound' or  'recurrence' of a disease.  Some people have stopped ART and been able to maintain undetectable or low levels of HIV viral load.  However, because there is always a chance that the viral load may rebound, many researchers feel the term 'remission' is more appropriate.\"", "\"One reason researchers prefer to use the term remission is that it is difficult to know for sure whether even very low levels of HIV might eventually damage the immune system and cause illness.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "Do you have any experience studying the effects of ART on the reduction or prevention of mother-to-child transmission of HIV?", "answers": ["One study has evaluated whether early ART can lead to remissions or cures in newborns who acquired HIV because their mothers did not receive ART to prevent mother-to-child transmission (MTCT), or because MTCT was inadequate.  Share your thoughts or experience on this subject.", "\"When I first began studying MTCT, I researched the case of 'the Mississippi Baby, a child who was initially thought cured of HIV infection but experienced a rebound of viral load after 27 months off ART.   I believe encouraging mothers to continue ART throughout pregnancy and administering medications to their newborns can help slow or stall the infection while we continue to work toward finding a cure.\"", "\"I am currently following a case study that is comparing the differences between mothers who were on ART therapy during pregnancy and those who did not maintain a consistent therapy to see the percentages of babies that were born of those pregnancy HIV+.  The numbers are staggering and often leaves us questioning why someone would ever choose not to participate in a therapy that could possibly slow or stall the progression of their own infection and possibly lower the chances of their child being born infected.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "Company ABC understands that some change is inevitable.  However, our objective is find researchers who want to build a long-term career with us.  Do you anticipate any significant changes in your life within the next 2-3 years?", "answers": ["Knowing what goals you have and any changes you anticipate in your life will give the interviewer an opportunity to evaluate two things: 1. what positions are available that won't disrupt your plans and, 2.  are you interested in having a long-term relationship within the company?  Change is good and growth is encouraged.  However,  because employers invest time and money in training new employees, they prefer that they have a plan to stay for the long-term.  Nevertheless, if you do not plan on staying in the same place for an extended period of time, it is best to be honest in the beginning rather than risking a poor job reference later.", "\"I am very interested in finding a place where I can grow and possibly have room for advancement.  I understand that some projects at Company ABC are being conducted on a short-term or trial basis, and I would be willing to participate in those and earn my way to a more stationary role here.\"", "For example:  \"I recently became engaged.  Although we have not set a date yet, we have agreed to wait twelve months before the marriage.  My fiance' just passed the Bar exam here and has been offered an opportunity to join an existing law firm.  Presently, our plans are to stay where we are and build a career, not just work a job.  Also, we do not plan on having children for at least two years after our marriage.  We both feel that being able to become established in our careers and save for our future would be the responsible thing to do before starting a family.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "Some of the projects at Company ABC require travel.  Would you be interested in a position that requires travel?", "answers": ["Many times candidates feel like they have to give an answer that the interviewer would choose.  For instance, when being asked a question like this one, some candidates will answer 'yes' just so they won't be overlooked for any open position.  Interviewers are not looking for you to give an answer that does not reflect what you really want.  Notice the questions says 'some projects'.  If you like to travel, that's great.  If you don't or feel like that would not be the best option for you, say so.", "\"While I love to travel, I have two small children and prefer to have a position with little to no overnight stays.  Nevertheless, I am very interested in working with Company ABC and would be willing to work a travel position until a more stationary opportunity becomes available.\"", "\"I love to travel.  One thing I enjoy about traveling for work is getting to experience working with people from different areas and gleaning from their knowledge.  I believe anything we can do to add value to one another is adding value to our research.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "Have you ever heard of the 'kick and kill' approach with regard to cell depletion?", "answers": ["Interviewers do not expect you have a perfect understanding of every trial or every bit of information that is available.  If you are asking about something that you are not familiar with, say so, but show an interest in learning.  This tells the interviewer that you are not intimidated by those who may know a little more than you and that you are willing to learn, which is what research is about.", "\"I have heard the term 'kick and kill' but I am not really familiar with what it involves.  If time allows, I would love to hear some information about it.\"", "\"I have recently heard about the 'kick and kill approach.'  If my understanding is correct, this is a one-two combination of activating latent HIV infected cells followed by targeting the infected cells for elimination.  If this is successful, it could lead to some great advances in curing HIV.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "At Company ABC some of the projects that are currently active require at least one research technician to be present in the lab 24 hrs/day.  Is there a schedule that would best fit your personal obligations but still allow you to work?", "answers": ["While being assigned your preference of a schedule may not be a guarantee, the interviewer still wants to know what is best for you.  Stating a preference is not saying that you will decline another reasonable offer.  It does, however, create a platform for discussing options that could meet your needs and the needs of Company ABC while allowing some time for personal things.  Whatever your preference, share a bit of why you prefer that schedule.", "\"I am a bit of a night owl, so working nights would definitely be a position I would consider.  Also, I am not married and have no children so I could possibly fill a position in a later shift and give employees with families more time at home with them.\"", "\"I have a child who is in elementary school and my spouse works evenings.  A day shift would be an easier transition for me.  However, my spouse and I have discussed the fact that we may need to make some scheduling adjustments if I am offered a position with Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "What made you choose to apply for a position with us at Company ABC?", "answers": ["More likely than not, the interviewer wishes to see how much you know about Company ABC and whether you can identify with the organization's values and vision. Every organization has its strong points, and these are the ones that you should highlight in your answer.", "\"I have heard so many good things about Company ABC.  One thing that caused my attention to be drawn to Company ABC is the many avenues of research that are utilized in trying to find a cure for HIV.\"", "\"One of the physicians that I used to work with spoke very highly of Company ABC when I asked who the top HIV research companies were, he mentioned Company ABC immediately.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "What do you find most stressful about working in the research industry?", "answers": ["The interviewer knows that all jobs are stressful at times, so saying that you are never stressed at work is not a good idea.  Remember to end on a positive note.", "\"I think the thing that stresses me the most is when I feel that I am close to a breakthrough in my research and then face a set-back.  However, a setback is not a stopping point.  It's just a place of reflection and planning.\"", "\"Although I am not easily stressed, there are times that we all feel a little anxious about things.  I think the most stressful thing about research is not finding a cure as fast we all hope to.  Still, research is my passion.  I couldn't imagine doing anything\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "Have you ever done any volunteer work such as participating in efforts to educate the public about HIV?", "answers": ["While volunteering is likely not a requirement for Company ABC, your willingness to volunteer or provide education regarding cancer research tells the interviewer that you are committed to being involved in any efforts possible to help create awareness.  If you have not volunteered in the past, that's OK.  Ask about opportunities for employees to be involved with research on a community/volunteer level.", "\"One thing I have wanted to do is become more involved in educating the public about HIV research efforts.  I've spent a great deal of time conducting research, but I've not yet had the opportunity to share that research on a public level.  If Company ABC has an opportunity for someone to research as well as educate others, I would love to hear about it.\"", "\"I have participated in some public education classes such as at health units on more than one occasion.  Much of the substance of the encounters involved educating healthcare providers about efforts to help prevent the spread of HIV so that they could, in turn, provide more up-to-date statistics to their clients.  I would like to explore opportunities to be more involved with community education regarding HIV research and options for treatment.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "What do you think  your previous co-workers would say are your best and worst qualities?", "answers": ["No one wants to share anything negative about themselves.  However, any honest person will admit that he has both good and bad characteristics.  The important thing is recognizing the things that may need to be improved and being willing to address them.  Share some things about your personal qualities with the interviewer and remember, when sharing any quality that could be improved, tell how you are working to make a change.", "\"I would have to say that one of the things I'd like to improve about myself and that most people recognize about me is I always want to be the 'fixer.'  While I know that this is not always a negative thing, for me, I have often let the fact that I couldn't fix a certain situation be something that troubled me.  On a lighter note, I believe I have a positive, out-going personality.  I enjoy getting to know others and like to make them feel comfortable.\"", "\"My best quality, I believe, is that I am willing to work on any project I am asked to take on.  My worst quality is that I am willing to take on too many projects at once.  I've had to learn to pace myself and prioritize things that need to be done so I am not overwhelmed and so that my quality of work does not suffer because I am too busy.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "At Company ABC, our researchers spend a great deal of time with and rely upon one another.  This requires building strong relationships.  Do you consider yourself a strong relationship builder?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you would treat everyone at Company ABC with great respect and a positive attitude. Discuss the ways that you would build strong and healthy relationships if hired.", "\"I have often been complimented on my relationship building skills. I like to get to know people and ask them questions about themselves. I find it's a great and simple way to start building rapport with others. I consider myself to be a strong relationship builder and take pride in my 'people skills'.   For this reason, I feel I would be a great ambassador of positive relationships for Company ABC.\"", "\"I do feel like a have strong relationship skills.  I have always believed that treating others with respect is the key to building a strong foundation in a relationship.  The better our relationship with others, the more we can accomplish and I plan on doing my part to make sure we meet our goals.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "Many people have voiced different opinions regarding embryonic stem cell research.  What is your understanding of this branch of research and do you have thoughts about why some people are opposed to this?", "answers": ["There are various reasons that people voice opposition to stem cell research.  Even if you have never worked with stem cell research, you can share your thoughts about why some people may be opposed.", "\"I believe that the majority of people who oppose embryonic stem cell research do so because they don't have a clear understanding of what type of cells are used and the benefits that the research can accomplish.  Embryonic stem cells are derived from the inner cells of human blastocysts, which occur 5-10 days after fertilization, but before implantation into the uterus.  I honestly believe if those in opposition were educated to understand that embryonic stem cells are not taken from a living fetus they would be  more supportive.\"", "\"I believe there are many reasons that people oppose stem cell research.  When the word 'embryonic' is used, the majority of the population relates this to an unborn child.  If people can understand that a pregnancy has not been achieved at the time these cells are harvested and can know that cloning for reproductive purposes in human beings is not legal, they would be more open to the idea of this type of research.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "What are some things that you would like people you meet to notice about your personality?", "answers": ["Personality and character are closely related.  For instance, someone with an honest character or good work ethic will tend to be more open about his or her beliefs as well as personal and professional expectations.  The interviewer is looking for ques as to what character you may bring to the table, so to speak.  It is important to remember, body language speaks volume and eye contact is a big indicator of your self-esteem, and your self-esteem is reflected outwardly in your personality.  Be confident when you answer and make eye contact with the interviewer.", "\"I would describe my personality as approachable, light-hearted, and positive.  I like to give more than I take and pride myself on being part of a team.\"", "\"I would like for people to feel that I am genuine and easy to get along with.   Life can be stressful, but we don't have to dwell on difficult things.  I want to people to see that, no matter what may be going on whether at home or work, I have a positive attitude and a good work ethic."]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "Research has shown that people who have family (spouse, life partner, etc) are more likely to survive a life-threatening diagnosis.  Do you have thoughts as to why this may be true?", "answers": ["Research shows that when you're married, you're less likely to die from major illnesses.   A study published recently looked at more than 780,000 Californians diagnosed with cancer and other life-threatening diseases over a nine-year period.  It found that single men were 27 percent more likely to die from their condition than married men were. For single women, the mortality rate was 19 percent higher than for their married counterparts.  What are some reasons you can think of that may support these findings?", "\"I can understand the idea that states married people may survive longer.  In fact, I would venture to say that anyone with a strong support system or a long-term commitment with a significant other will be more likely to survive any illness.  I believe this is in part because when a patient is going through a tough treatment plan, having someone to encourage them through it helps them to endure the difficultly and complete the plan.\"", "\"I can think of a few reasons that this may be true.  One factor that I think is conceivable is that a married couple often has two incomes which allows them to afford healthcare costs.  Also, if someone has a spouse or partner, that person often encourages them to seek a diagnosis and treatment plan in hopes of becoming well again.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "While doing research or HIV studies, what is something you have learned that others may not know? This can be an HIV fact or something related to HIV patients.", "answers": ["Often, interviewers will ask questions that include 'what is your opinion....' or 'what have you learned...'.  These type of questions are useful for an interviewer to see where your interests lie and how motivated you are with regard to learning independently.  Share something you learned while researching HIV and include in the answer why it is of interest to you or what makes it important in providing care to HIV patients.", "\"I once did a study on depression and anxiety disorders that developed after an HIV diagnosis.  In that study I found that the suicide rate of  HIV victims is 25% higher than that of the general population.\"", "\"I learned that 1.1 million people in the United States are living with HIV. Based on statistics, about 15% do not even know they are infected.\""]}, {"topic": "Medical+Research+-+HIV", "question": "If you could travel anywhere in the world, where would you go?", "answers": ["Employers realize that there is life outside of work.  Getting to know employees/potential employees and what interests them gives employers an opportunity to develop a relationship with them.  Share what you like.  Have you been to a destination you'd like to return to?  Is there somewhere you've always dreamed of going?  This is also an opportunity for you to get to know the employer.  Ask questions to show your interest in building a relationship.", "\"Without a doubt, I would go to Italy!  I have always wanted to travel and Italy will be one of the first places I go to once I have time to go and really experience it!  Have you ever been to another country?\"", "\"When I was younger, I went on a mission trip to Brazil.  I have always wanted to return and spend time with the missionaries who are still there.  I came back with such an appreciation for the opportunities and conveniences that we have here.  What about you?  Have you ever traveled abroad?"]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "At Company ABC we want to give everyone a fair chance.  However, salary is often commensurate with experience.  How do you feel about someone with the same job title as you having a higher salary based on experience?", "answers": ["Most employers do offer higher salary incentives to get more seasoned employees.  This is not meant to devalue a person's knowledge or experience, but rather paying for more experience.  It is important to note that the interviewer is not saying you will definitely make less than someone with more experience.  Many times this question is to see how you respond and how badly you want a position.  If an employee is willing to put in the work and earn the pay increase, employers often see them as someone worth investing in.  This is a good time to ask what the beginning salary is and discuss options that are negotiable such as benefits and paid time off.", "\"I understand that years of experience are often rewarded with higher earning.  I feel, given the chance to demonstrate my knowledge and skills, you will find that I am capable of doing the job as well as some of the more experienced employees.  Having said that, I will not turn down an offer of employment because of a difference in pay based on my present lack of experience.  With that in mind, what benefits are available for someone coming on board with your company with my resume?\"", "\"I would agree that experience speaks volumes.  While I am confident in my abilities, I do not expect to be given preferential treatment.  I am willing to work and let my skills speak for themselves as I earn my way to a higher salary.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "If you were the person responsible for hiring :Cnew employees, what qualities would you be looking for during the interview?  Do you feel that you display those qualities yourself?", "answers": ["There is more than one reason for asking this question.  First, the interviewer wants to know what qualities you think are important to perform this job.  Second, and most importantly, your answer will tell the interviewer if you hold yourself to the same standard as you do others.    If you want to see certain characteristics in your peers, you should be able to tell the interviewer with confidence that you possess those traits, as well.  This question is one that interviewers often use to distinguish sincerity on the part of the candidate.", "\"I believe that honesty is important no matter what job title a person holds.  I have found that being honest with people creates an atmosphere of mutual trust and respect.  Those qualities, I feel, are essential when building rapport with patients and co-workers.\"", "\"For me, a person who is confidant in their abilities, yet humble enough to know that we all need to continue growing and learning is a great quality.  Also, I enjoy working with people who strive to have a positive outlook despite some of the more difficult situations we face as healthcare providers.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "Has there ever been a time that you felt singled out for your personal convictions?  If so, what did you learn from that experience that allows you to feel empathy towards your patients and/or co-workers?", "answers": ["Bullying is unfortunately not exclusive to school-aged children.  It is often seen among peers in the workplace.  Company ABC wants to know that you are capable of showing empathy with others.  This question presents an opportunity for you to share a personal experience that may have caused you to feel vulnerable, but also gave you the chance to react in a way that is positive.  Feeling like your personal beliefs are under scrutiny can be stressful.  Your answer, especially if you have experienced this personally, will show the interviewer how you handle stress and how you may be able to diffuse a similar situation in the future.", "\"I think we all have felt singled out at one time or another.  For  me, religious issues have been where I have experienced the most trying situations.  My religion practices a strict dress code and there were times, especially as a teenager, that I felt some of my practices were the reason I was excluded from activities.  However, I believe that differences are what make the world a more interesting place.  If I can't participate in something because of a particular practice that I observe, I simply find other things to occupy my time.\"", "\"Of course there have been times when co-workers and I have had differences of opinions.  However, I have always tried to be the kind of person that does not 'wear my feelings on my shoulder.'  There are bigger issues at hand, like trying to help our patients get through difficult times.  So, while I have been aware of certain things that others may have taken issue with, I have tried to not let them get in the way of patient care and professionalism.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "One common diagnosis weamong cancer patients is Altered Body Image.  Have you ever had a patient with this diagnosis?", "answers": ["Company ABC specializes in the care of cancer patients.  Because of the changes that occur in these patient's bodies, Altered Body Image is a common d  Understanding why a patient has an altered perception of the view of his/her body is important in helping them to adjust to the changes in their body.  If you have ever had a patient with altered body image, this is a good time to share that experience with the interviewer.", "\"Most of the patients I have had with altered body image were women who had to have mastectomies related to breast cancer.  We always made sure these patients had counseling referrals and an option for prosthetics, if desired.  It is unfortunate that society places such value on body parts that the loss of those parts cause can lead a patient to feel a loss of a sense of themselves.\"", "\"I am familiar with patients with altered body image.  One patient that I will never forget was a 16 yr old girl.  She was involved in a car accident and lost her right leg.  Before the accident, she had plans to play college basketball.  Although she received counseling and was fitted for a prosthetic leg, she did not pursue her dream of playing sports.  I can only imagine the grief that she had to deal with.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "What are some ways that you feel are beneficial in resolving work-related tension among co-workers?", "answers": ["Being able to help resolve issues and relieve tension is a great characteristic in anyone, especially in healthcare providers.  Share your thoughts with the interviewer regarding how to help with day to day tensions and stress.", "\"We all have a bad day from time to time, no matter what our job is.  I think the important thing is to remember to be forgiving and as understanding as possible.  If I finish my assignments a little early, I always try to offer help to others to try and take the pressure of falling behind off of them.\"", "\"I always try to have a light-hearted approach to stressful issues.  It's easy to get caught up in tense situations but I think that being kind is a great way to help others take a step back and evaluate the situation and try to resolve those issues.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "Please share one of your most difficult cases and how you dealt with it.", "answers": ["Being able to talk about a difficult case is one thing that will show the interviewer your coping mechanisms.  Proper coping mechanisms are essential when caring for any clients, especially those with a diagnosis such as cancer, as these cases are usually multi-faceted.  Share your thoughts with the interviewer.", "\"The most difficult case I have ever had was a four year old with leukemia. I will never forget her. She had been misdiagnosed before coming to us which caused a delay in an appropriate treatment plan being started. Her family, understandably, experienced denial through the whole process of her treatment. She survived for 6 months after her diagnosis. I poured myself into work and eventually took classes to become a bereavement counselor. Learning how to process grief and how to help others process grief helped me deal with the feelings I had regarding her death.\"", "\"The most difficult case I ever had was actually not my patient.  My dad was diagnosed with lung cancer on his 62nd birthday.  He was given 6-12 months to live.  He survived for 9 weeks.  I went to a counselor after his death to help me process the grief.  Once I decided to return to work full-time, I knew oncology is where I wanted to be.  I wanted to care for people who were going through the same things my family and I went throug"]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "At Company ABC, we encourage growth and advancement. Have you ever worked as a team leader or in another supervisory position?", "answers": ["While having previous experience as a supervisor may not be required for the job for which you are applying, having that type of experience could tell the interviewer some things about your work ethic.  Share your experience, and if you've never been a supervisor, be sure to include your strengths as part of your answer.", "\"Up to this point in my career, I have not taken on a supervisory role.  I enjoy the one on one interaction with my patients and always felt like if I took a supervisor position I may miss out on that part of the job.  I can see where, in time, I may choose to seek a different role.  For now, though, I am happy to be in a more 'hands-on' role.\"", "\"I worked as a shift supervisor at my previous job.  It was a great opportunity and I really enjoyed what I did there.  I know many people who say once they've worked as a supervisor they wouldn't want to step down from that type of position.  For me, it's not about the title I wear but the difference I can make.  It takes a group of different people with different skills to make a healthcare team work.  I just want to do my part in any way I can.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "We like to have a community presence and like to work with community leaders to identify needs of people in the areas we serve.  Have you ever done any volunteer work within the community?", "answers": ["Although being a community volunteer is not a requirement for employment at Company ABC, willingness to give of your time and resources to others without compensation shows the interviewer that you have a sincere desire to serve others.  If you have volunteered, share a positive experience you had as a volunteer.  If you have not volunteered, it is not necessary to embellish your answer.  Stating that you have not volunteered previously is not going to disqualify you from employment.", "\"I love to volunteer!  A group of ladies from my church volunteer at a soup kitchen close to my home once a month.  There is nothing like the feeling of giving to someone that you know cannot give back to you!  Are there opportunities for employees to volunteer through the hospital?\"", "\"I think being present in the community and offering resources is a great idea.  So many people do not know about all of the medical resources there are to help them live healthier lives.  One thing I have wanted to do is spend more time volunteering.  If there is a place where I can be used as a volunteer, I would love to hear more about it.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "At Company ABC we believe in rewarding good work. Have you ever received recognition for your job performance or contribution?", "answers": ["While previously receiving recognition for a job well done is not a requirement for most employment, receiving credit for your performance or contribution demonstrates to the interviewer that your work is a priority.  Employers do not hand out awards for people who don't earn them.  This is your opportunity to share something positive about yourself.  However, remember to be humble!", "\"I was so excited to be awarded 'Who's Who Among (Facility Name) Nurses' at one of my former places of employment.  Employees within each department nominated and voted on who should be given the honor.  Then hospital administration chose an employee of the year from each of the winners.  I am very grateful for the recognition.\"", "\"I was chosen as employee of the month at a family practice clinic where I used to work.  I was so surprised and felt so honored.  For me, even the simplest smile or 'thank you' from a fellow employee or co-worker would have been enough.  Still, I am very thankful.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "Everyone you meet has an individual personality.  What is something you would like people who are meeting you to know about your personality?", "answers": ["Company ABC wants to know about you.  This question will give the interviewer ques as to what character you may bring to the table, so to speak. Personality and character are two things that are closely related.  For instance, someone with an honest character or good work ethic will tend to be more open about his or her beliefs as well as personal and professional expectations.   It is important to remember, body language speaks volume and eye contact is a big indicator of your self-esteem, and your self-esteem is reflected outwardly in your personality.  Be confident when you answer and make eye contact with the interviewer.", "\"I would describe my personality as approachable, light-hearted, and positive.  I like to give more than I take and pride myself on being part of a team.\"", "\"I would definitely describe my personality as honest and giving.  I like the feeling of being someone that others can trust and depend on.  I think those two"]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "While we at Company ABC seek to hire employees who have intentions of staying with us for the long-term, we understand that changes occur in life.   What changes in your personal or professional life do you anticipate to occur within the next 3-5 years?", "answers": ["Knowing what goals you have and any changes you anticipate in your life will give the interviewer an opportunity to evaluate two things: 1. what positions are available that won't disrupt your plans and, 2.  are you interested in having a long-term relationship within the company?  Change is good and growth is encouraged.  However,  because employers invest time and money in training new employees, they prefer that they have a plan to stay for the long-term.  Still, if you don't plan on being in the same geographical area five years from now, it's OK to say that now.  With large companies,  there are often opportunities for transfers to other facilities within the same network.  Either way, being upfront and honest is always appreciated.", "\"I recently became engaged.  Although we have not set a date yet, we have agreed to wait twelve months before the marriage.  My fiance' just passed the Bar exam here and has been offered an opportunity to join an existing law firm.  Presently, our plans are to stay where we are and build a career, not just work a job.  Also, we do not plan on having children for at least two years after our marriage.  We both feel that being able to become established in our careers and save for our future would be the responsible thing to do before starting a family.\"", "\"I don't anticipate any significant changes, such as a move or a career change.  I have come to a place in my life where I want to be in one place.  I did all of my traveling years ago and now I just want to work and enjoy a slower pace of life.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "At Company ABC, we encourage growth and development with regard to education and specialty skills.  Have you ever considered going back to college or getting a certification in a specialty area?", "answers": ["Many employers realize that an investment in their employees is actually an investment in their company.  With employer-sponsored education opportunities, employees can continue their education with little to no out-of-pocket expense in exchange for signing a contract to continue working with that company for a set amount of time.  For many, it is a win-win situation.   An interviewer is likely to recommend a candidate for employment if he feels that the candidate has the intention to stay employed within the company for an extended time and taking advantage of an employer-sponsored education can guarantee that.   However, if you are not interested in continuing your education at this time, simply state that you have reached a place where you are satisfied with your degree, but appreciate the fact that the option is there if your future goals change.", "\"I think having an opportunity to continue education while working is an awesome benefit!  I initially completed my Associate's degree and planned to go back to school later.  I want and need to work, but would love the opportunity to work toward my Bachelor's degree without having to sacrifice my job.\"", "\"I loved nursing school and completed my practical nursing degree.  While I realize there are several opportunities for nurses with higher degrees, at this point in my life, I feel content with where I am professionally.  It is nice to know that I could explore the option of continuing my education and continue working later on, if my goals change.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "At Company ABC, we try to accommodate employees by offering different options for shifts or schedules, when possible. Is there a specific shift or schedule that would fit best with your family life and schedule?", "answers": ["Many people work more than one job or have a one parent home which requires them to have a flexible schedule.  Others simply prefer to work one shift rather than another.  Being upfront with the interviewer about what schedule suits your preference could help prevent conflict later on.  It is easier to plan a schedule you can agree on than it is to fix problems that arise due to fear of being rejected.  Be honest and direct.", "\"I am not married and have no children at this time.  So, I am pretty flexible with my schedule.  If I had a choice, I would prefer the late shift, as I am a bit of a night owl.  However, I am  excited about the opportunity to become a part of this team and am willing to work where I'm needed.\"", "\"I am a single mom with two school-aged children.  Ideally, the day shift would be a better fit for me.  This would allow me to fulfill both my work and home responsibilities without a conflict.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "Many times healthcare providers who work with critical patients, such as cancer victims, tend to distance themselves from others.  Why do you think this is, and do you think it is beneficial?", "answers": ["Understanding the reasons a person may wish to distance himself/herself from others is helpful when trying to address the stresses of work.  The interviewer values your opinion; so don't be afraid to share your thoughts.", "\"While I understand that many healthcare workers often feel a need to distance themselves from attachments, I do not think it is beneficial in the end.  I think as healthcare providers, especially in areas where there is a high risk of loss of life, many of us create a barrier between ourselves and others.  It's like a 'self-protect' mode.  However, when we are secluded from others, we tend to internalize our emotions and the stress related to caring for these seriously ill patients can begin to affect us personally.  I worked with a group of people previously in critical care who had a weekly dinner scheduled.  Everyone was not able to attend every week, but it was a standing 'date' for those who were able.  It gave us an opportunity to laugh and enjoy one another's company without the anxiety of the day looming over us.\"", "\"I emphatically feel that seclusion is not in the best interest of healthcare providers.  While we all need a chance to refocus and get our thoughts together, I think it is important to remember the old saying 'no man is an island.'  What I mean is, we need each other.  No one can offer support to a healthcare provider like someone who does the same job.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "At Company ABC we encourage a healthy balance between our work and personal lives.  What are some things that you do to help create a healthy work/life balance?", "answers": ["No matter what profession a person chooses, everyone needs some time to unwind and relax.  Psychologists today say that a healthy balance in life allows a person to recharge and refocus which can result in better productivity at work. Company ABC simply wants to know what you do for you.  Maybe you have a favorite pass-time or hobby.  This is yet another way for the interviewer to get to know you as a person.", "\"One of my favorite pass-times is writing.  After a busy day at work, I like to journal or write articles for a blog that I author.  Both of these forms of writing allow me to release any feelings of frustration I may experience, especially after a stressful day or a difficult situation at work.   The writings in my journal are private and my way of 'letting it all out.'  The blog articles, on the other hand, are my way of using creative writing to share stories with my followers.\"", "\"For years I have kept a journal.  I also love creative writing.  When I have a stressful day, I like to write.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "Do you know how to perform a breast self-exam and how to instruct others to perform the exam?", "answers": ["Awareness regarding self-care is very important.  Educating patients on what may seem very simple, such as a breast self-exam could mean the difference in life or death for some people.  Statistics show that 39% of breast issues (lumps, masses, etc) are first found by the patient during a self exam.  Share your experience with the interviewer.", "\"I do know how to perform a breast self-exam and have taught others how to perform one correctly.  For the last two years, I have volunteered during Breast Cancer Awareness month teaching self-exams and assisting with mammograms.  Early detection is the best cure.\"", "\"I do know how to do a self exam and have taught patients how to perform them.  I believe it is crucial for both men and women to perform monthly exams.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "At Company ABC, we actively participate in clinical trials.  What are your thoughts regarding cancer patients being involved in clinical trials?", "answers": ["Clinical trials are essential for moving new methods of preventing, diagnosing, and treating cancer from the laboratory to physicians' offices and other clinical settings.  The ultimate goal is to improve care and quality of life for these patients.  Still, many people have varying opinions regarding whether or not patients should be subjected to something that is not proven to be effective.  The interviewer is getting to know you and your thoughts regarding evolving medicine.  You are not required to agree with clinical trials;  just share your thoughts.", "\"I think that clinical trials for any disease are a crucial part of developing effective treatment options for patients.  I do understand that many people do not agree with the idea and, to a point, I can see why.  Nevertheless, I believe the benefits outweigh the risks in the end if it means we can discover new ways for treating patients in hopes for a cure.\"", "\"I believe that any patient has the right to be a part of his/her treatment plan and it is up to each patient whether or not he/she wants to participate in a trial.  There are times when a new, unproven method may be the only option left.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "How long have you worked oncology, and what is the most stressful part of this job?", "answers": ["Any job that requires one to care for others, especially others who may be terminally ill, has times that are more stressful than others.  The interviewer does not expect you to be some super hero with no emotional connection or who does not feel overwhelmed at times.  This is the time to show your 'human nature side.'  A good way to respond would be to share what is most stressful for you and briefly add how you deal with the stress.", "\"I have worked with oncology patients for almost (X) years.  I would have to say that the most stressful part of this job is the 'not knowing.'  What I mean by that is, every patient is different.  They each respond to treatment in their own unique ways.  I try to stay positive and encouraging despite the fact that I do not always know the 'perfect answer.'  I have found that simply being an ear to listen or a shoulder to cry on not only relieves the patient's stress, but it often helps relieve my own, as well.\"", "\"The most stressful part of working oncology is having to acknowledge that not everyone I care for from day to day is going to beat cancer.  There are days when I feel like my patients are more resilient to the reality of their prognosis than I am. I am a 'fixer' and knowing that I can't always fix things or make them better is the hardest part for me.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "Not all cancer patients will go into remission.   How do you deal emotionally knowing that you are caring for someone who probably will not survive their illness?", "answers": ["Dealing with terminally ill patients is taxing, no matter how strong you are or how much experience one has.  Sharing your thoughts on how you deal with these difficult situations gives the interviewer a chance to know you and what drives you to overcome these difficult times.", "\"That question is one that could have a different answer on any given day.  None of us wants to lose a patient.  For me, one of the best ways I have found to cope is by offering my time and understanding to patients and their families.  Often times they feel like I am helping them when, in fact, they are really the ones helping me to cope.\"", "\"Knowing that someone I am caring for today may not be alive tomorrow is very hard.  I guess we all have our own way of dealing with things.  For me, when I leave work for the day, I try to surround myself around people and things that I love so that I can have some positive vibes to carry me through.  Some days are more difficult than others, but I am still here and can't imagine myself doing any other type of work.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "Have you ever been responsible for providing education to chemotherapy patients regarding changes that may occur in their bodies due to treatment?", "answers": ["Chemotherapy, while beneficial at times, also has its negative effects.  Most patients experience hair loss and weight loss.  For most, swallowing becomes difficult because the chemotherapy often causes blisters or sores in the mouth and throat.   Preparing a patient for these possible effects beforehand allows them some time to begin to process what to expect and often helps with their mental well being through the process.  Share any experience you have with the interviewer.", "\"I have been responsible for the education of chemotherapy patients and family members.  One of the most concerning things is making sure that they understand alternatives to meeting nutritional needs such as drinking supplemental shakes (Ensure, Glucerna, etc) if mouth sores develop during treatment.\"", "\"One of my main responsibilities at my previous employer was pre-chemotherapy education.  One of things that patients always thought they were 'prepared for,' but really were not was hair loss.  I got to know some people who own a wig company in that town who provided complimentary consultations to our patients.  It was heartwarming to see people reach out and help in such a giving w"]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "Chemotherapy often affects a patient's immune system.  What are some things you would suggest to these patients to help prevent complications during chemotherapy treatment?", "answers": ["One of the  main concerns in providing care to patients who are receiving chemotherapy treatment is their susceptibility to other illness or infections related to a compromised immune system.  Sharing your understanding of this risk with the interviewer is important.", "\"I think education before beginning chemotherapy is essential.  Including family members in the education is also helpful since patients require a bit of assistance during the chemo  regimen.  It has been my experience that if patients and family understand the most common infection control measures such as proper hand hygiene, staying away from people who are ill, and for patients to wear a mask if they have to be in public places, this reduces many of the illnesses that these patients could acquire.\"", "\"I believe it is important for patients to understand that prevention is key when it comes to protecting themselves during chemotherapy treatment.  One of the easiest ways to protect against illness is to restrict visitors in and out of the home.  We also advise that if people are going to visit, the patient or family asks them if they have been sick or around anyone who has been sick within the previous week.  If they have, they are encouraged to ask the guest to wait to visit until they are sure they are not ill themselves.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "If you could choose a specialty area other than oncology, what would you choose, and why?", "answers": ["It is common for healthcare providers to choose different specialty areas.  Sometimes those areas complement one another while other times they may be opposites.  This is an opportunity for the interviewer to get to know you.  Share what an alternate specialty would be for you and why.", "\"I love oncology, but if I had to choose a different specialty, I would choose something on the opposite end of the healthcare spectrum.  I would choose labor and delivery. Dealing with cancer can be very heart-wrenching at times.  I think I would welcome the opportunity to be a part of something as joyful as helping to bring a baby into the world.\"", "\"I have always had a fascination with the heart and really think I would like an opportunity to learn more about cardiology and cardiac care.  Of course, I love oncology, but I think learning is something we should do every day.  Cardiology would definitely be my next choice.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "Cancer is the leading cause of death from disease among children and adolescents in the United States.  Have you ever worked with pediatric oncology patients?", "answers": ["Any experience you have working with cancer patients is a plus when applying for employment with an oncology care provider.  Because cancer is the leading cause of death from disease in children & adolescents, if you do have experience with pediatric oncology, you may be an asset in the pediatric oncology ward.  If you don't have experience with pediatric oncology, that's OK.  Share what knowledge or experience you do have.", "\"I have worked with some pediatric cancer patients in the past, but not exclusively with pediatric oncology.  If you have an opening on the pediatric oncology ward, I would love to hear about it and perhaps become part of that team, if you feel I am a good fit.\"", "\"I spent a summer working at St. Jude Children's Hospital.  I believe that one summer changed my life forever."]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "Would you say that you agree or disagree with using complimentary or alternative medicine in place of or in addition to standard medical treatment for cancer?", "answers": ["Complimentary medicine involves treatments that are used along with standard medical treatments, such as acupuncture, in hopes of reducing some side effects of cancer treatment.  Alternative medicine involves treatments that are used, such as a special diet, instead of standard medical treatments prescribed by an oncologist. Healthcare providers have many different opinions regarding whether a patient should deviate from their physician's plan of care.  What are your thoughts?", "\"I believe anything a patient can do to be proactive in his/her care is important.  However, I also believe any approaches to self-care should be monitored closely by the patient's physician.\"", "\"I personally feel that patients should be able to have input in their plans of care.  I had some experience with a loved one who had cancer and there came a point when she didn't want to use traditional forms of treatment due to the side effects.  She chose some alternative treatments which allowed her to have less severe side effects and feel a little more in control in the end.  As with anything, I do recommend that patients discuss any treatment options with their primary care provider and their loved ones\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "At Company ABC, we like to provide holistic care which includes spiritual care.  What are your thoughts about this?", "answers": ["A holistic approach to healthcare includes not only physical and mental health, but spiritual care as well.  Many people confuse spirituality with religion.   What are your thoughts or experience?", "\"I believe any approach that we can take that gives a patient more peace of mind and helps them to begin a journey of recovery is an approach that we should explore.   We all have different ideas about what we think is best for us, and I believe we should extend the courtesy to our patients of asking what they want as part of their healthcare and providing the best care we can.\"", "\"I strongly believe in a holistic approach to healthcare.  I have found that when we address all aspects of an individual, creating plans of care that are more effective becomes easier, and patients resonate better with those plans.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "Statistics have shown that healthcare providers who work in high stress areas such as oncology or emergency rooms are more likely to abuse drugs.  Have you or anyone you know ever experienced an issue with drug abuse?", "answers": ["When someone is affected either personally, or through someone they know, it tends to give a deeper sense of understanding what it takes to overcome these addictions. Be honest. There is no wrong answer. If you have never used or been around someone who has used drugs, that's fine.  If you have, that's ok, too. This is a perfect time to share your feelings regarding an epidemic that is sweeping across our nation.", "\"I have never abused drugs of any type. I have a family member who was addicted to pain medicine after a bad car accident.  I saw the effects that the addiction had not only on him, but his family, as well.  It took a long time to break that addiction. I believe my personal experience with what I saw my family member go through is something I can use to encourage others to live a life free from drug abuse.\"", "\"It is shocking to see how many healthcare providers become addicted to drugs, whether prescription or illegal.  I have never used any drugs illegally and am not a big fan of using even prescribed pain medication.  I try to use more  natural resources for my healthcare, when I can.  I suppose the number of people I have seen who have developed addictions has been an 'eye-opener' to me and it has led me to find alternative ways to relieve pain.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "What made you choose a career in healthcare?", "answers": [":compan With so many career choices available, the interviewer is curious to know what made you choose this profession.  If you experienced something in your past that made you appreciate a healthcare provider, share that experience.  This is a perfect opportunity for the interviewer to know you on a personal level.", "\"When my son was born, he had to be in the neonatal intensive care unit for the first two weeks of his life.  I watched those nurses and doctors attend him with such care and concern, as if he was their baby.  Something about their gentleness with him and their compassion toward me and my family made me realize what a difference healthcare providers can make.  From that time forward, I began to pursue my career in the healthcare industry and I will never look back!\"", "\"Initially I did not choose healthcare as a career.  I went to school and got a degree in accounting and planned to open my own accounting business.  One day, I was at my office sitting at my desk and I realized that I did not want to spend the rest of my life sitting behind a desk.  I wanted to do something that really touched the lives of others.  I talked to friends and confidants and shared with them some of the things that I wanted to accomplish in my life.  I ended up registering for nursing classes and here I am!  I am so happy I made the change.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "Company ABC has several employees from different backgrounds.  What are your thoughts on diversity in the workplace and can you share a personal experience ?", "answers": ["Some people are intimidated when faced with learning new cultures and beliefs, but in the healthcare industry, it is crucial to provide effective care.  Company ABC would like to know that you are open to meeting and learning about new people and becoming an integral part of the team.  Be positive with your response.", "\"The largest diverse group I worked with was probably when I did my clinical rotation at University Medical Center.  I was afforded the opportunity to meet people from different cultures, religions, and professional backgrounds.  It gave me an eye-opening experience of how many wonderful people there are!\"", "\"I think diversity in the healthcare industry is essential.  People from all over the world now call our country their home.  I believe learning about and showing an appreciation for people from different walks of life only makes us stronger as we build upon the common bond of caring for others.\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "A disagreement can be expected when large groups of people work together.  Can you think of a time you had a disagreement with a co-worker and, if so, how did you resolve it?", "answers": ["Any time you work with someone else, there is a chance of having a disagreement about something at one time or another.  The interviewer knows this.  It's human nature for people to have their own opinions.  What is important to the interviewer in this question is whether or not you are willing to compromise and work through difficult situations with your co-workers.  Being unwilling to compromise or find alternative solutions to a dispute can affect everyone on the team, even if it is indirectly.  Sharing a personal experience is OK, but do not embellish it to 'be the hero.'", "\"I believe if we think about it, each of us could remember at least one disagreement with a friend or co-worker.  Although I consider myself to be pretty easy-going, I am also very passionate about my patients and the care that they receive.  I have been aware of disagreements between other co-workers, but really like to think of myself as more of a peacekeeper.  I feel like professional people should be able to discuss things logically and come to an agreement that is satisfactory for everyone involved.\"", "\"I think the most common disagreement between myself and others have involved our personal feelings about how healthcare should be carried out.  However, I have learned, as have most of the people that I have worked with, that while our opinions are important, plans of care are designated by strict guidelines and with the input of everyone on the care team as well as the patient.  Learning to respect those guidelines and patient wishes usually resolves issues that arise\""]}, {"topic": "Oncology+Clinics", "question": "If you could travel anywhere in the world, where would you go?", "answers": ["While this question may have nothing to do with the job for which you are interviewing, not all interviews have to be serious and 'stuffy.'  The interviewer is taking an interest in who you are as a person and what interests you.  Take some time to share what you would enjoy with him.", "\"Oh, if I could anywhere, I would love to spend a summer in Paris!  I can't speak but two or three words in French that anyone can understand, but I would love it!\"", "\"I have always wanted to travel to Rome.  I have always wanted to be a world traveler, and when I retire, Rome will be the first place I go!\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "Are you currently taking any mood altering drugs?", "answers": ["While all people have an expectation of privacy regarding any medical condition, healthcare providers are expected to disclose any medical condition they have or medications they are taking with their employer.  This is not meant to compromise confidentiality, but may be necessary in the event of an emergency.  If you are taking medications, be sure that you can present a current prescription if asked.  Remember, to be honest.", "\"I don't take any medications at this time.  A few years ago I went through a divorce and I took an anti-depressant.  I have not taken any medications for over a year now.\"", "\"I have taken Prozac for the last two years.  I experienced mild depression after the death of my sister and my primary doctor prescribed this.  Other than this medication, I only use over the counter pain relievers and herbal supplements.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "Pediatric care, while rewarding, can be very stressful.  What are some ways you may suggest for Company ABC to do that may allow employees a chance to confront and release workplace stress?", "answers": ["Stress in the workplace is inevitable, but it is important that it is addressed.  Healthcare providers often internalize stress and have been known to carry those frustrations home after work.   Do you have suggestions for helping to address work-related stress?  Share your thoughts with the interviewer.", "\"I think that offering a little extra time at shift change, maybe 10-15 minutes, for staff to not only give report on the patients, but to express any stresses or issues that were experienced that day would be very helpful.  We can't go home and talk about issues of the day or how a certain case made us feel because we risk compromising a patient's right to confidentiality.  However, in report with our co-workers, we can share our feelings and get support from people who really know how we feel.\"", "\"I have had this same conversation with some of my peers before.  Many people who work in high stress areas say that they would prefer to work longer hours 3-4 days a week rather than 8 hours a day for five or more days.  Having a schedule with more time off allows for some down time and an opportunity to unwind and come back to work refreshed.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "Company ABC puts forth our best effort to help break barriers that interfere with patient care.  Can you think of anything that may create a barrier to us being able to provide patient care to our pediatric patients, and how would you resolve the issue?", "answers": ["Anything that delays the implementation of a plan of care can be a barrier.  This question gives you an opportunity to show the interviewer your problem solving skills.  Share your thoughts on resolving barriers to care.", "\"One of the most common barriers to care is the lack of patient or caregivers.  Many times I have seen patients or their responsible party refuse care because they do not understand the treatment plan.  I believe taking a little extra time to explain what care needs to be provided helps to alleviate anxiety for the patient/caregiver and allows the healthcare provider to complete their job effectively.\"", "\"I think that prioritizing what job needs to be done first and taking the time explain any treatment or procedure to the patient and/or caregiver will prevent delays as the plan of care is being implemented.  Sometimes a simple bedside conversation can make things run much more smoothly.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "When you meet new people, what are some things you would like for them to know/recognize about your personality?", "answers": ["Personality and character are two things that are closely related.  For instance, someone with an honest character or good work ethic will tend to be more open about his or her beliefs as well as personal and professional expectations.  The interviewer is looking for ques as to what character you may bring to the table, so to speak.  It is important to remember, body language speaks volume and eye contact is a big indicator of your self-esteem, and your self-esteem is reflected outwardly in your personality.  Be confident when you answer and make eye contact with the interviewer.", "\"I would describe my personality as approachable, light-hearted, and positive.  I like to give more than I take and pride myself on being part of a team.  I always put effort into making sure that people who meet me quickly see those qualities in me and continue to see me as that type of person.\"", "\"I am a very-easy going person and love to laugh and joke.  Although I know there are times to be serious and focused, I still feel like we can have a good attitude and approachable personality.  I would hope that people who meet me recognize that qualities in my personality.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "Has there ever been a time that you felt like you should have chosen a career that is not healthcare related?", "answers": ["We all have days that we feel like we could have or should have done things differently.  Whether it's a minor decision like a paint color or a major decision like a career choice.  It's normal to wonder what things would be like if we had chosen a different path.  The interviewer is not asking this question to disqualify you based on a 'yes' answer.  Share your thoughts with the interviewer, honestly.  If you have ever wondered if you made the right decision, share what made you stay in healthcare.  There is no wrong answer.", "\"There have been times that I wondered what it would be like to be a teacher or a a research specialist.  For me, those were just fleeting thoughts and nothing that I really wanted to pursue.  I have always had a passion for patient care.  At the end of the day, I can't imagine myself ever doing anything else as a career.\"", "\"Several years ago I had an experience at work that left me questioning my career choice for a while.   An accident that occurred outside the hospital resulted in several patients being brought into our facility for care.  There were several fatalities, including children.  That incident took an emotional toll on several of us who worked that case.  I took a little time and also saw the bereavement counselor at work to help me work through the emotions from that incident.  I realize now that those emotions were natural and part of me questioning if I was in the right place was misplaced guilt for not being able to do more.  Despite the emotional experience of that day, I really can't think of anything I would rather do other than be a healthcare provider.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "What makes you think you will be successful at Company ABC?", "answers": ["Rather than just sharing how you have gone above and beyond expectations in the past, focus on how your qualities will help you to meet and exceed expectations with Company ABC. Discuss the reasons why will you be great at this job. Talk about your qualifications and skills that will help you to do this job well. If you can, match your strengths to the requirements outlined in the job description.", "\"I know I will be successful in this role because I have been working in this industry for five years with great training and under excellent leadership. I have a solid understanding of X, Y, and Z (skills listed in the job description). Also, I have all of my updated certifications as outlined in your job description. I am well-prepared for this next step in my career and look forward to becoming an integral part of Company ABC.\"", "\"I believe I will be successful with Company ABC because I have the skills outlined in your job description and a strong desire to grow and develop more skills.  I have researched Company ABC and feel that my personal goals and patient care philosophy aligns well with this company.  I look forward to seeing where I can be best utilized at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "Company ABC values education and tries to accommodate employees who are seeking to further their education by offering flexible schedules as much as possible.  If you could further your education, what specialty or sub-specialty would you choose?", "answers": ["Many employers offer employer-sponsored education opportunities.  Those who do not offer tuition assistance may offer flexible scheduling to accommodate an employee who is seeking higher education.  Sharing your thoughts regarding any specialty/sub-specialty that you would like to learn about gives the interviewer an opportunity to know you and to see if there are any opportunities within Company ABC that may help meet your educational goals.", "\"Pediatrics has always been my heart and I am happy anywhere I can work with children.  If I did have to choose a sub-specialty in pediatrics, it would definitely be cardiology.  The heart fascinates me and being able to learn more about it while caring pediatric patients would be a dream come true for me!\"", "\"I would definitely saw that endocrinology would be my first choice for a specialty area.  If I could study pediatric endocrinology, that would be awesome.  I have never questioned my decision to work in pediatrics, but being able to focus in on one specific area of study would be a great opportunity.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "When you were in school preparing for your career, what was the most difficult subject for you to grasp?", "answers": ["Your answer to this question is not going to give you a 'pass' or 'fail' on your interview.  The interviewer is getting to know what you feel are your strengths and weaknesses.  Don't be shy about sharing something you may have struggled with.  Be sure to share how you overcame that weakness to become successful in the class.", "\"Without a doubt, college math was my most dreaded subject!  I honestly think I have a mental block about math.  I did pass the class with a 3.0 average, but it was not easy!  I hired a tutor and spent extra time studying.  In the end, it was worth it.\"", "\"In the beginning, psychology was difficult for me.  It took me a while to separate my personal feelings from what I was being taught in some of the classes.  I had to take some time and change my way of thinking so that I could understand where certain theories came from and why and then I was able to begin to grasp the course more clearly.  Now I love psychology and enjoy studying it."]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "Company ABC  offers well-child care as part of our pediatric care clinic.  Part of well-child care is giving age appropriate immunizations.  Have you ever been responsible for doing well-child evaluations and giving immunizations?", "answers": ["Well-child care includes routine hearing and vision screenings, and immunizations.  While not all pediatric healthcare providers offer well-child care, those who do must hire or train employees in the proper education regarding and administration of immunizations.  Any experience you in this area or a willingness to be trained in well-child care could be a plus for you with the interviewer.", "\"Yes, I do have experience working with KidMed programs.  I used to work in a local health unit and was responsible for well-child screenings and for providing immunizations.  The fact that Company ABC offers well-child care is one of the things that attracted me to your facility.\"", "\"Until now, I have only worked pediatric critical care.  Knowing that Company ABC offers well-child care is one of the things that attracted me to your facility.  I realize I may have to have some training to work in the well-child area and am willing to participate in whatever training is necessary.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "Here at Company ABC we want to go the extra mile to help make hospital stays as comfortable as possible for children.  Do you have any ideas of ways that could make a patient's stay more pleasant or comfortable?", "answers": ["Being sick and/or hospitalized can be a frightening experience, especially for children.  Company ABC realizes that anxiety can impede treatment and healing times and seeks to find team members who are willing to put forth the necessary effort to make children feel as comfortable as possible.  If you have any ideas to help create this kind of atmosphere, share it.", "\"I think it is such a great thing that Company ABC  wants to make children more comfortable.  My experience working with children has been that children love to create things and have those things displayed.  One idea of something fun would be to give pediatric patients a blank ceiling tile, allow them to paint it, and then display it along the ceiling in place of a previously blank one.  With this idea, the child's art becomes a permanent part of the pediatric facility and can be enjoyed by patients and family now and in the future.\"", "\"I would love to see an activity room where children who are not contagious can meet and greet one another.  I feel like when children see that others are going through something and being brave, they become brave themselves.  An activity area would also give parents of the children an opportunity to develop a support system.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "Do you have any previous experience working with pediatric patients?", "answers": ["As a pediatric care facility, Company ABC values the expertise of those with pediatric experience.  However, do not let a lack of pediatric experience be a deterrent to applying for employment here.  Often times employers like to hire less experienced workers and train them.  If you have pediatric experience, share it.  If you do not, tell the interviewer why you are interested in this specialty area.", "\"I have worked with pediatric patients previously, but not in a specialty facility.  I have always wanted to concentrate on pediatrics as a specialty which is why I chose to apply at Company ABC.  I'd love to see what employment positions you have that would be a fit with my education and experience.\"", "\"I worked in a pediatrician's office for two years and loved it.  I have wanted to make a move in my career where I can learn more skills and have more hands-on experience but stay within the pediatric realm of care.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "Company ABC has volunteers who work in many areas of our facility.  Have you ever been a volunteer in any healthcare setting, and if so, what was your favorite part of being a volunteer?", "answers": ["Pediatric patients, when possible, like to be engaged.  With this in mind, many pediatric facilities such as Company ABC recruit volunteers to participate in different activities with children and their families.  While volunteering is not likely to be a requirement for employment with :company,: a willingness to give of yourself without expecting compensation tells the interviewer that you are active and willing to go the extra mile when needed.  Share any experience or thoughts you have.", "\"I think utilizing volunteers with pediatric patients is a great idea.   I loved volunteering with children.  Some of the simplest things like coloring or working puzzles seemed to put a smile on their faces.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "One unfortunate thing that pediatric health care providers have to deal with from time to time is a child abuse case.  Have you ever had to work with any cases of abuse?", "answers": ["Nearly 700,000 children are abused in the United States each year and these are some of the most difficult cases for any healthcare provider.  Many facilities have specific staff that handle these special cases.  If you have experience with these cases, you could be an integral part of this team of specialists.  Remember to show compassion when you answer this question.", "\"The number of children who experience abuse is so alarming.  I have never worked with childhood abuse cases, but have some experience working elderly abuse cases.  No matter who is abused or by home, it is such a sad tragedy.\"", "\"I have not worked the medical side of abuse cases, but I used to work at junior high school and was aware of some cases of suspected abuse while there.  When those cases were brought to our attention, we had to refer them to administration who notified family services.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "As much as possible, Company ABC tries to offer flexible scheduling for employees.  Is there a particular shift or certain days that would work best for you?", "answers": ["Many people work more than one job or have dependents who require care and need to have a flexible schedule.  Others simply prefer to work one shift rather than another.  Being up front with the interviewer about what schedule suits your preference could help prevent conflict later on.  It is easier to plan a schedule you can agree on than it is to fix problems that arise due to fear of being rejected.  Be honest and direct.", "\"I am not married and have no children at this time.  So, I am pretty flexible with my schedule.  If I had a choice, I would prefer the late shift, as I am a bit of a night owl.  However, I am  excited about the opportunity to become a part of Company ABC and am willing to work where I'm needed.\"", "\"I am a single mom with two school-aged children.  Ideally, the day shift would be a better fit for me.  This would allow me to fulfill both my work and home responsibilities without a conflict.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "As you know, Company ABC is a pediatric care facility.  Is there a sub-specialty within pediatrics that you are interested working in?", "answers": ["There are many specialty areas to choose from as a healthcare provider.  Pediatrics is a specialty, but there are also sub-specialties.  Examples include: orthopedics, pediatric psychology, asthma and allergy care.  This question offers you an opportunity to share your interests with the interviewer.  Don't be shy.  Being open may just land you in the exact position you want!", "\"I love pediatric psychology!  The human mind is so interesting to me.  I've worked with adults who have mental health issues, but pediatric mental health is a world of its own.  I believe I read that Company ABC has a department devoted to pediatric psychology.  I would love to discuss any employment opportunities you have in that department.\"", "\"I am new to pediatrics and haven't really settled on a specialty area where I'd like to work.  One reason I sought out an employment opportunity at Company ABC is the various specialty areas here.  I look forward to having an opportunity to learn and grow here.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "Company ABC values the opinions of our employees.  If you were responsible for hiring someone, what qualities would you look for in a candidate?", "answers": ["There is more than one reason for asking this question.  First, the interviewer wants to know what qualities you think are important to perform this job.  Second, and most importantly, your answer will tell the interviewer if you hold yourself to the same standard as you do others.    If you want to see certain characteristics in your peers, you should be able to tell the interviewer with confidence that you possess those traits, as well.  This question is one that interviewers often use to distinguish sincerity on the part of the candidate.", "\"I believe that honesty is important no matter what job title a person holds.  I have found that being honest with people creates an atmosphere of mutual trust and respect.  Those qualities, I feel, are essential when building rapport with patients and co-workers.\"", "\"I always look for people who are passionate about what they do.  It's easy to tell if someone loves what they're doing.  When someone is passionate about their job or career, they have a sense of happiness when you talk with them about it.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "What do you think is a good practice for a healthcare provider to help get assigned work done in a timely manner, but with as little stress as possible?", "answers": ["A day in the life of a healthcare provider can be very hectic.  The interviewer wants to know how you approach these busy days and accomplish the things you need to get done.  Share your thoughts.", "\"I think we all have different approaches to getting our jobs done.  One habit I believe everyone should develop is prioritization.  I like to look at all of the assignments I have for the day and, if possible, work on the ones that take the least amount of time.  That way, I can complete the smaller jobs and then focus on the ones that take more time.\"", "\"Each day can bring different things.  I have made a practice of reviewing all of my daily assignments and making a 'to do' list.  I try to take the most serious cases and work those, then work the less critical ones.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "While we realize changes happen in life, Company ABC hopes to find employees who want to have a long-term working relationship with us.  What changes in your life/career do you anticipate in the next 3-5 years?", "answers": ["Knowing what goals you have and any changes you anticipate in your life will give the interviewer an opportunity to evaluate two things: 1. what positions are available that won't disrupt your plans and, 2.  are you interested in having a long-term relationship within the company?  Change is good and growth is encouraged.  However,  because employers invest time and money in training new employees, they prefer that they have a plan to stay for the long-term.  Still, if you don't plan on being in the same geographical area five years from now, it's OK to say that now.  Larger companies may haveopportunities for transfers to other facilities within the same network.  Either way, being upfront and honest is always appreciated.", "\"I recently became engaged.  Although we have not set a date yet, we have agreed to wait twelve months before the marriage.  My fiance' just passed the Bar exam here and has been offered an opportunity to join an existing law firm.  Presently, our plans are to stay where we are and build a career, not just work a job.  Also, we do not plan on having children for at least two years after our marriage.  We both feel that being able to become established in our careers and save for our future would be the responsible thing to do before starting a family.\"", "\"I do not anticipate any significant changes.  I have worked different specialty areas before finding a love of pediatrics.  I am at a place in my life where I want to stay in one place and grow my career.  It is my hope that I can become a part of Company ABC and have a long-term career here.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "At Company ABC we strive to attract and retain a highly skilled, talented, and diverse workforce.  What are your thoughts on diversity in the workplace and can you share a personal experience with diversity in the workplace?", "answers": ["When going to work for a company as large as Mercy Health Systems, diversity among peers and clients should be expected.   Some people are intimidated when faced with learning new cultures and beliefs, but in the healthcare industry, it is crucial to provide effective care.  The interviewer wants to know that you are open to meeting and learning about new people and becoming an integral part of the team.  Be positive with your response.", "\"The largest diverse group I worked with was probably when I did my clinical rotation at University Medical Center.  I was afforded the opportunity to meet people from different cultures, religions, and professional backgrounds.  It gave me an eye-opening experience of how many wonderful people there are!\"", "\"I think diversity in the healthcare industry is essential.  People from all over the world now call our country their home.  I believe learning about and showing an appreciation for people from different walks of life only makes us stronger as we build upon the common bond of caring for others.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "Company ABC works diligently to uphold the highest standards of care.   Do you have a clear understanding of the HIPAA law?", "answers": ["HIPAA (Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996) is part of United States legislation that provides data privacy and security provisions for safeguarding medical information.  Before receiving care or becoming an established patient at medical facilities, patients/responsible parties must sign a HIPAA compliance form which acknowledges they understand that their medical information is protected under federal guidelines.  They must also list the name(s) of anyone who is able to receive information regarding their medical care or health.  Without proper authorization,  no one can legally obtain this information.  It is crucial for anyone working in healthcare who may be responsible for handling any patient information to understand this law and abide by it strictly.  Share any knowledge or experience you have with the interviewer.", "\"I am very familiar with HIPAA guidelines and why they are in place.  I appreciate the fact that my medical information is protected by such a specific law and respect the rights and privacy of those for whom I provide care by abiding by those guidelines.\"", "\"I do have a clear understanding of HIPAA regulations.  I have taught continuing education classes on HIPAA and firmly believe that abiding by those guidelines is one thing that helps us build a strong relationship with our patients.  All patients want to know that we protect and safeguard their personal information.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "Here at Company ABC, we encourage employees to be proactive in learning about changing medicine and important topics related to their employment positions.  How do you make sure that your knowledge and certifications, if any, remain current?", "answers": ["State guidelines require that healthcare providers in various fields have continuing education credits annually.  While you may not hold a position that requires documented continuing education, it is still important to remain aware of changes in healthcare and how those changes affect your role.  Do you subscribe to a nursing or healthcare magazine or attend local workshops?  Anything that you do to help you stay informed is something you should share with the interviewer.", "\"I try to schedule at least two workshops each year that are focused on something within my licensing requirements.  A few months ago I attended a workshop on wound management for diabetic patients.  It was very informative.  I am also a member of some social media groups for nursing education.  In those groups, administrators share news and updates regarding new techniques or methods for providing healthcare as they become available.\"", "\"I love to read and subscribe to a few different healthcare magazines .  I also participate in continuing education classes any time they are offered locally or within my place of employment.  With regard to healthcare, I believe we should grow and learn as much as possible each day.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "It is easy for people to feel overwhelmed at work, especially those who provide care for other people.  What are some things that you do to unwind and give yourself a chance to relax and recharge?", "answers": ["No matter what profession a person chooses, everyone needs some time to unwind and relax.  Psychologists today say that a healthy balance in life allows a person to recharge and refocus which can result in better productivity at work.  The interviewer simply wants to know what you do for you.  Maybe you have a favorite pass-time or hobby.  This is yet another way for the interviewer to get to know you as a person.", "\"I really enjoy working out at the gym and, I also take a kickboxing class twice weekly.   After a good workout or class, I always feel like I can rest better and wake up energized and ready for the next day.\"", "\"One of my favorite pass-times is writing.  After a busy day at work, I like to journal or write articles for a blog that I author.  Both of these forms of writing allow me to release any feelings of frustration I may experience, especially after a stressful day or a difficult situation at work.   The writings in my journal are private and my way of 'letting it all out.'  The blog articles, on the other hand, are my way of using creative writing to share stories with my followers.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "Can you think of a time you had a disagreement with a co-worker and, if so, how did you resolve it?", "answers": ["Any time you work with someone else, there is a chance of having a disagreement about something at one time or another.  The interviewer knows this.  It's human nature for people to have their own opinions.  What is important to the interviewer in this question is whether or not you are willing to compromise and work through difficult situations with your co-workers.  Being unwilling to compromise or find alternative solutions to a dispute can affect everyone on the team, even if it is indirectly.  Sharing a personal experience is OK, but do not embellish it to 'be the hero.'", "\"I believe if we think about it, each of us could remember at least one disagreement with a friend or co-worker.  Although I consider myself to be pretty easy-going, I am also very passionate about my patients and the care that they receive.  I have been aware of disagreements between other co-workers, but really like to think of myself as more of a peacekeeper.  I feel like professional people should be able to discuss things logically and come to an agreement that is satisfactory for everyone involved.\"", "\"I have always tried to be someone that is easy to talk to and genuinely try to avoid conflict.  I understand that tensions can run high, especially when dealing with critical issues, but I am of the opinion that professional people should be able to talk to one another rationally and work together to resolve conflicts without arguing.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "Company ABC likes to recognize employees for their hard work and contributions.  Have you ever received an award or recognition for a job well done?", "answers": ["While previously receiving an award or recognition is not a requirement for employment at Company ABC, having received such could be an indicator to the interviewer about the type of work ethic you have.  Employers do not put names in a hat to pick who to give recognition to.  Those privileges are earned by dedication and hard work.  Those are qualities any employer is looking for.  Any recognition you have earned is worth mentioning now, but remember to be humble with your answer.", "\"At my last place of employment, I was honored to be chosen as employee of the month.  I was so shocked because my co-workers nominated me and then voted for me to receive the award.  I nominated someone else and later found out that the person I nominated nominated me!\"", "\"I love the fact that Company ABC recognizes the efforts of its employees.   Anytime someone can feel appreciated it seems to make them want to give even more effort to do a job well.  I received an award for outstanding character at one of my previous places of employment.  It was such an honor because at the end of the day I always want to know that I have done my job with honesty and integrity.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "Company ABC values strong relationships among our staff and patients.  What are some things you feel are important in relationship builder?", "answers": ["Building strong relationships is crucial for any business to be successful.  A career in healthcare demands the ability to communicate well with others and to develop strong relationships so that patients feel comfortable seeking care.    If you have a personal experience regarding relationship building, this is a good time to share.", "\"I believe consistency is key in building any relationship.  If I say I am going to do something, I do everything I can to follow through with what I say and make sure that I communicate with the appropriate people along the way.  It is easy for one mistake to destroy a relationship that took a great deal of time to build.  Knowing that, I always try to be upfront with those I am working with and for and make goals and objectives clearly known so that we all know what to expect from one another.\"", "\"I think giving others an opportunity to express what they expect from me gives me a chance to acknowledge expectations and set reasonable goals for achieving the outcome desired.  Knowing what is expected, keeping open communication, and being accountable, I believe, are key to building a strong relationship.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "Company ABC has some positions available in a few different departments.  Would you prefer to work in a position that involves more teamwork or a position that requires someone to work independently?", "answers": ["Knowing your preference with regard to a working environment will help the interviewer when trying to find the position that best fits your skills and preference.  Share your preference, but also make it clear that your main goal is to become a part of Company ABC.   If you should have to take a position that is not your first choice, you may later be given an opportunity to transfer to your preferred position.", "\"While I am comfortable working independently, I prefer to work in a team environment.  I like being able to work with and learn from others.  When I work within a team, I feel like I am challenged to do my best at all times.\"", "\"I appreciate teamwork and always strive to be a strong part of any team that I am part of, but if I had an opportunity to work independently, such as in a Case Management position, I would love that.  I enjoy knowing what job needs to be done and setting goals for myself.  I find pleasure in meeting those goals and moving forward.  Still, I am excited about the possibility of becoming a part of Company ABC and will gladly accept any position for which I am qualified.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "What has been your favorite place to work in your career, and is it similar to what you think Company ABC has to offer?", "answers": ["Sharing your experience regarding a favorite place you've worked will show the interviewer what areas are a good fit for you and what you value in an employer.  Further, it gives interviewers ideas of things to present to planning committees as they endeavor to improve employee satisfaction within their own facilities.  Now is your chance to have a say so!", "\"I know this may come as a shock, but my favorite place to work, so far, was hospice care.  That may sound strange because hospice deals only with terminally ill patients, but for me, there was so much more to this job than that.  I had an opportunity to add something of value to the life that my patients had left.  My bosses were awesome to work with.  They understood how emotional being a hospice care provider can be and were always so supportive of the 'not so good days' when we had a difficult day or a death.  They taught me the true meaning of compassion.  As far as being similar to Company ABC, I can only speak of what I have been told.  I know people who have worked here at Company ABC and have given exceptional opinions about the management and staff.  Their opinions are part of the reason I felt compelled to seek employment here\"", "\"I really can't think of any job I've had that I did not enjoy, but if I had to choose just one, emergency care would be the place I would choose.  Not everyone likes working the ER, but I love it!  The fast pace and the diverse group of people and medical issues always seemed to present an opportunity for learning and sharing.  I do feel like Company ABC could offer me a smiliar experience.  I read about your emergency department and applied with hopes of becoming a part of the emergency team.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "If you could travel anywhere in the world, where would you go?", "answers": ["Employers realize that there is life outside of work.  Getting to know employees/potential employees and what interests them gives employers an opportunity to develop a relationship with them.  Share what you like.  Have you been to a destination you'd like to return to?  Is there somewhere you've always dreamed of going?  This is also an opportunity for you to get to know the employer.  Ask questions to show your interest in building a relationship.", "\"Without a doubt, I would go to Italy!  I have always wanted to travel and Italy will be one of the first places I go to once I have time to go and really experience it!  Have you ever been to another country?\"", "\"When I was younger, I went on a mission trip to Brazil.  I have always wanted to return and spend time with the missionaries who are still there.  I came back with such an appreciation for the opportunities and conveniences that we have here.  What about you?  Have you ever traveled abroad?\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "Has there ever been a particular case that was difficult for you, and what did you take away from that experience to help you later?", "answers": ["A day in the life of a healthcare provider is never 100% predictable.  There are times when unexpected situations arise.  Learning to accept challenges and carry what we've learned with us is a valuable asset.  What is something you've experienced that you learned from?", "\"One situation I can think of taught me the importance of having a Living Will.  One of my patients was admitted to the hospital with pneumonia and while he was in the hospital, it was discovered that he had lung cancer.  His condition deteriorated quickly and he became unresponsive.  His children did not agree on the extent of care they wanted him to receive and, for a while, it left us unable to proceed with certain treatments.  I now encourage everyone to discuss their wishes with loved ones and to put those wishes in writing because anyone can suffer an emergency situation at any given time.  Having provisions in place takes such a burden off of loved ones who often don't know what to do.\"", "\"One of the most difficult situations I can remember was a young woman whose mother had been admitted to hospice care.  She and her mother had not spoken for several years and it wasn't until someone notified her that the daughter knew her mother was terminally ill.  It made me appreciate those I care for and also made me think about relationships I had with people that I felt like needed to be mended.\""]}, {"topic": "Pediatrics", "question": "Company ABC values experience and expertise and tries to offer compensation based upon experience.  What are your thoughts regarding people in the same position having different salaries based on experience?", "answers": ["Most employers do offer higher salary incentives to get more seasoned employees.  This is not meant to devalue a person's knowledge or experience, but rather paying for more experience.  It is important to note that the interviewer is not saying you will definitely make less than someone with more experience.  Many times this question is to see how you respond and how badly you want a position.  If an employee is willing to put in the work and earn the pay increase, employers often see them as someone worth investing in.  This is a good time to ask what the beginning salary is and discuss options that are negotiable such as benefits and paid time off.", "\"I understand that years of experience are often rewarded with higher earning.  I feel, given the chance to demonstrate my knowledge and skills, you will find that I am capable of doing the job as well as some of the more experienced employees.  Having said that, I will not turn down an offer of employment because of a difference in pay based on my present lack of experience.  With that in mind, what benefits are available for someone coming on board with your company with my resume?\"", "\"Having worked in management before, I appreciate the fact that Company ABC likes to acknowledge those with more experience by offering a salary based on that experience.  While I feel that my skills and knowledge are comparable to some of your more experienced staff, I understand that I may start a lower salary and am willing to work and prove that I can be a valued employee.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "List 3 qualities that make you the best candidate for Company ABC.", "answers": ["After researching Company ABC you should have a firm idea of the qualities they admire most in their candidates. Discuss the attributes that will help you to stand out as a top candidate.", "\"I understand that this role requires stand-out skills in organization, leadership, and an energetic demeanor. I would say that these are 3 of my top skills, and I have many others! My references would attest to these skills as well.\"", "Here are some qualities that make you a great candidate for any company: \n\n- A robust existing network in the industry\n- A great reputation\n- Leadership capabilities and experience\n- Integrity and likability \n- Strong minded \n- Thirst for knowledge", "\"I am service-oriented, tenacious, and accountable to both my success and setbacks. These would be the qualities I would look for in a person I would want to work with, so this is what makes me stand out!\"", "Yeah! This is perfect! I like that you didn't lean on the typical answers like good communicator, etc. This is a stand-out answer."]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "This position requires a minimum Bachelor's Degree in a science related field. Walk me through your post-secondary education.", "answers": ["Your post-secondary career is significant when it comes to displaying your ability to complete a degree, multitask, and apply yourself. Walk the interviewer through your post-secondary experience making sure to highlight any recognition or awards you may have achieved.", "\"I have a Bachelor's Degree in Biology from Tampa College of Natural and Health Sciences. I graduated with Honours which was an especially proud moment for me since I had also been working part-time.\"", "\"I recently graduated from the University of Georgia with my Degree in Pharmaceutical Science. With this degree, I look forward to joining Company ABC and carving out a great career with you. When the timing is right, I do plan to return to school to obtain my Master's Degree in a science-based field. This extension of learning, of course, would be in tandem with my full-time job.\"", "\"I have a degree in Biology with an emphasis in Chemistry. What is not reflected on my resume is that I worked as a high school science teacher, applying what I learned in university.\"", "Good! I like that you add in your teaching experience since it's very valuable. Depending on how engaged the interviewer is, they may ask why you left the teaching industry, so I recommend you be prepared with a concise response for that potential inquiry."]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "How do you determine priorities when you have multiple projects due?", "answers": ["When you feel torn between multiple projects or tasks, how do you decide which one needs your attention the most? Assure the interviewer that you can be diligent when it comes to assessing your priorities.", "\"I will determine which project requires my attention by the number of hours we are behind and then the project size. I am comfortable delegating tasks when needed, but I am also aware that these times will require an additional commitment of hours from me. Never have I under delivered on a deadline.\"", "Prioritizing is a skill that requires practice. There are many approaches you can take. Here are some suggestions:\n\n1) Make a list. By thinking through and writing down each item that needs completion, you can see it on paper.\n2) Mark what is urgent or essential. Take into account deadlines and meetings.\n3) Order each task based on effort and estimated value. Considering due dates and how long it will take to do each item (also considering how much time you have). \n\nIn answering this question, show the interviewer that you have a system in place that helps you to think through what needs to happen, and when. The better you can prioritize, the more productive you will be, making you an asset to their company!"]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "In your opinion, what is the biggest development in Pharmaceuticals in the past 3 years?", "answers": ["The term 'pharmaceutical' refers to the creation and sale of medicine. What do you foresee as the most significant development that has happened in the past few years?", "\"There have been so many developments in the pharmaceutical industry the past three years, but I do feel that the biggest was the creation of the first vaccine for Dengue.\"", "\"I am most impressed by the way the pharma industry has switched their focus from treatment to prevention. It's a great way to flip our thinking in the industry, and will save the lives of so many people.\"", "\"Vaccines fascinate me, and I believe our research and development in the field of HIV has produced a great many advances in the world of medicines. We now treat diseases we once thought were incurable.\"", "This answer is specific and well thought out while remaining brief enough. Good work!"]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "If you could choose any special area of focus with Company ABC, which would you choose?", "answers": ["Working for Company ABC could open a variety of career options for you. If you had your choice when it comes to a career path, which career do you think you would choose? Talk to the interviewer about where you'd like to see your career path go with Company ABC.", "\"I am currently working as a Clinical Research Assistant and would like to eventually grow into a Principal Scientist role, or something of the like, with Company ABC. My primary goal is to find a long-term home where I can continue to expand my knowledge in the area of (choose an area of study).\"", "\"That is a challenging question when there are so many interesting options at my fingertips. If I had to choose just one area of specialty today, I would choose a topic within animal science. I am passionate about the health of animals.\"", "\"Since my background is in science, I never got a formal education in marketing. That is an area of business that I would like to dig deep into as I feel it would greatly sharpen my understanding of how the business units collaborate and make me a better salesperson.\"", "Having a clear understanding of marketing approaches is always helpful in sales. Good answer!"]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "When have you shown great integrity at work?", "answers": ["Integrity comes from honesty and consistent moral values. Talk to the interviewer about the way (s) that you show your integrity in the workplace.", "\"In my last position, I was responsible for the cash deposit on a daily basis. There was never a discrepancy, in the four years that I worked there. I best show my integrity by being a consistently reliable employee.\"", "\"Always! Honesty and integrity are two values at the center of my being. I like to think I practice this in the workplace by always doing the right thing by the company, its customers, and its people.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "What sources do you look to when you need to solve a complicated problem?", "answers": ["The interviewer wants to know that you can think outside the box, or even ask for help when you are stuck on a complicated problem.\n\nMaybe you look to a mentor or boss for advice. Perhaps you have handbooks, manuals and systems you turn to for help. Offer some relevant examples based on your industry. If you work in the medical field, you may turn to textbooks, online research, colleagues or even patient's history to find the right solution. If you work in customer service, you may ask the customer what they need to find the best way to solve the problem. \n\nShow the interviewer that you are knowledgeable and equipped to handle these types of scenarios.", "\"When faced with a complicated problem, I will look to the resources that my current company has provided me. The answer is almost always in there. If it's more of a moral dilemma vs. a knowledge-based dilemma, I will ask my supervisor for his thoughts and opinion since I value him as a mentor and expert in our industry.\"", "\"To solve a complex issue, I will reach out to a manager or mentor from a previous role to ask them how they've handled such issues in the past. I am always ready to dive back into our handbook, but these types of scenarios are often not covered there, which is why I value a human, experiential approach. I know that there are so many folks in the industry who have so much to teach me and have probably already \"been-there-done-that,\" so I love to utilize them as a resource.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "Would you further your post-secondary education to include a Ph.D. in your field?", "answers": ["Some upper-level positions within Company ABC may require a higher level of education. Assure the interviewer that you would be willing to discuss enhancing your knowledge to grow within the organization eventually.", "\"I have considered furthering my education to include a Ph.D. It would need to be in tandem with full-time employment, but I would certainly consider achieving this goal through evening and weekend coursework.\"", "\"Oh yes! I am a big believer in higher education. These days, to be a stand-out candidate or employee, I think that having a Ph.D. is best.\"", "\"I have considered furthering my education to include an MBA. It would need to be in tandem with full-time employment. There are on-line services that feature courses offered from universities such as Michigan State, and while these courses do not provide college credit, they are worth while to take.\"", "The interviewer should appreciate that you have already done your homework on what type of continued-studies would be available to you. Good response!"]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "When have you had to be extra thorough in completing tasks?", "answers": ["Some tasks will require a keener eye and additional diligence. Discuss a time when you were extra thorough during a work-related project.", "\"I have to be extra thorough from time to time when I have clients that are especially detail oriented. Often this will mean spending additional time on calls with them to highlight project changes. I am okay with being extra thorough when needed.\"", "\"I am always thorough, but we do have monthly team meetings where we discuss our performance metrics.  That reporting takes a little longer.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "Why did you choose a career in the Pharma/Biotech industry?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to know what drew you into a career within their industry. Show the hiring manager that you have a natural attraction to this particular industry and that you're here to stay.", "\"I chose a career in Pharma/Biotech because I have always had an attraction to the study of medicine, and science, and the correlation between them. It's an ever-changing industry which never becomes dull.\"", "\"The drive behind my choosing a career in Biotechnology was because I love science and helping others. With these two drivers combined, I knew it would be a career choice that I would be happy with for years to come.\"", "\"My background is in science, and I have always been attracted to being involved in the cutting edge of medical technology. This industry is always evolving and feeds my competitive spirit.\"", "Great! You give a unique answer that is still pharma/biotech-centric."]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "If you could choose any area in your field to study further, which area would you focus on? How do you feel that would help you with a career at Company ABC?", "answers": ["Talk to the interviewer about your favorite area of study when it comes to pharma /biotech. Why would you choose to focus on that area? Share with the interviewer why you feel that strengthened skills, in this particular area, will help you to achieve your goals with Company ABC.", "\"If I could choose any area of focus I would enjoy a deeper focus on orthobiologics. The idea of finding advanced ways of assisting the body in healing itself is fascinating to me. If there were advancements in this area, I feel it could help your organization to achieve some major goals as well.\"", "\"If given the opportunity to further my studies, I would choose to focus on Biochemical Pharmacology. I feel that will help me in this career here since this is one of your larger areas of focus. Your biochemical pharmacology department is so advanced, the idea of landing a job in that area is fascinating to me.\"", "\"If I could focus on just one thing, it would be in the field of stem cell research. We are only beginning to understand what this type of therapy can do.\"", "Fantastic! The stem cell is a topic that any interviewer could further discuss so; a great conversation could come of this."]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "How many years have you worked in the Pharma/Biotech industry? What keeps you interested in our line of work?", "answers": ["Take a few minutes to walk the interviewer through your work history, highlighting the most relevant positions and skills. Talk to the interviewer about your desire to work for Company ABC long term.", "\"I have worked within Pharma/Biotech for the past 15 years. I started in a lab assistant role and am now at the supervisory level with my current company. I stay in this industry because the opportunities are endless. I would be thrilled to continue my career growth in this industry with Company ABC.\"", "\"I am new to the Pharmaceuticals industry and recently graduated with my Bachelor's degree in Pharmaceutical Science. I plan to remain in this industry for the entire length of my career. At this point, starting in this apprenticeship role and then, moving forward into a role further focused on the development of new treatments.\"", "\"I've worked in the Pharma/Biotech world for over a decade. The industry is always changing and improving upon itself, and I like the opportunity to bring cutting edge medications to patients.\"", "Great response! Your passion for the industry shines through."]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "Tell me about your greatest work related accomplishment.", "answers": ["Talking about your most significant accomplishment will give the interviewer a definite idea of where you place your values. It will also show the interviewer more about your personality, how you like to be motivated, and how to coach you in the future. It is okay to brag a little bit when answering this question. Show that you are proud of yourself and your career accomplishments!", "\"The greatest accomplishment in my career was graduating University as an honors student while still working full time in a related field. I was top of my class, and working full time. This success showed me that I could dedicate myself to my career, and reach the goals that I set for myself. It felt great to accomplish so much and receive recognition for my dedication.\"", "\"I am proud of having been chosen to be a mentor to new hires in the department. I think I've informally mentored and exhibited leadership since day one, and to be recognized for being a great teacher and being able to train and shape the new additions to the department is an awesome pat on the back.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "What are your strengths?", "answers": ["Which personal advantages make you excellent at your job? Strengths can be skills or qualities that help you overcome difficult circumstances or accomplish challenging tasks. \n\nIn a work context, your strengths will help you to complete your to-do list, understand client needs, and help you to apply what you have learned in your training. Talk to the interviewer about a couple of your strengths and why those will help you to be successful in this role. \n\nSome great strengths to mention are: \n\n- Communicative\n- Loyal\n- Collaborative \n- Tech Savvy\n- Flexible in Schedule/Availability \n- Persistent and Determined\n- Eager for Knowledge/New Skills", "\"I think my strengths are in my perceptiveness and ability to be observant of the needs of others. These strengths are part of what makes me an excellent performer in a client facing role.\"", "\"I am not sure what others would pick, but I feel that my strengths are my dedication, determination, and ability to build long-lasting and trusting professional relationships.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "What industry related changes do you foresee in the next 12 months?", "answers": ["Assure the interviewer that you have a keen and honest interest in this industry by discussing the growth and change that you foresee in this next year. If the organization itself has any upcoming news or changes, be sure to mention these as well.", "\"I read on your website that Company ABC is expected to see a 43% increase in the sales of product ABC. This fact piqued my interest as I have seen reports that forecast a strong increase in the use of product ABC for alternative medical therapies. There are continual changes in this industry, but I see this particular one being very significant in the upcoming months.\"", "\"I was recently reading an article by Q1 Productions that addressed this exact topic. They mentioned in the article that 2018 is going to be a great year for the pharma industry due to the economic upturn. The thought is that this will increase stock prices; thus, allowing pharma companies to grow their offerings, expand operations, and further their research and reach. It's an exciting thought!\"", "\"Medicare sets the standard for what private insurance is going to pay for, and I foresee many changes we will have to navigate through before this year is over. It will be important to remain adaptable and continue to meet the needs of our customers and their patients.\"", "Try digging in a bit deeper into the changes, and the impact of these changes. This is a good start!"]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "How do you stay informed on changes in the Pharma/Biotech industry?", "answers": ["The Pharma/Biotech industry is fast moving with changes and developments happening all the time. Assure the interviewer that you are engaged when it comes to industry related changes.", "\"I follow multiple medical journals and blogs related to changes in the Pharma/Biotech industry. My favorite is wiley.com which is a strong source for updates in a variety of related medical studies.\"", "\"I have set up some industry related google alerts, and I also subscribe to Pharma Forum, Science Direct, and Medical Futurist, online. I am always looking for new opportunities to learn so if you have recommendations, I am happy to hear them!\"", "\"I stay abreast by reading about new therapies on line and following posts from my professional network.\"", "Go further into this response by adding in which resources you use in your professional network. Perhaps you are referring to articles on LinkedIn?"]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "In your opinion, what is the biggest development in Biotechnology in the past 3 years?", "answers": ["The term 'biotechnology' refers to the use of cells and molecules to create a product within medicine, genetic testing, or even agriculture. What do you foresee as the most significant development that has happened in the past few years?", "\"There have been so many developments in biotechnology the past three years, but I do feel that the biggest was the development in gene editing. It's an incredibly controversial and intriguing practice.\"", "\"There is a multitude of biotech developments from which to choose! I was recently reading about these new methods of manipulating human cells to beat a range of diseases. According to Fortune Magazine, Chinese scientists have launched the first CRISPR gene-editing trial for the treatment of cancer. It's all pretty incredible, isn't it?\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "Do you prefer to work with studies related to humans, animals, or plant life?", "answers": ["Perhaps you have a preference, and maybe you don't. However, you answer this question, be sure to keep your reply positive. (IE: Avoid saying \"I dislike studies related to animals.\" You don't want to shut down any particular practice.)", "\"I can honestly say that I do not have a preference as of yet. As I continue to carve out my career, that may change; however, for the moment, I am happy to be working in the biotech industry in any related focus.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "If you could research any particular disorder, disease, or illness which one would you choose, and why?", "answers": ["The interviewer would like to get to know you and your particular interests. If you had zero limitations, what area within pharmaceuticals would you focus on? Be sure to show your passion for your career path and tie your answer into an area of focus related to Company ABC.", "\"At Company ABC I know that one of your primary focus' is on XYZ. This particular focus is one of the reasons why I applied to work here; because the study of XYZ is a particular passion of mine.\"", "\"We have so many options when it comes to research topics. If I had to choose just one area of research, I would choose to research autism, and the spectrum, in full. My little brother received an autism diagnosis recently, and I have the drive to learn more about it.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "In your opinion, why is it important to develop relationships with coworkers?", "answers": ["This answer may seem obvious to you because enjoying your time with coworkers is sometimes the best part of the job! If you aren't a naturally social person, this question may seem more challenging to answer. \n\nTalk to the interviewer about how you develop relationships with coworkers when you start a new job. Think about what is important to you about these relationships. Do your co-workers motivate you when you feel overworked? Do your coworkers give you a reason to show up to work when your boss has been giving you a hard time?", "\"I value my relationships with my coworkers because we support each other and make each other laugh when the work environment becomes intense. I have a coworker that I eat lunch with every day. We've helped each other out by simply listening to what's going on in each other's lives. It's nice to have colleagues who understand you on a personal level.\"", "\"To accomplish anything in a job, you need your team members. Your team members are who you rely on to get a project done. You will often call them in when you need advice, or to help pick up the slack when you're in a pinch. If you don't have a good rapport with your co-workers, it can limit your ability to be great at your job.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "By this time in your career, you should have advanced further, what has slowed down your career progression?", "answers": ["When an interviewer sees slow career progression on your resume, they will immediately want to determine whether this is by your own choice, any outside circumstances, or if you are not motivated to create growth. If your career has progressed slower than you wish, you must be honest with the interviewer when discussing this.", "\"I agree with you that my career progression has been slower than some. You will see that between 2001 - 2009 I worked for the same company without an increase in my job title. The company was too small to offer a promotion to me as the next level was ownership and the business wasn't for sale. After this, from 2009-2012 I was on leave as I needed to care for my ailing parents. The growth since returning to work has been steady but those years were a bit of a standstill for me. I am ready to spring into action now, and forge ahead in my career.\"", "\"Early in my career, I was left to care for an elderly, sick parent.  Her care required more of me than expected, so I allowed my career to sit and wait.  I am happy with that decision.  Spending those last precious moments with a loved one is worth the setback.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "How does this position fit into your career goals?", "answers": ["Is this particular position a good fit? Is it a step up in your career or - a stagnant move that you are just complacent with taking until something better comes along? Assure the interviewer that this position will be challenging for you, is a step up in responsibilities, and that it fits with your overall career goals.", "\"My primary goal in my career as an HR professional is to eventually work my way from an Administrator level to HR Partner. I feel that what your organization offers is a strong path towards those goals and I am excited about what this position has to offer.\"", "\"My primary career goal is to find a position where I can stay long term. Because your company has such a strong reputation for workplace culture, it fits perfectly with my desires for a long-term fit.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "Who would you say inspires you?", "answers": ["Your life's inspiration can come from a book, a mentor, your family, a celebrity, author - literally anyone! Talk to the interviewer about who has inspired your life and why.", "\"I find inspiration in a variety of people and things. I would have to say that the person who has most greatly inspired me has been my grandmother. She always had a smile on her face no matter how hard she worked and she loved everyone. She was well respected and always gave more than she received. I try to live like she did, as much as I can.\"", "\"My previous manager was a huge inspiration to me. Her passion for this industry was motivating and put the fire in me to climb the ladder in my career.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "When a problem requires a quick solution, how do you respond?", "answers": ["When it comes to complex problem solving, the decisions do not always arrive quickly. It takes practice, experience, and confidence to learn what sorts of decisions yield the best results. \nProblems that require you to act quickly can be emergency situations such as knowing where the fire extinguisher is and grabbing it fast enough to put out a small grease fire in the company kitchen. Other quick decisions could be if you are asked to take on a new responsibility and only given five minutes to decide if it's something you are prepared to take on. \n\nGoing with your gut is a skill, and the more you learn to trust your intuition, the easier it becomes to make these types of decisions. Demonstrate that you are confident and able to react swiftly when the need arises.", "\"When an urgent problem arises at work, I always try to respond in a calm and assuring manner. I am a natural leader which means that my team often looks to me for answers. One instance of my fast-thinking was just last week when we had an administrative employee no-show on a crucial and busy day for us. I called a temp agency, and they had the position filled in just one hour.\"", "\"I react swiftly in emergency situations. Perhaps my skills come from my years as a parent, having to think fast and put out fires! If a quick solution is required, I will do a fast overview of the facts and make a decision based on risk factors.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "How do you define success?", "answers": ["What does success mean to you? Tell the interviewer how you see success and be sure to tie your answer into the success that you plan to bring to this particular position, should you be offered the role.", "\"I define success by my ability to reach the goals that are set out for me. On a personal level, the things I wish to achieve in my life. On a work level, the targets that are set out for me as well as the professional development that I seek.\"", "\"Success, to me, is achieved when I am pleased with the quality of my work and feel proud to submit it.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "Describe to me your ideal employer.", "answers": ["A job search isn't just a one-sided hunt. You must also feel as though this is a good fit for yourself. Tell the interviewer what your ideal employer may be. Be specific and be sure to keep the conversation positive. Avoid speaking poorly of any previous managers or organizations.", "\"My ideal employer is one that brings charisma and passion to their work. I work best with organizations who have a penchant for learning and promote their employees based on performance.\"", "\"I am looking to join an organization where I continued learning is encouraged. It's important to me, as I carve out my career, to learn new skills under an organization that wants me to grow with them.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "What are your salary expectations?", "answers": ["The best way to discuss your salary expectations is to use your current earnings as an example. Be open, and honest. Transparency is the best choice when salary based questions arise.", "\"Currently, I earn a base salary of $45,000 per year plus a potential 20% annual bonus. Last year my earnings were $52,000, and I would like to stay in the same range or slightly higher.\"", "\"I am currently making $100,000 per year with two bonus opportunities.  I am looking for compensation that is aligned with the role and provides an opportunity for growth.\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "Are you applying for any other jobs?", "answers": ["It always puts a little bit of fire under the hiring manager if they are aware that you are actively looking for a new position. Tell the interviewer about your search so far.", "\"I am keeping an eye out for viable positions. Although I am not in final stages with any other company, I am actively seeking a new position.\"", "\"Yes, I am active in my job search and am in final stages with another company. Do you have a timeline in mind for a decision on this position?\""]}, {"topic": "Pharmaceuticals+and+Biotechnology", "question": "How would you rate your performance in this interview so far?", "answers": ["This question can create feelings of stress and anxiety, so it's best to be prepared. Be honest with the interviewer on how you feel the interview has gone so far. \n\nIf you feel that your performance in the interview is going well: \"I believe that this interview has been quite informative and I am happy with my performance. Is there anything that I can clarify for you from this conversation?\"", "\"I believe that this interview has been quite informative and I am happy with my performance. Is there anything that I can clarify for you from this conversation?\"", "If you feel that your performance in the interview is not going well: \"I am not sure if I have been able to portray myself 100% accurately in this interview; although, I am trying my best. If there is anything more that I can clarify for you, I would be happy to do so.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "Company ABC understands that healthcare careers can be very demanding and we encourage employees to have balance between their work and personal lives.  What do you do to help promote healthy work/life balance?", "answers": ["No matter what profession a person chooses, everyone needs some time to unwind and relax.  Psychologists today say that a healthy balance in life allows a person to recharge and refocus which can result in better productivity at work.  The interviewer simply wants to know what you do for you.  Maybe you have a favorite pass-time or hobby.  This is yet another way for the interviewer to get to know you as a person.", "\"I am an animal lover.  I have three dogs that are like babies to me.  When I am not at work,  you can usually find me at a dog-friendly park playing ball or Frisbee with my fur-babies.  I also enjoy cooking and hosting dinners with family and friends.\"", "\"I love anything to do with nature.  I enjoy hiking and camping, most especially.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "Women's healthcare covers many different aspects of care.  What is your favorite area to work in?", "answers": ["This question gives you an opportunity to share your preference of where to work as the interviewer gets to know you.  If you are experienced in this area, share your favorite thing about women's health.  If you are just beginning a career in women's health, share why you chose this specialty.", "\"I have always been fascinated with women's health.  My favorite part of women's health is maternity care.  While there are critical patients and difficult births, at times, the joy of working this specialty area is something I never get too accustomed to experiencing.\"", "Note in this answer option that it says 'This will be my first......'   Showing confidence in an interview is a great way to have the interviewer remember you.  This is important because, most of the time interviewers see more than one candidate before offering the open position to some\n\n\"This will be my first job working women's health exclusively, and I am so excited!  I know there are many specialty areas in women's health and I look forward to seeing where my current knowledge and skills can be best utilized and built upon.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "While Company ABC likes to give all candidates for employment an opportunity, salary is one thing that is often commensurate with experience.  What are your thoughts regarding someone with same job title as you making a higher salary based on experience?", "answers": ["Most employers do offer higher salary incentives to get more seasoned employees.  This is not meant to devalue a person's knowledge or experience, but rather paying for more experience.  It is important to note that the interviewer is not saying you will definitely make less than someone with more experience.  Many times this question is to see how you respond and how badly you want a position.  If an employee is willing to put in the work and earn the pay increase, employers often see them as someone worth investing in.  This is a good time to ask what the beginning salary is and discuss options that are negotiable such as benefits and paid time off.", "\"I understand that years of experience are often rewarded with higher earning.  I feel, given the chance to demonstrate my knowledge and skills, you will find that I am capable of doing the job as well as some of the more experienced employees.  Having said that, I will not turn down an offer of employment because of a difference in pay based on my present lack of experience.  With that in mind, what benefits are available for someone coming on board with your company with my resume?\"", "\"I am supportive of employers who offer more experienced employees a higher salary.  I am confidant with  my skills and experience, but am willing to prove  myself worthy of a higher salary.  I am excited about the prospect of becoming a part of the team here at Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "At Company ABC we often see patients with different types of mental health diagnoses.  Are you familiar with post-partum psychosis?", "answers": ["Postpartum psychosis is a severe mental illness characterized by extreme difficulty in responding emotionally to a newborn baby. While its occurrence is not as prevalent as that of postpartum depression, women's healthcare providers are encouraged to know the signs and symptoms, which are often debilitating.  Share your understanding of the condition.", "\"Yes, I am familiar with the diagnosis of postpartum psychosis.   One of my colleagues was diagnosed with it after the birth of her second child.  I am so glad to know that Company ABC actively educates its employees on mental health issues.\"", "\"I do have experience working with women suffering from postpartum psychosis.  Not only for the patients, but for family members who have never heard of it, postpartum psychosis can be a frightening experience.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "Like most employers, Company ABC likes to attract employees that want to build a long-term relationship with us.  What changes, if any, do you anticipate in your personal or professional life within the next 2-3 years?", "answers": ["Knowing what goals you have and any changes you anticipate in your life will give the interviewer an opportunity to evaluate two things: 1. what positions are available that won't disrupt your plans and, 2.  are you interested in having a long-term relationship within the company?  Change is good and growth is encouraged.  However,  because employers invest time and money in training new employees, they prefer that they have a plan to stay for the long-term.  Still, if you don't plan on being in the same geographical area five years from now, it's OK to say that now.  Some companies offer opportunities for transfers to other facilities within the same network.  Either way, being upfront and honest is always appreciated.", "\"I recently became engaged.  Although we have not set a date yet, we have agreed to wait twelve months before the marriage.  My fiance' just passed the Bar exam here and has been offered an opportunity to join an existing law firm.  Presently, our plans are to stay where we are and build a career, not just work a job.  Also, we do not plan on having children for at least two years after our marriage.  We both feel that being able to become established in our careers and save for our future would be the responsible thing to do before starting a family.\"", "\"I understand that people have different plans and goals and that sometimes things happen unexpectedly.  However, other than something very unexpected happening, I have no intention of moving away from this area and would like very much to find a position here with Company ABC that can become long-term placement.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "A growing area of women's health is mental health wellness.  One common condition is postpartum depression.  Do you have any experience caring for patients with this diagnosis?", "answers": ["While mental health issues were not focused on as much in years past, today those issues are addressed by all areas of healthcare.  With women's health, there are many factors to consider.  Post-partum depression affects 1 in 7 women.  If you have experience in this area, share it with the interviewer.  If you don't, showing an interest in learning is a great way to attract the attention of the interviewer.", "\"I have personal experience with post-partum depression.  I didn't realize it in the beginning, but after my second child was born, I began to develop the symptoms of PPD.  Thankfully those who were closest to me recognized the symptoms and I went to my doctor for treatment.  It is a very real, often overlooked condition.  I'm glad to know that a facility like Company ABC cares enough to focus on these issues.\"", "\"I worked in an OB/GYN clinic for a while and one of the most common complaints of patients who had new babies was the symptoms of post-partum depression.  Honestly, if I had not worked in that clinic, I may not have realized how often patients experience this and how detrimental it can be if left untreated.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "Infertility is a diagnosis that is difficult for families, especially the women that it affects, to cope with.  Have you ever cared for a patient dealing with infertility?", "answers": ["One of the most difficult diagnosis that women's health care providers have to help patients through is infertility.  While a woman may receive the diagnosis, it often affects the dynamic of a whole family.  Whether you are experienced in dealing with this diagnosis or not, the interviewer will be looking for cues from you that show you are able to show compassion to patients.", "\"I actually have a personal experience dealing with infertility.  My sister was unable to conceive a child.   She and her husband went through fertility counseling and many appointments with specialists, but to no avail.  They adopted a child, but the emotional trauma of wanting a biological child took a toll on their whole family for a while.\"", "\"I worked for a while at a Women's and Children's clinic.  While I worked there, I met several families who dealt with infertility issues.  I think one of the hardest things about fertility is knowing that if there were a lifestyle change or special diet that would cure it, all of the patients would.  It's just not that simple, though.  I learned that being as supportive as possible made such a difference for these families.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "At Company ABC we value education and are supportive of employees who seek higher education or certifications in their specialty areas.  Have you ever thought about continuing your education?", "answers": ["While wanting to continue your education is not a requirement for employment at Company ABC, interviewers often ask this question.   Having a desire to continue your education in the healthcare tells the interviewer that you have long-term plans in the industry.  Whether you plan on returning to school or not, share your thoughts on what you may choose if you ever change your mind.", "\"I initially completed my Associate's degree and planned to go back to school later.  I want and need to work, but would love the opportunity to work toward my Bachelor's degree without having to sacrifice my job.\"", "\"I loved nursing school and completed my practical nursing degree.  While I realize there are several opportunities for nurses with higher degrees, at this point in my life, I feel content with where I am professionally.  It is nice to know that I could explore the option of continuing my education and continue working later on, if my goals change.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "Specializing in women's healthcare, Company ABC takes care of many obstetric patients of all ages.  Have you ever dealt with pediatric patients (16 or under) who were referred for obstetric care?", "answers": ["While obstetric care is a specialty in itself, caring for younger mothers presents even more risks because of reproductive systems may not be completely mature, lack of education, etc.   Share any experience, if any, you have in this area.", "\"I do have experience working with obstetric patients of varying ages, including teenagers.  The rate of young teen pregnancy is very alarming to me.  Many of the young women I cared for did not have much of a support system after delivery.  We always scheduled appointments for the mom and baby before being discharged from the hospital for a check-up and for education classes to assist the new moms as they transitioned into the role of caregiver.\"", "\"One of my first delivery cases was with a 15 yr. old mom.  She did not have any family support and chose to give her baby up for adoption.  It was, understandably, a very emotional case.  I can't help but believe if she had been a little older or had some type of support system, she would have made a different decision.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "When dealing with different scenarios such as those often seen in Women's Health, some employees show a tendency to distance themselves from others.  Why do you think this is so?", "answers": ["Understanding the reasons a person may wish to distance himself/herself from others is helpful when trying to address the stresses of work.  The interviewer values your opinion; so don't be afraid to share your thoughts.", "\"While I understand that many healthcare workers often feel a need to distance themselves from attachments, I do not think it is beneficial in the end.  I think as healthcare providers, especially in areas where there is a high risk of loss of life, many of us create a barrier between ourselves and others.  It's like a 'self-protect' mode.  However, when we are secluded from others, we tend to internalize our emotions and the stress related to caring for these seriously ill patients can begin to affect us personally.  I worked with a group of people previously in critical care who had a weekly dinner scheduled.  Everyone was not able to attend every week, but it was a standing 'date' for those who were able.  It gave us an opportunity to laugh and enjoy one another without the anxiety of the day looming over us.\"", "\"I emphatically feel that seclusion is not in the best interest of healthcare providers.  While we all need a chance to refocus and get our thoughts together, I think it is important to remember the old saying 'no man is an island.'  What I mean is, we need each other.  No one can offer support to a healthcare provider like someone who does the same job.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "Unfortunately, the drug crisis worldwide is no respecter of persons when it comes to the unborn.  Company ABC often cares for patients who are addicted to drugs, or are pregnant and addicted to drugs.  Do you have any experience with addiction disorders?", "answers": ["When someone is affected either personally, or through someone they know, it tends to give a deeper sense of understanding what it takes to overcome these addictions.  Be honest.  There is no wrong answer.  If you have never used or been around someone who has used drugs, that's fine.  If you have, that's ok, too.  This is a perfect time to share your feelings regarding an epidemic that is sweeping across our nation.", "\"I have never abused drugs of any type.  I have a family member who was addicted to pain medicine after a bad car accident.  I saw the effects that the addiction had not only on him, but his family, as well.  It took a long time to break that addiction.  I am glad to know that an institution like Company ABC recognizes this epidemic and offers treatment opportunities.  I believe my personal experience with what I saw my family member go through is something I can use to encourage patients at Company ABC to live a life free from drug abuse.\"", "\"While I do not have personal or family experience dealing with addiction, I worked with clients who have fought different addictions.  It is very troubling to see how many people and families struggle with addiction issues.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "Holistic care involves caring for the whole patient: mind, body, and spirit. What are your thoughts regarding combining physical and spiritual care within a healthcare facility?", "answers": ["Although there are specialists who are trained to deal with one specific body system or one specific disorder, healthcare providers often offer services or referrals to services that provide support such as emotional or spiritual counseling to help patients deal with a diagnosis.  On the other hand, there are healthcare providers who prefer for care to be specific and 'problem-focused' only.   Share your thoughts with the interviewer.", "\"I am very supportive of physicians offering additional services or referral to services that provide emotional or spiritual support for patients.  There is so much more to the patients we care for than a diagnosis on the page of a chart.  While some people have support systems such as family or friends, not everyone does.  I believe offering the option of additional resources can be beneficial in providing the most effective care for patients.\"", "\"I believe patients expect us to offer the best care possible.  Part of meeting those expectations is looking beyond our own resources and abilities and finding those who can compliment our skills while providing the best care possible for our patients.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "At Company ABC, in an effort to attract diverse patients, we strive to employee individuals from different backgrounds .  What are your thoughts on diversity in the workplace & do you have any experience working with people of different backgrounds/beliefs?", "answers": ["Some people are intimidated when faced with learning new cultures and beliefs, but in the healthcare industry, it is important to provide effective care.  The interviewer wants to know that you are open to meeting and learning about new people and becoming an integral part of the team.  Be positive with your response.", "\"The largest diverse group I worked with was probably when I did my clinical rotation at University Medical Center.  I was afforded the opportunity to meet people from different cultures, religions, and professional backgrounds.  It gave me an eye-opening experience of how many wonderful people there are!\"", "\"I think diversity in the healthcare industry is essential.  People from all over the world now call our country their home.  I believe learning about and showing an appreciation for people from different walks of life only makes us stronger as we build upon the common bond of caring for others.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "Everyone you meet has a different personality.  What is something you would like for people to notice about your personality?", "answers": ["Personality and character are two things that are closely related.  For instance, someone with an honest character or good work ethic will tend to be more open about his or her beliefs as well as personal and professional expectations.  The interviewer is looking for ques as to what character you may bring to the table, so to speak.  It is important to remember, body language speaks volume and eye contact is a big indicator of your self-esteem, and your self-esteem is reflected outwardly in your personality.  Be confident when you answer and make eye contact with the interviewer.", "\"I would describe my personality as approachable, light-hearted, and positive.  I like to give more than I take and pride myself on being part of a team.\"", "\"I love meeting new people and getting to know them.  I would like to think that people who meet me think that I am friendly and that I am the type of person they can be comfortable getting to know.  Especially in the work place, I feel it is important to help people feel at ease when building a new relationship.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "Will you share one of your most difficult cases and how you handled the stress of it?", "answers": ["Stressful situations arise in any job.   While the interviewer is asking you to share a difficult case, what he is looking for is how you handled the situation.  Were you able to stay cool under pressure?  Is the stress of that situation something that you have carried with you?  Your answer will tell the interviewer about your coping mechanisms.", "\"One of the most difficult cases I ever worked was a labor and delivery case.   The baby died prior to birth and the mother had to deliver the baby naturally.  It was my first time to work a delivery case when we knew that the baby had died.  I understand now the reasons for it, but at the time, it was very difficult for me to process.\"", "\"The most difficult case I ever worked was not a women's health case, but an ER case.  We had a case of a motor vehicle accident that was caused by a drunk driver.  The accident involved several cars and the majority of the injured were brought to our ER.  There were three fatalities.  It was such a senseless tragedy.  I dealt with a lot of frustration because I knew the accident could have been prevented.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "At Company ABC we are proactive regarding education of our patients.  Have you ever participated in patient education?", "answers": ["Education of patients is crucial in healthcare.   When auditing charts, insurance companies look for documentation to show that a patient has been provided education regarding their illness.  The idea is that the more educated a person is about what is causing his/her illness, the more likely he/she will be active in trying to prevent exacerbations of the disease process.  Any experience you have education patients, especially women, will be valuable and should be shared with the interviewer.", "\"I agree that education is a vital part of caring for our patients.  My previous employer required that we educate a patient on at least one topic (illness, medication, etc) during each encounter with that patient.  Even things that seem simple to us as healthcare providers, I have come to realize are not simple or commonplace for most patients.  I really enjoyed working OB/GYN and educating expectant mothers regarding the changes they would experience during their pregnancy.\"", "\"At one time I was torn between a career in healthcare or a career  in education.  After becoming a healthcare provider, I realized I got the best of both worlds.  I get to care for people and educate them daily.  I love what I do!\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "If you were the person responsible for hiring new employees, what qualities would you be looking for during the interview?  Do you feel that you display those qualities yourself?", "answers": ["There is more than one reason for asking this question.  First, the interviewer wants to know what qualities you think are important to perform this job.  Second, and most importantly, your answer will tell the interviewer if you hold yourself to the same standard as you do others.    If you want to see certain characteristics in your peers, you should be able to tell the interviewer with confidence that you possess those traits, as well.  This question is one that interviewers often use to distinguish sincerity on the part of the candidate.", "\"I believe that honesty is important no matter what job title a person holds.  I have found that being honest with people creates an atmosphere of mutual trust and respect.  Those qualities, I feel, are essential when building rapport with patients and co-workers.\"", "\"Compassion is a quality I look for in everyone.  I feel that those of us who choose a career in healthcare should especially put forth an effort to be compassionate.  Also, being willing to be accountable for oneself, I believe, is an important quality.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "Company ABC offers planned parenthood counseling.  One topic that people often have different opinions on is abortion.  What are your thoughts on this option for unwanted/unplanned pregnancy?", "answers": ["Abortion is a subject that is often at the center of heated discussions.  One thing that healthcare providers need to remember is that, while patients have many questions, caution must be used so that it does not appear that personal preferences are being forced upon the patients.  The interviewer will use this question to see how you approach a 'touchy' subject objectively.", "\"I agree that this is a difficult subject for many people to discuss.  For me, I try not to let my personal opinions influence the way I relate with patients and their education regarding options.  At the end of the day, a woman's right to continue or end a pregnancy is legally her choice.  I believe in offering education and support.\"", "\"I have friends and co-workers who all have different opinions regarding abortions.  I've never been pregnant, so I've never had to decide whether or not to continue a pregnancy.  I believe that different situations require patients to make different decisions and that, as their care provider, I should be respectful.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "Statistics show that one out of every two people between the ages of 15-20 will be exposed to a sexually transmitted disease.  What are your thoughts on educating school-aged children regarding safe sex practices?", "answers": ["Many people strongly object to the idea of sex education in schools.   It is ok to have an opinion, even a strong opinion, regarding this subject.  Answer honestly, but remember that you are not trying to convince the interviewer to agree with your opinion.", "\"I am not sure if saying I have 'mixed feelings' regarding this subject would be appropriate.  However, I do feel like a bit of caution should be used when planning this type of education.  I feel like age-appropriate subjects can be taught by qualified people, but that parents also should have the right to decide whether or not their child participates in a school sponsored sex ed program.\"", "\"I am very supportive of anything we can do to promote education.  I know that many people are not comfortable with the thought of providing sex education to teenagers, but I am a firm believer that education is often the best prevention.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "As much as possible, Company ABC tries to accommodate employees by working to create flexible work schedules.  Is there a schedule that fits best with your family/education responsibilities?", "answers": ["Many people work more than one job or have a one parent home which requires them to have a flexible schedule.  Others may be interested in continuing their education o simply prefer to work one shift rather than another.  Being up front with the interviewer about what schedule suits your preference could help prevent conflict later on.  It is easier to plan a schedule you can agree on than it is to fix problems that arise due to fear of being rejected.  Be honest and direct.", "\"I am not married and have no children at this time.  So, I am pretty flexible with my schedule.  If I had a choice, I would prefer the late shift, as I am a bit of a night owl.  However, I am  excited about the opportunity to become a part of this team and am willing to work where I'm needed.\"", "\"I have considered enrolling in a class at the community college that is scheduled on Tuesday and Thursday evenings.  Other than those days, my schedule is very flexible.  However, if an offer of employment at Company ABC is contingent upon me being able to work those nights, I will certainly opt for an opportunity here and discuss other options of classes at a later time.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "At times, Company ABC may have an expectant mother who is 15 yrs old or younger.  Have you ever dealt with a maternity patient that is this young?", "answers": ["One of the unfortunate things about being a women's health provider is that Company ABC cannot dictate the age of patients who become expectant mothers.  The younger a person is when they become pregnant, the higher risk the pregnancy is for a number of reasons.  If you have any experience with this issue, share it with the interviewer.  Whether you have experience or not, be sure to be compassionate with your answer.", "\"I have limited experience with maternity health and have only dealt with adult prenatal clients.  However, I can see where the age of an expectant mother, especially a very young mother, can create higher risks for both mother and baby.\"", "\"I love working prenatal care.  I have had a few OB patients who were 15 or 16 years old.  Most of my patients, however, have been adults.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "Has there ever been a time that you considered changing career?", "answers": ["This is not a trick question.  Many people have considered career changes or at least taking their current profession in the direction of a new level or certification.  This is an opportunity for the interviewer to get to know you.  Be honest and direct.", "\"I considered a few career opportunities before choosing healthcare.  I weighed things carefully in my mind and shared my thoughts with loved ones who were supportive of me.  When I made the decision to pursue healthcare, I have never looked back!\"", "\"I have actually thought about getting a certification in maternity nursing.  One of the reasons I chose Company ABC as a place to apply for employment was the many specialty areas of women's health that are offered here.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "Many healthcare employees express that at one time or other they have experienced stress or anxiety related to work.  Has there ever been a time when work-related stress interfered with your job performance?", "answers": ["Experiencing stress or anxiety is natural when caring for individuals, especially those who are very ill.  The interviewer knows this.  Don't be afraid to share an experience that  may have been stressful, but be sure to follow-through with how you dealt with the situation.", "\"I would be dishonest to say I have never had a very stressful situation at work.  When things seem overwhelming, I try to make sure that I am communicating well with my team members and supervisor.  Often refocusing on the present goal or situation helps us, as a team, to relieve some of the stress.\"", "\"While there have been stressful situations at work from time to time, I have never had an experience that interfered with my job performance.  If I feel overwhelmed or anxious , I try to take a moment or two to clear my mind and get back to the task at hand.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "Company ABC offers a number of prenatal care and counseling.  Some of the prenatal services offered include 3D and 4D sonograms.  Have you ever performed sonograms?", "answers": ["Often times candidates for employment feel uneasy when they are asked about experience performing a certain skill, especially when interviewing for a facility that focuses on a specialty area, such as Company ABC.  However, interviewers do not ask this question to disqualify a candidate.  Rather, the objective is to see where you may fit within the facility with your current skills as well as where you could be placed and be educated further.  If you have experience with sonograms, share it.  If you do not, express an interest in learning within the facility.", "\"I have assisted with some sonograms in the past, but am not sure that I have yet developed the skills to perform them independently.  If you have an opportunity for training additional sonogram assistants or technicians, I would be very interested to learn more.\"", "\"One of my favorite things about maternity care is getting to do sonograms!  I especially love performing them for new parents who are getting to see their baby for the first time on the screen.  The looks on their faces is so great.  What is priceless, though, has got to be informing expectant parents that there are multiple babies!  That one never gets old.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "Often women's health providers have to deal with patient and family disagreements regarding what care should be sought.  Can you think of a time you have dealt with this in the past?", "answers": ["Unfortunately, not all family members agree on how to proceed with healthcare, especially when cases of an unwanted pregnancy arise.  One job of healthcare providers is to offer a safe way for patients and family members to ask questions and receive medical information so that they make an informed decision.  It is important to remember, however, the final decision for care belongs to the patient, as long as she is not mental incapable of decision-making.  Share your thoughts with the interviewer.", "\"I think sometimes fear gets in the way of being able to make a rational judgment call.  Family members, especially, want to help and don't realize that they sometimes come across as pressuring.  One case I remember was a patient who was expecting a baby and prenatal diagnostic testing determined the baby may be born with severe medical issues.  She was offered the option of early termination.  She wouldn't discuss the option, while her husband wanted to discuss it.  In the end, she did not terminate the pregnancy and the baby was born with a few difficulties, but not as severe as had been predicted.\"", "\"Some of the most difficult decisions I have had to deal with in regard to patient and family opinions being different with regard to care is the option to try a life-saving or life-prolonging treatment like chemotherapy.  When someone is given a diagnosis such as requires aggressive treatment, it is a very emotional time for everyone involved.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "Company ABC values strong relationships among our team members and with our patients.  Do you consider yourself to have strong relationship building skills?", "answers": ["Strong relationships within a healthcare team and with their patients is crucial to building a successful business.  The interviewer wants to know that you are committed to building relationships that are conducive to productivity at work and to making patients feel comfortable with care.   What are your thoughts?", "\"I have often been complimented on my relationship building skills. I like to get to know people and ask them questions about themselves.  I find it's a great  way to start building rapport with others.\"", "\"I consider myself to be a strong relationship builder and take pride in my 'people skills'.  I believe I will be a great ambassador of positive relationships for Company ABC.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "One issue that many women have difficulty dealing with is unresolved grief.  Company ABC would like to offer opportunities for patients to have an outlet to discuss these issues.  Do you have any experiencing working with bereavement care?", "answers": ["There are stages to grief.  Typically, women are more likely than men to have issues with unresolved grief.  This is important to recognized as the emotions of unresolved grief have been connected to other disorders such as anxiety, depression, and even suicide attempts.  Any experience you may have helping patients deal with grief is important to share.", "\"I believe bereavement services are a great way to reach out to patients.  I understand the frustration of unresolved grief all too well.  My sister passed away unexpectedly when she was 35 yrs old and I struggled for quite some time trying to cope with the reality of what happened.\"", "\"I used to work in a hospice facility and we had a bereavement counselor who worked with patients and family members.  She was a great person to work with.  The staff were dependent upon here in difficult times, as well."]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "Healthcare workers have a high incidence of what many call 'burn out.'  Have you ever experienced a time that you felt like you needed to take a break from your job?  If so, will you share what led up to the incident and how it was resolved?", "answers": ["We all experience stress at one time or another.  Although needing to take time way from work is not a reason for disqualification, not sharing an important incident could raise questions.  If you've ever been in a situation like this, share it with the interviewer.  The fact that you are interviewing for a position says a lot about your resilience and ability to recover from a difficult time.", "\"I have been working in healthcare for many years.  I have only felt the need to take some time off regarding a case once.   During that time, I worked emergency pediatrics and was assigned a traumatic abuse case.  The child died because of her injuries.  I asked for a few days off, but returned as scheduled.\"", "\"I am familiar with workers experiencing burn out, but I have not experienced any situation that left me feeling that overwhelmed yet.  I try to make sure that when I am not at work I stay involved with things I enjoy like doing like writing and cooking.  Focusing on fun things helps to reduce the stresses associated with work related tensions.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "Do you know how to perform a breast self-exam and do  you know how to teach others to do one?", "answers": ["Awareness regarding self-care is very important.  Educating patients on what may seem very simple, such as a breast self-exam could mean the difference in life or death for some people.  Statistics show that 39% of breast issues (lumps, masses, etc) are first found by the patient during a self exam. One thing that all women's healthcare providers should learn to do/teach is a breast self-exam. Share your experience with the interviewer.", "\"I do know how to perform a breast self-exam and have taught others how to perform one correctly.  For the last two years, I have volunteered during Breast Cancer Awareness month teaching self-exams and assisting with mammograms.  Early detection is the best cure.\"", "\"I have taught breast self-exams at a local health unit and in a women's health clinic where I previously worked.  I am glad to see that Company ABC offers se education to its patients.\""]}, {"topic": "Womens+Health", "question": "Have you ever had a disagreement with a co-worker?  If so, how was it resolved?", "answers": ["Any time you work with someone else, there is a chance of having a disagreement about something at one time or another.  The interviewer knows this.  It's human nature for people to have their own opinions.  What is important to the interviewer in this question is whether or not you are willing to compromise and work through difficult situations with your co-workers.  Being unwilling to compromise or find alternative solutions to a dispute can affect everyone on the team, even if it is indirectly.  Sharing a personal experience is OK, but do not embellish it to 'be the hero.'", "\"I believe if we think about it, each of us could remember at least one disagreement with a friend or co-worker.  Although I consider myself to be pretty easy-going, I am also very passionate about my patients and the care that they receive.  I have been aware of disagreements between other co-workers, but really like to think of myself as more of a peacekeeper.  I feel like professional people should be able to discuss things logically and come to an agreement that is satisfactory for everyone involved.\"", "\"I think the most common disagreement between myself and others have involved our personal feelings about how healthcare should be carried out.  However, I have learned, as have most of the people that I have worked with, that while our opinions are important, plans of care are designated by strict guidelines and with the input of everyone on the care team as well as the patient.  Learning to respect those guidelines and patient wishes usually resolves issues that arise\""]}]